<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="10258"><title>Doom Editor has just wiped out my map</title><posts><post id="p91699" date="Posted: Sat Apr 30, 2005 8:49 am "><author>mintydog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yep, i was compiling my map and it gave me ane rror message saying the map was empty, i thought oh shit whats happened here, so i went back into the editor and ALL of my brushes had vanished. All models are still in the map and lights but all brushes have gone, so ive got no structure. Does anyone know if this is retrievable?
<br />thanks</div>]]></body></post><post id="p91711" date="Posted: Sat Apr 30, 2005 9:56 am "><author>W01f</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There should be a backup of your map on your C drive (or whatever your primary hard drive is)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p91739" date="Posted: Sat Apr 30, 2005 2:20 pm "><author>Zephbane</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You can set the editor to save it in 3 different ways. 2 Auto, 1 Manual.
<br /><br />The manual way is obvious. In the prefrences. You can check "snapshots". And ever time you manualy save, it saves a snapshot of your level also. The snap shot is saved in base/maps/<span style="font-style: italic">map name</span>/snapshot.
<br /><br />The other auto is autosave in prefrences, and you can set the time interval it saves. It will save two types of auto. <span style="font-style: italic">autosave1.map</span> &amp; <span style="font-style: italic">autosave2.map</span>. These are located where ever you have it defined in your *.qe4 file/prefrences.
<br /><br />About your problem. I've had that happen numerous times. And the reason is different everytime. If you have an autosave/snapshot. Load it up, turn off the view of everything but "caulk/nodraw/clip/hint/world". After everything is hidden, draw a box around the remaining brushes, select inside, copy, open fugged map, past. Save.
<br /><br />Hope this helps.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p91768" date="Posted: Sat Apr 30, 2005 5:34 pm "><author>mintydog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thanks for the help, ive checked the preferences and its on autosave every 5 minutes, but i cant find the path it saves to. But everything is at default, i didnt know about snapshots. Just turned on snapshots, saved the map, and i cant find the snapshot <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /><br />thanks anyway</div>]]></body></post><post id="p91787" date="Posted: Sat Apr 30, 2005 7:28 pm "><author>elroacho</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">open your Doom3\doom.qe4 (might be Doom3\base\doom.qe4)
<br /><br />it will say where they are, and you can set it to a different dir if you want.
<br /><br />{
<br />"mapspath" "F:\Doom3\maps"
<br />"bsp" ""
<br />"bsp noflood" ""
<br />"bsp shadowOpt 2" ""
<br />"bsp noaas" ""
<br />"bspext" ""
<br />"bspext noflood" ""
<br /><span style="font-weight: bold">"autosave" "F:\Doom3\base\maps\autosave\autosave.map"<br />"autosave1" "F:\Doom3\base\maps\autosave\autosave1.map"<br />"autosave2" "F:\Doom3\base\maps\autosave\autosave2.map"</span>
<br />"texturepath" "F:\Doom3\base\textures"
<br />"entitypath" "F:\Doom3\base\scripts\*.def"
<br />"remotebasepath" "F:\Doom3\base"
<br />"rshcmd" ""
<br />"basepath" "F:\Doom3\base"
<br />"brush_primit" "1"
<br />"bsp lightcarve" "-lightCarve"
<br />}</div>]]></body></post><post id="p91789" date="Posted: Sat Apr 30, 2005 7:39 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's also probably a good idea to point out that the backups are not something you should rely on.
<br /><br />It's good practice to get in the habit of saving incremental versions of your maps.
<br /><br />For example...
<br /><br />my_map_v001.map
<br />my_map_v002.map
<br />... ect ...
<br /><br />You can always give the file a more suitable name when you've finished it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92128" date="Posted: Mon May 02, 2005 7:20 pm "><author>mintydog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i cant find a doom.qe4, windows search cant find it either, and its just wiped out my map AGAIN!!!. I did save another copy of my map i could go back to, but its still a few steps beind so ive got a lot of tinkering to do, but its extremely annoying. even the snapshot has been FUBAR</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92164" date="Posted: Mon May 02, 2005 10:48 pm "><author>funcrusher</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">you might be able (and have to) save your map. 
<br /><br />you can open .map files in a text editor - sometimes the 'worldspawn' entity can get messed up and you have to do some text editing of the .map file to fix it. 
<br /><br />what happens exactly I do not recall - but I bet all your brush info is still there, but will not 'initialize' and load because it runs into an error early on in the map file. 
<br /><br />some informative links
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=5866">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=5866</a><!-- m -->
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=4710">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=4710</a><!-- m -->
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=4617">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=4617</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />post any error messages (or even the whole pile of text in a 'code' block) you get in the editor console, when you load the broken map, and more specific advice can be had.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92195" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 5:10 am "><author>gleeful</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i have my doom installed in G:\Doom3 yet it autosaves my maps to C:\autosave1.map and C:\autosave2.map by default.
<br /><br />so i'd look in C:\.
<br /><br />kind regards
<br />gleeful</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92199" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 5:25 am "><author>doomkid3000</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yeah i have noticed this too, whats that .Map doing in my C drive lol <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p92203" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 5:48 am "><author>S@TaNiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">gleeful wrote
<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">i have my doom installed in G:\Doom3 yet it autosaves my maps to C:\autosave1.map and C:\autosave2.map by default.</div><br /><br />This can be changed in the editor File-&gt;ProjectSettings which is your doom.qe4 file.<br /><br />I dont know about the 1.2 patch but everything before had a known bug that the .qe4 file is saved to the wrong place, its ment to be in your mod folder not doom3.<br /><br />IDDEVNET<div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">The first time you open DOOMEdit, you will want to click File-&gt;Project Settings and change all the paths to point to wherever you have Doom 3 installed (by default they are set to where the level designers here at id have Doom 3 installed). There is a small bug in that dialog box, after you click OK, you will need to copy the "doom.qe4" into the "base" folder.</div>
<br /><br />Has this changed in 1.2 ?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92220" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 8:43 am "><author>gleeful</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">S@TaNiC wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">gleeful wrote<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">i have my doom installed in G:\Doom3 yet it autosaves my maps to C:\autosave1.map and C:\autosave2.map by default.</div><br /><br />This can be changed in the editor File-&gt;ProjectSettings which is your doom.qe4 file.<br /><br /></div>
<br /><br />i know, thanks - i just wanted to tell mintydog where to look.
<br /><br />btw, i decided to leave them there as my C:\ and G:\ partitions are different hard-drives and i figured that's even safer.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />kind regards
<br />gleeful</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92270" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 4:19 pm "><author>mintydog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thank you all for the help, ill check out the links now, and ive found 4 autosaves sitting in my C drive, good stuff <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p92271" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 4:55 pm "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I don't believe you're the first to have had this problem, Minty. Someone else who had this map problem I asked to send it to me. I ran it in Doom 3, and sure enough, all brushes were missing. I open it in the editor, and all the brushes magically reappear. There's no explanation as to how I 'fixed' the map, but send someone your map to take a look at it. This is pretty illogical, in my opinion, but getting someone else to open up your map did something that might not even be the case. Just try it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92272" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 5:09 pm "><author>gleeful</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">2 more general pieces of advice:
<br /><br />1. always save versions of your map (mymap_1.map, mymap_2.map etc.) - preferably whenever you've accomplished a big piece of work and bsped it to see if everything works. saved my butt just today.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />2. occasionally the view-menu goes berzerk and all of the sudden you don't see certain elements anymore although they appear to be checked in the view menu. in that case uncheck everything and check it again - everything should be visible again.
<br /><br />kind regards
<br />gleeful</div>]]></body></post><post id="p92278" date="Posted: Tue May 03, 2005 6:04 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If there are any inconsistancies between what you see in the editor and what you see in game, delete the *.cm, *.proc, and *.aas files and recompile your map.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
