<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="10690"><title>Does "twosided" work with textures on md5meshes??</title><posts><post id="p96103" date="Posted: Wed May 25, 2005 5:22 am "><author>russ_c</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I am trying to create a waving flag that would be tessalated polygon plane with the texture rendered on both sides of the poly's face.  I am having trouble with my testing...the "twosided" parameter in my mtr file doesn't seem to cause the engine to render my diffuse map on both sides of the animated mesh it is applied to.  It only renders the texture on the side the normals are facing on.  Are there any other parameters that I must include to make this work?
<br /><br />Any suggestions?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p96181" date="Posted: Wed May 25, 2005 3:23 pm "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">No. What ever you do don't use that on MD5s. Not only does it *not* work but it'll make the mesh 'transparent' for some reason so it won't even cast shadow volumes.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p96242" date="Posted: Wed May 25, 2005 9:06 pm "><author>russ_c</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">wow, huh....that's lame.  That means cloth will take twice the polygons to produce.   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" />   Glad to have that cleared up though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p96340" date="Posted: Thu May 26, 2005 5:12 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, yes and no because you'll never see twice the polygons.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p107003" date="Posted: Fri Aug 05, 2005 10:13 pm "><author>reklipz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ya, that'd be a no, there may be a couple more verts in the vert list, but they will use the same weights if you do it right...
<br /><br />and then when u render, u should only see one side(unless you added wind somehow) then it should still work, just u would see both sides,lol</div>]]></body></post><post id="p107015" date="Posted: Fri Aug 05, 2005 11:37 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">And I wouldn't really consider cloth using "twice the polygons" to be a big problem <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p107049" date="Posted: Sat Aug 06, 2005 4:44 am "><author>doomkid3000</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i think if you do cloth, make the material file use no shadows whatsoever, and use a common/shadow of a very thin box around the cloth's shape <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif" alt=":o" title="Surprised" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p107090" date="Posted: Sat Aug 06, 2005 3:13 pm "><author>reklipz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yes, that'd work, but if there is wind...(other wise i dont really see the need for a cloth...) then that prob wouldnt be the best</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
