<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="10961"><title>noob working with lights</title><posts><post id="p98665" date="Posted: Thu Jun 09, 2005 10:28 am "><author>rivit</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.msnw?action=ShowPhoto&amp;PhotoID=704">http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.ms ... hotoID=704</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />ok i have droped a few lights in this pic but still i get shaddow i dont like
<br />what would i do to set lighting not to get this ...
<br /><br />edit here is what  i get ..but maybe its the way its ment to be ..
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.msnw?action=ShowPhoto&amp;PhotoID=705">http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.ms ... hotoID=705</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p98674" date="Posted: Thu Jun 09, 2005 2:05 pm "><author>wARmAcH1n3</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">from the pics i dont get what ur prob is, it that there is too much shadow? to understand ur pics would it better to have a screenshot of the editor so we can see the placed lights 
<br /><br />maybe u should put a ambient light. put a dark collor on it and set the shadows off (and the 2 other i disable too always but dont know exactly why) and put it to a place which is near an oposite wall, celling or bottom. this creates a little the illusion, the walls would refelct the light and throw it back into the room. keep the range of the ambient light in mind thats not to small but not to big becasue to not touch to much polies which are unnecessary</div>]]></body></post><post id="p98735" date="Posted: Thu Jun 09, 2005 11:28 pm "><author>rivit</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.msnw?action=ShowPhoto&amp;PhotoID=707">http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.ms ... hotoID=707</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />thx u for your time
<br /><br />edit....
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.msnw?action=ShowPhoto&amp;PhotoID=708">http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.ms ... hotoID=708</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />Ok blue = light bleeding in from right //new area I will make 
<br />Red = the light on right bleeding to the left
<br /><br />Sort of give it length ”depth “ on glance if u know what I mean ..i need light on roof to emphasize this I would think… and like as before I get un wanted shadows</div>]]></body></post><post id="p98751" date="Posted: Fri Jun 10, 2005 2:35 am "><author>DoV_Tomas</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There are a few ways to reduce unwanted shadows. As wARm said, select your light, hit the j key, and untick the shadow box. Alternatively just place lights and adjust them so they only throw a small pattern (say 50x50x50) and place them carefully to fill in the dark spots. Just take care not to have too many overlapping lights hitting any surfaces otherwise frame rate may suffer. A large ambient light flooding the area will also reduce the shadows but of course the room will then be lightened and you may loose those nice moody dark spots. You can also perhaps apply a spot light texture to the lights and control the spill onto unwanted areas. 
<br /><br />Lighting can sometimes take a while to get just right and you have to keep messaging it until you're satisfied with the look. Sometimes I just delete every light and start from scratch, and keep working at it until it looks good.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p98761" date="Posted: Fri Jun 10, 2005 4:58 am "><author>rivit</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br />ok thx
<br />ye any thing becomes good in time with trying;)
<br /><br />edit..
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.msnw?action=ShowPhoto&amp;PhotoID=709">http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.ms ... hotoID=709</a><!-- m -->
<br />Theoretically speaking if I set my light out in this manner as shown in pic I should be able to control  it a lot better?
<br /><br />Orange = small lights  lighting roof and objects placed on roof
<br />Yellow = spot lights  giving bulk light
<br />White= standard lights mimicking a sort of base ambience for the rest of the lights to work off ..and would slightly give light to floor
<br /><br />edit
<br />hmm how come it  worked nothing like that ..this ed has a power full lighting system that is very versatile and can be used in many ways to get the same effect ..like in this pic  nothing like my theory
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.msnw?action=ShowPhoto&amp;PhotoID=710">http://uk.msnusers.com/acidDrean/new.ms ... hotoID=710</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
