<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="11539"><title>Free CUSTOM music/sound effects for your games/maps</title><posts><post id="p104206" date="Posted: Fri Jul 15, 2005 11:14 pm "><author>Shadowbunny</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi everyone.
<br />Not sure where to put this topic (feel free to move it if I have put it in the wrong area - my apologies).
<br />Just wanted to let you all know that I am a music producer of several genres of electronic-orientated music (industrial, techno, electro, trip-hop, acid, breakbeat, ambient, IDM), and I am free to work with anyone who would like to have music or sound effects for their games/maps.
<br />Right now I have only done this for two people. I thought it was fun and everything so i'd like to do it for others as well. Basicly all I do is sit in my room programming music/sounds into my Alesis Andromeda (which is a rare analog monster synth - which means you will get rare and neato sounds!), as well as my Yamaha RS7000. So to me it is fun, and right now i'm not seeking payment for this type of thing, just a credit on your website and/or read me file is okay with me, and I will also add you in my portfolio of people I have worked with.
<br />I am capable of creating sci-fi ambience, sound effects like metal scrapes, machinery, spaceships, robots, computers glitching, etc. Voices, as well as almost any genre of electronic music you would need.
<br />Feel free to contact me through here in a P.M. or email me shadowbunny(at)shadowbunny(dot)org . I also have AIM: shad0wbunny (but i'm rarely on there...). If I don't answer right away, don't fret, it's probably because i'm away from the internet due to travelling or playing shows, but I promise i'll try and respond within 72 hours at least.
<br />Thanks for taking the time to read this long as hell post <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br />xoxoxoxo-Shadowbunny</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104209" date="Posted: Fri Jul 15, 2005 11:38 pm "><author>modern</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Are you only synthesising sounds or can you do ambient sound recording, like traffic, running water, dogs barking, buzzzing machinery, crowd noise?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104210" date="Posted: Fri Jul 15, 2005 11:52 pm "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">topic moved to pimping
<br /><br />Some interesting 'club' clothing you've got that as well.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104258" date="Posted: Sat Jul 16, 2005 7:31 am "><author>Shadowbunny</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thanks kat.
<br />Modern: I do both.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104263" date="Posted: Sat Jul 16, 2005 8:15 am "><author>modern</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm currently making (like a few people) urban maps, and some ambient city noise would be great!  Have you thought about putting together a .pk4 of sound shaders?  You could get it hosted on PCGamemods.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104280" date="Posted: Sat Jul 16, 2005 1:34 pm "><author>jizaboz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Shadowbunny's brother here. Just saw this post here today. If you guys would like a small example of some her "spacey" sounds, go here <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://home.triad.rr.com/fragmeister/downloads/mars/index.htm">http://home.triad.rr.com/fragmeister/do ... /index.htm</a><!-- m --> . She did the sounds for both of the ships shown hovering over my old Mars map for enemy territory. Download it and check it out. They were originally 2 long stereo clips that I clipped smaller and looped, then converted to the ol' 8-bit mono format. I was really happy with the results. 
<br />She's going to be helping me with sounds and ambience for the big Doom III - Mydevil RPG mod I'm working on, but my progress with that has been SO slow with that she's got time to do other stuff ;)
<br /><br /><br />Shadowbunny: A shader is just a short script that tells Doom 3 how to play your sound. Most map makers do their own, but if you distribute them in a big .pak4 (like a .zip) it's nice to have the shader scripts included. I can do them for you if yr interested in that or show you how to do them.
<br /><br />Kat or BNA or whoever: Any chance of making this thread sticky here?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104283" date="Posted: Sat Jul 16, 2005 3:05 pm "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've added a link to the Editing Resource sticky thread in LE pointing to this one. We don't really have that much info on sound to warrent a sticky in here.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104467" date="Posted: Mon Jul 18, 2005 3:49 am "><author>jizaboz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeahman, that's even better. Thanks.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p104530" date="Posted: Mon Jul 18, 2005 5:47 pm "><author>Shadowbunny</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">modern wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I'm currently making (like a few people) urban maps, and some ambient city noise would be great!  Have you thought about putting together a .pk4 of sound shaders?  You could get it hosted on PCGamemods.</div>
<br /><br />Unfortunately I have no idea what a .pk4 is  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" />  (I'm just the music maker  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /> ) , but yes, almost anything you could want I can do for you, just drop me an email sometime (I won't be on here a lot, no offense to you guys or anything. I just haven't had much time/interest to play many computer games - I'm still quite attatched to my old 8-bit Nintendo and 16-bit Sega Genesis. 0ld sk00l reprazent, dawg.)
<br /><br />P.S. I can clip/convert sounds/music now, so you won't have to do it yourself like my poor brother jizaboz did a while ago.
<br /><br />I've gotten a nice handful of interesting replies, i'd like to thank you guys for that and I wish you the best of luck in your magical gaming/map world and hopefully can lend my help someday <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />xoxoxox-Shadowbunny</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
