<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="12616"><title>how do i apply textures to only selected polys?</title><posts><post id="p114610" date="Posted: Sat Oct 01, 2005 4:31 pm "><author>xfxgeforced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how do i apply textures to only selected polys?  I have this model, and whenever i just select one poly, and set a material to it, it applies it to the whole model.  this is probably really obvious, but i just started trying to model  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_redface.gif" alt=":oops:" title="Embarassed" /><br />heres a pic of it just for kicks:&#13;<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://img30.imageshack.us/my.php?image=gundemo24oy.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://img30.imageshack.us/img30/4347/gundemo24oy.th.jpg" alt="Image" /></a>&#13;<br /><br />i put a target light and omni for i dont know why but im probably going to start on something else like a static object, maybe a box or barrel</div>]]></body></post><post id="p114693" date="Posted: Sun Oct 02, 2005 10:10 am "><author>Shallow</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The first material you apply to an object gets applied to the whole mesh because you aren't allowed to mix sufaces with and without materials on an object. Make a neutral material and apply that to the whole object first if this really bothers you that much.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p114767" date="Posted: Mon Oct 03, 2005 3:46 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Make a cube, convert to poly, select few polys and then fire up the material editor(m)&#13;<br /><br />select a bitmap or just change the diffuse color of the material&#13;<br /><br />Assign matetrial selection (3rd button below the material slots)  &#13;<br /><br />Show map in viewport (9th button below the material slots)  &#13;<br /><br />The selcted polys with get the new material and the others will probably become grey</div>]]></body></post><post id="p114822" date="Posted: Mon Oct 03, 2005 8:37 pm "><author>xfxgeforced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thanks alot, im no longer working on that model because it sucked, but now i know for the future <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
