<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="12739"><title>MyDevil - A RPG mod</title><posts><post id="p190752" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 10:30 am "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's good news! Can you be a little specific about what elements make this a RPG mod? From the screens it looked just like a FPS shooter. Does the character have some stats that can be raised or manipulated, or are items and an inventory involved?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190764" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 2:08 pm "><author>Hexen Terzo</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Great News!!  <img src="/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190825" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 1:34 pm "><author>jizaboz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">der_ton wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">That's good news! Can you be a little specific about what elements make this a RPG mod? From the screens it looked just like a FPS shooter. Does the character have some stats that can be raised or manipulated, or are items and an inventory involved?</div><br /><br />Yeah, it looks like most basic shooters because all the pics are in 1st person mode, but 3rd person mode will work too. There are stats (Level, Experience, Gold) and a shop system. No special inventory system yet though. But it's more like say... Quake 2's "King of the Server" mod than other more story-based single-player RPG mods. The first version will be a bit bare-bones but playable and should be stable over network games... if there's some interest and as time goes on I hope to make additional versions with more content.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192520" date="Posted: Thu Dec 13, 2007 9:00 pm "><author>jizaboz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just to let everyone know, this is still coming... and soon! I have just sent out all the files and source code as a sort of "developer alpha" to get just a few more things fixed before the public beta. If you have given any contribution to this mod such as help with problems here, etc and did not receive the group email I sent out (I know I'm missing a few) and would like to test this and help me fix just a couple more things, please send a mail to sirdirk79(at)gmail.com</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
