<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="12900"><title>Skybox parameters</title><posts><post id="p116988" date="Posted: Thu Oct 20, 2005 6:26 pm "><author>OrbWeaver</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have been doing some experimentation with skybox textures. It seems that the standard example with both "texgen skybox" and "texgen wobblesky 0 0 0" is redundant - the skybox will work with just one of them.&#13;<br /><br />I'm guessing that the texgen is used to alter the texture co-ordinates, since without one of these lines the skybox is totally corrupted. I am not sure what the numbers after "texgen wobblesky" are for though - the first one seems to impart a fixed rotation to the texture co-ordinates around a horizontal axis (perhaps to simulate the sun moving across the sky), while the third one causes the sky to rotate continuously around the vertical axis if set to a positive value. The second one does not seem to do anything.&#13;<br /><br />Does anyone have a better explanation of what these parameters do?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p116989" date="Posted: Thu Oct 20, 2005 6:31 pm "><author>doomkid3000</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">wobble makes the skybox rotate so it moves a bit like in the hell levels in the game <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071028054812im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif" alt=":o" title="Surprised" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p117172" date="Posted: Fri Oct 21, 2005 5:37 pm "><author>OrbWeaver</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">doomkid3000 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">wobble makes the skybox rotate so it moves a bit like in the hell levels in the game <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071028054812im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif" alt=":o" title="Surprised" /></div>&#13;<br /><br />Well the third parameter certainly seems to do that, but I have no idea what the second one is supposed to do (if anything). I will have a look through the hell sky textures to see if there is any clue.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
