<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="12949"><title>Quake4 specific Tutorial Requests</title><posts><post id="p117338" date="Posted: Sat Oct 22, 2005 7:24 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Please post your tutorial requests here, but ONLY Quake4 specific.
<br /><br />General editing tutorial requests should go into the Doom3 section.
<br /><br />Don't pull your hairs out if you're unsure whether a request is Quake4 specific or not - you don't get hung for undeliberately posting in the wrong section <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p117709" date="Posted: Sun Oct 23, 2005 10:34 pm "><author>Gazado</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I would like to know how to make the arched quake 3 style doorways - I have checked a number of patch tutorials but they all seem to only detail the basics of patch meshes and not how to specifically make Q3A style gothic doors with arches.
<br /><br />If anyone knows of a tutorial that is already out there somewhere (Im sure there is) then please let me know.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p117736" date="Posted: Mon Oct 24, 2005 1:28 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I want to know how to add custom MP player characters and/or heads. I do not want to replace vanilla content or create a seperate mod, I want to add to the MP selection list ala Q3A. Any and all tidbits appreciated in this goal.
<br /><br />A basic character with a simple skeleton that has the the head and body as one mesh, and another player model with a body mesh with two heads to choose from would be good info to get assembled.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p117758" date="Posted: Mon Oct 24, 2005 4:14 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Gazado wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I would like to know how to make the arched quake 3 style doorways - I have checked a number of patch tutorials but they all seem to only detail the basics of patch meshes and not how to specifically make Q3A style gothic doors with arches.<br /><br />If anyone knows of a tutorial that is already out there somewhere (Im sure there is) then please let me know.</div>
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509/http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/tutorials/doorway_1.html">http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/tutor ... way_1.html</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509/http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/">http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p117905" date="Posted: Mon Oct 24, 2005 8:33 pm "><author>Gazado</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for the tutorial links shank however that is not the kind of arch way I am looking for. The style Im after seems to be over-sized around the arch-way (it kinda plumps out a bit). If you've seen that type before you'll know what I mean. Its basically the same as the one you linked too but it sticks outwards from the main structure with a patch mesh.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p117993" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 5:38 am "><author>Democritus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Anyone figured that out yet?
<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">textures/editor/visportal_distance_512_768<br />{<br />	qer_editorimage	textures/editor/visportal_fade.tga<br /><span style="font-weight: bold">portalDistanceNear	512<br />	portalDistanceFar	768</span><br />	portalImage			"_black"<br />	areaportal<br />	noshadows<br />}<br /></div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p118030" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 12:12 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What, that you can add visportals that close after the player is at a certain distance?  Not sure what your question is, Demo.  The new visportals are really neat, and great for outdoor area mapping.
<br /><br />G</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118100" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 5:54 pm "><author>Democritus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">So the Portal is only active when the player is between a distance of 512 and 768 units away from it? That's the only explanation I have for these two values but I wondered if somebody already tested/figured this out.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118108" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 6:37 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">- When you are outside the "portalDistanceFar" value, the portal will be closed, even if it's completely visible to you or other visportals.  
<br /><br />- If the portal isn't visible to you or other portals (i.e. you have "normal" visportal closure situation), the visportal will be closed.  
<br /><br />- When you are at the "portalDistanceFar" value, the portal will open, but will be "faded".  As you move closer, it'll fade in.  When you reach the  "portalDistanceNear" value, the portal will still be open, but there will be no "fade" occurring.
<br /><br />So, if you don't want the fade effect, but you do want the portal to act like a "fade" visportal, you can set the near and far distance values to be very close/the same.
<br /><br />Goliath</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118181" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 11:17 pm "><author>Democritus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Aye. Very nice.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118243" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 5:40 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Awesome info BUT I believe this thread should be used specifically for ASKING for tutorials, and when one gets found or put together, a responding post with a LINK to a NEW THREAD specific to the topic would be more beneficial than clouding up this main thread with questions and answers. JUST A SUGGESTION IS ALL!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118285" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 1:20 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You're not wrong, BT... in fact, I would have moved his post elsewhere and not replied to it here but *ahem* BNA didn't take my mini-slinky prodding seriously.  *glares* 
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />(we can't moderate this particular forum at the moment)
<br /><br />*looks around quickly*
<br /><br />*removes clothes and runs around in circles yelling, "I'm invincible!", "Amuck! Amuck! Amuck!" and various obscenities, while teabagging the bewildered passers-by.*
<br /><br />(I'll get rid of all my dribble and move off-topic posts once I can.)
<br /><br />G</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118354" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 5:30 pm "><author>zombiedom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi there, I was wondering if someone could write a short tutorial regarding how one can use custom textures in a Q4 map. Is there a specific folder structure that needs to created in the quake4 folder?? and is the file format the same as used in Q3?
<br /><br />I opened the PK4 files to find out what the file structure was and then created a new zip file with the following path to the textures within the zip and renamed the zip extension to pk4:
<br /><br />progimg\addnormals\textures\testtxr\...
<br /><br />this didnt work, i then created another pk4 file with the following directory structure: \textures\testtxr\...
<br />and I still cant see the texture folder in the the editor 
<br /><br />Im most probably asking a really lame question, but could someone enlighten me?
<br /><br />thanks</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118362" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 6:32 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Texture creation between Quake 3 and Doom 3/Quake 4 is almost completely different.  It's almost more useful to forget what you know about Q3 texture creation (with the exception of some of the basic shader math stuff) altogether, I think.
<br /><br />Here's why:
<br /><br />Every texture in Doom 3 and Quake 4 must be accompanied by a material shader.  
<br /><br />rich_is_bored's primer for Doom3 works just fine for Q4:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=6617">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=6617</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />Keep in mind that every texture will also likely need diffuse, bump and specular images.  
<br /><br />Check out BNA's quickie tutorials on Texture creation, as well as others written by various folks:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=11893">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=11893</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />We have a whole forum dedicated to texture creation for D3, which applies to Quake 4 about 90% of the time, roughly.
<br /><br />Goliath</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118382" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 7:31 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">goliathvt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">*removes clothes and runs around in circles yelling, "I'm invincible!", "Amuck! Amuck! Amuck!" and various obscenities, while teabagging the bewildered passers-by.*</div>
<br /><br />Show us the movie!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118397" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 8:23 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">LOL!  Yeah, I <span style="font-style: italic">would</span> be caught on film if I did something like that, without a doubt.  
<br /><br />Slap our pal il padrino in here and you just might get your wish, you naughty, naughty boy... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />Bwhahahahah!
<br /><br />G</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118484" date="Posted: Thu Oct 27, 2005 7:35 am "><author>zombiedom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi G,
<br /><br />Thanks for the info, I'll check out the D3 texture tuts.
<br /><br />D</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118735" date="Posted: Fri Oct 28, 2005 2:15 pm "><author>voldemort</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Probbably not phrasing my inquiries correctly but I havnt found any good reference for shaders so unless someone can show where one is could someone familiar with shaders whip out a quick tut on what they are how they word and their parms etc...
<br /><br />I know Im probably asking a lot but  I have a feeling this an invaluable resource that I am as yet not tapping
<br /><br />thanks</div>]]></body></post><post id="p119202" date="Posted: Sun Oct 30, 2005 11:42 am "><author>nexx</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Teleporters for TOTAL newbies <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br />EDIT: Ok nevermind figured it out <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081204190509im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /><br />Maybe I'll do up a tute if/when I have time.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p119263" date="Posted: Sun Oct 30, 2005 8:07 pm "><author>Audio</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi
<br /><br />Ok, what I'd like to request is a tut on porting maps from Q3 to Q4. That would include a way to scale an entire .map up in value so that it retains the "feel." I know that in Ued, I bsp&gt;transform permanently. That makes the brushes "solid" so I can scale evenly in x,y and z. Without it, it creates an "exploded" version of the brushes.
<br /><br />I'm starting to get the impression that I should stay in GTK as long as possible until its time to add entities, retexture, light and visport. Q4Radiant is not as intuitive as I would have thought out of the box.
<br /><br />Theres a ton of mappers out there that want to recreate the "classics" from vanilla/cmpa/osp. I'm certain it wouldnt be a waste of your time.
<br /><br />I'd love to do my brush work in Unreal Editor as I'm intimate with the operations. The problem here is its a subtractive bsp creation and I've spent a week scouring the internet trying to find a way to convert a .t3d to ANY format that GTK can read. If someone has ever had this problem, please let me know what you found. It must be possible because theres plenty of Q3 map ports for UT2k4.
<br /><br />Longwinded request but very needed.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p120875" date="Posted: Wed Nov 09, 2005 5:36 pm "><author>assboat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I would like a ligting tutorial. Not so much a "how" but a "why" one.  WHY do you put lights where you do, and the reasoning behind it (looking purdy vs. r_showLightCount having a fit)
<br /><br />As on old-fart Quake 1 mapper, the whole light volume thing is a bit new, so I'm looking to understand it better. 
<br /><br />My ideal dream tutorial would be taking a map, unlit; and lighting it, with a WHY each one is there. I'll even provide a small map if somebody would do this.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p121848" date="Posted: Thu Nov 17, 2005 12:09 pm "><author>Ash The Zombie</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I would like a tutorial on Moving blocks that crush the player and start when the map is loaded.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p122249" date="Posted: Sun Nov 20, 2005 5:52 am "><author>tyrelhill</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How-to on converting doom3 textures to use in quake4 editor.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p122256" date="Posted: Sun Nov 20, 2005 6:50 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I don't see why copying the shader and the corresponding images wouldn't work.
<br /><br />I mean, provided you understand all the references being made in the material shader, it's pretty straight forward where the images will need to be.
<br /><br />I suggest you read this...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132241/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Material_%28decl%29">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Material_%28decl%29</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />And if that doesn't make sense read this...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132241/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p124423" date="Posted: Tue Dec 06, 2005 11:54 am "><author>tyrelhill</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">didnt read any of the links you posted but instead, I downloaded the clean shaders pack for doom3 and that made it alot for more simpler for changing the textures over. basically in quake4, you have to have all the tga and dds files in the same directory and the proper scripts in the right mtr file. or, well, it just wont work. dont try it any other way in q4 edit, it gets really pissy and crashed alot.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p127983" date="Posted: Sun Jan 01, 2006 6:19 am "><author>Neo Striker</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I need a '<span style="font-style: italic">complete</span>' tutorial(notice the emphasis on "complete") on how to create decals for Q4(how to get them to show up right in editor, getting them transparent, making the non-important parts on the image to disappear like the black parts, etc.)
<br />This would be very helpful. All the posts I have read on decals are just not complete enough to explain it well.
<br />Thx.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p127989" date="Posted: Sun Jan 01, 2006 7:47 am "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">assboat wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I would like a ligting tutorial. Not so much a "how" but a "why" one.  WHY do you put lights where you do, and the reasoning behind it (looking purdy vs. r_showLightCount having a fit)<br /><br />As on old-fart Quake 1 mapper, the whole light volume thing is a bit new, so I'm looking to understand it better. <br /><br />My ideal dream tutorial would be taking a map, unlit; and lighting it, with a WHY each one is there. I'll even provide a small map if somebody would do this.</div>
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132241/http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials/doom_3_lighting.htm">http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials ... ghting.htm</a><!-- m -->
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132241/http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials/doom_3_lighting_outdoor.htm">http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials ... utdoor.htm</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p128008" date="Posted: Sun Jan 01, 2006 9:13 am "><author>KungFuSquirrel</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'll see if we can accomodate some of these (decal creation, lighting, etc.) on the q4 sdk site once we get back to work this upcoming week... I've been wanting to do that unlit level step-by-step lighting for a while. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132241im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p132690" date="Posted: Thu Feb 09, 2006 5:21 pm "><author>nikita.</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i would like a video/toturial of how to guide your npc from scratch.
<br />how to make him talk, how to make him use animation of talking, how to make him fellow you, give you weapons, everything bout npc there is to know</div>]]></body></post><post id="p138210" date="Posted: Mon Mar 27, 2006 4:32 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">a tut on Q4 3d skyboxes would be nice..  a search revieled a ton of threads but no "this is how it's done" posts.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132241im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p165699" date="Posted: Wed Dec 27, 2006 1:12 am "><author>Vayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Video tuts work best for me rather than text and pics, but I guess either way.
<br /><br />If there could be a tut on Arched doorways as to say like in q3 dm6 that would be awesome.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p197130" date="Posted: Sat Mar 29, 2008 7:50 pm "><author>BloodMuffin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How do you make clouds in the FX editor?<br /><br />After making something in the FX editor, how do you import it into the level editor?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p117338" date="Posted: Sat Oct 22, 2005 8:24 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Please post your tutorial requests here, but ONLY Quake4 specific.
<br /><br />General editing tutorial requests should go into the Doom3 section.
<br /><br />Don't pull your hairs out if you're unsure whether a request is Quake4 specific or not - you don't get hung for undeliberately posting in the wrong section <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p117709" date="Posted: Sun Oct 23, 2005 11:34 pm "><author>Gazado</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I would like to know how to make the arched quake 3 style doorways - I have checked a number of patch tutorials but they all seem to only detail the basics of patch meshes and not how to specifically make Q3A style gothic doors with arches.
<br /><br />If anyone knows of a tutorial that is already out there somewhere (Im sure there is) then please let me know.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p117736" date="Posted: Mon Oct 24, 2005 2:28 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I want to know how to add custom MP player characters and/or heads. I do not want to replace vanilla content or create a seperate mod, I want to add to the MP selection list ala Q3A. Any and all tidbits appreciated in this goal.
<br /><br />A basic character with a simple skeleton that has the the head and body as one mesh, and another player model with a body mesh with two heads to choose from would be good info to get assembled.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p117758" date="Posted: Mon Oct 24, 2005 5:14 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Gazado wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I would like to know how to make the arched quake 3 style doorways - I have checked a number of patch tutorials but they all seem to only detail the basics of patch meshes and not how to specifically make Q3A style gothic doors with arches.<br /><br />If anyone knows of a tutorial that is already out there somewhere (Im sure there is) then please let me know.</div>
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412/http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/tutorials/doorway_1.html">http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/tutor ... way_1.html</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412/http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/">http://www.planetquake.com/gothic/</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p117905" date="Posted: Mon Oct 24, 2005 9:33 pm "><author>Gazado</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for the tutorial links shank however that is not the kind of arch way I am looking for. The style Im after seems to be over-sized around the arch-way (it kinda plumps out a bit). If you've seen that type before you'll know what I mean. Its basically the same as the one you linked too but it sticks outwards from the main structure with a patch mesh.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p117993" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 6:38 am "><author>Democritus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Anyone figured that out yet?
<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">textures/editor/visportal_distance_512_768<br />{<br />	qer_editorimage	textures/editor/visportal_fade.tga<br /><span style="font-weight: bold">portalDistanceNear	512<br />	portalDistanceFar	768</span><br />	portalImage			"_black"<br />	areaportal<br />	noshadows<br />}<br /></div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p118030" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 1:12 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What, that you can add visportals that close after the player is at a certain distance?  Not sure what your question is, Demo.  The new visportals are really neat, and great for outdoor area mapping.
<br /><br />G</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118100" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 6:54 pm "><author>Democritus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">So the Portal is only active when the player is between a distance of 512 and 768 units away from it? That's the only explanation I have for these two values but I wondered if somebody already tested/figured this out.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118108" date="Posted: Tue Oct 25, 2005 7:37 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">- When you are outside the "portalDistanceFar" value, the portal will be closed, even if it's completely visible to you or other visportals.  
<br /><br />- If the portal isn't visible to you or other portals (i.e. you have "normal" visportal closure situation), the visportal will be closed.  
<br /><br />- When you are at the "portalDistanceFar" value, the portal will open, but will be "faded".  As you move closer, it'll fade in.  When you reach the  "portalDistanceNear" value, the portal will still be open, but there will be no "fade" occurring.
<br /><br />So, if you don't want the fade effect, but you do want the portal to act like a "fade" visportal, you can set the near and far distance values to be very close/the same.
<br /><br />Goliath</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118181" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 12:17 am "><author>Democritus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Aye. Very nice.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118243" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 6:40 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Awesome info BUT I believe this thread should be used specifically for ASKING for tutorials, and when one gets found or put together, a responding post with a LINK to a NEW THREAD specific to the topic would be more beneficial than clouding up this main thread with questions and answers. JUST A SUGGESTION IS ALL!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118285" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 2:20 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You're not wrong, BT... in fact, I would have moved his post elsewhere and not replied to it here but *ahem* BNA didn't take my mini-slinky prodding seriously.  *glares* 
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />(we can't moderate this particular forum at the moment)
<br /><br />*looks around quickly*
<br /><br />*removes clothes and runs around in circles yelling, "I'm invincible!", "Amuck! Amuck! Amuck!" and various obscenities, while teabagging the bewildered passers-by.*
<br /><br />(I'll get rid of all my dribble and move off-topic posts once I can.)
<br /><br />G</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118354" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 6:30 pm "><author>zombiedom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi there, I was wondering if someone could write a short tutorial regarding how one can use custom textures in a Q4 map. Is there a specific folder structure that needs to created in the quake4 folder?? and is the file format the same as used in Q3?
<br /><br />I opened the PK4 files to find out what the file structure was and then created a new zip file with the following path to the textures within the zip and renamed the zip extension to pk4:
<br /><br />progimg\addnormals\textures\testtxr\...
<br /><br />this didnt work, i then created another pk4 file with the following directory structure: \textures\testtxr\...
<br />and I still cant see the texture folder in the the editor 
<br /><br />Im most probably asking a really lame question, but could someone enlighten me?
<br /><br />thanks</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118362" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 7:32 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Texture creation between Quake 3 and Doom 3/Quake 4 is almost completely different.  It's almost more useful to forget what you know about Q3 texture creation (with the exception of some of the basic shader math stuff) altogether, I think.
<br /><br />Here's why:
<br /><br />Every texture in Doom 3 and Quake 4 must be accompanied by a material shader.  
<br /><br />rich_is_bored's primer for Doom3 works just fine for Q4:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=6617">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=6617</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />Keep in mind that every texture will also likely need diffuse, bump and specular images.  
<br /><br />Check out BNA's quickie tutorials on Texture creation, as well as others written by various folks:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=11893">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=11893</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />We have a whole forum dedicated to texture creation for D3, which applies to Quake 4 about 90% of the time, roughly.
<br /><br />Goliath</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118382" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 8:31 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">goliathvt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">*removes clothes and runs around in circles yelling, "I'm invincible!", "Amuck! Amuck! Amuck!" and various obscenities, while teabagging the bewildered passers-by.*</div>
<br /><br />Show us the movie!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118397" date="Posted: Wed Oct 26, 2005 9:23 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">LOL!  Yeah, I <span style="font-style: italic">would</span> be caught on film if I did something like that, without a doubt.  
<br /><br />Slap our pal il padrino in here and you just might get your wish, you naughty, naughty boy... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />Bwhahahahah!
<br /><br />G</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118484" date="Posted: Thu Oct 27, 2005 8:35 am "><author>zombiedom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi G,
<br /><br />Thanks for the info, I'll check out the D3 texture tuts.
<br /><br />D</div>]]></body></post><post id="p118735" date="Posted: Fri Oct 28, 2005 3:15 pm "><author>voldemort</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Probbably not phrasing my inquiries correctly but I havnt found any good reference for shaders so unless someone can show where one is could someone familiar with shaders whip out a quick tut on what they are how they word and their parms etc...
<br /><br />I know Im probably asking a lot but  I have a feeling this an invaluable resource that I am as yet not tapping
<br /><br />thanks</div>]]></body></post><post id="p119202" date="Posted: Sun Oct 30, 2005 12:42 pm "><author>nexx</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Teleporters for TOTAL newbies <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br />EDIT: Ok nevermind figured it out <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225132412im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /><br />Maybe I'll do up a tute if/when I have time.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p119263" date="Posted: Sun Oct 30, 2005 9:07 pm "><author>Audio</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi
<br /><br />Ok, what I'd like to request is a tut on porting maps from Q3 to Q4. That would include a way to scale an entire .map up in value so that it retains the "feel." I know that in Ued, I bsp&gt;transform permanently. That makes the brushes "solid" so I can scale evenly in x,y and z. Without it, it creates an "exploded" version of the brushes.
<br /><br />I'm starting to get the impression that I should stay in GTK as long as possible until its time to add entities, retexture, light and visport. Q4Radiant is not as intuitive as I would have thought out of the box.
<br /><br />Theres a ton of mappers out there that want to recreate the "classics" from vanilla/cmpa/osp. I'm certain it wouldnt be a waste of your time.
<br /><br />I'd love to do my brush work in Unreal Editor as I'm intimate with the operations. The problem here is its a subtractive bsp creation and I've spent a week scouring the internet trying to find a way to convert a .t3d to ANY format that GTK can read. If someone has ever had this problem, please let me know what you found. It must be possible because theres plenty of Q3 map ports for UT2k4.
<br /><br />Longwinded request but very needed.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p120875" date="Posted: Wed Nov 09, 2005 5:36 pm "><author>assboat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I would like a ligting tutorial. Not so much a "how" but a "why" one.  WHY do you put lights where you do, and the reasoning behind it (looking purdy vs. r_showLightCount having a fit)
<br /><br />As on old-fart Quake 1 mapper, the whole light volume thing is a bit new, so I'm looking to understand it better. 
<br /><br />My ideal dream tutorial would be taking a map, unlit; and lighting it, with a WHY each one is there. I'll even provide a small map if somebody would do this.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p121848" date="Posted: Thu Nov 17, 2005 12:09 pm "><author>Ash The Zombie</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I would like a tutorial on Moving blocks that crush the player and start when the map is loaded.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p122249" date="Posted: Sun Nov 20, 2005 5:52 am "><author>tyrelhill</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How-to on converting doom3 textures to use in quake4 editor.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p122256" date="Posted: Sun Nov 20, 2005 6:50 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I don't see why copying the shader and the corresponding images wouldn't work.
<br /><br />I mean, provided you understand all the references being made in the material shader, it's pretty straight forward where the images will need to be.
<br /><br />I suggest you read this...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225131639/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Material_%28decl%29">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Material_%28decl%29</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />And if that doesn't make sense read this...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225131639/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p124423" date="Posted: Tue Dec 06, 2005 11:54 am "><author>tyrelhill</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">didnt read any of the links you posted but instead, I downloaded the clean shaders pack for doom3 and that made it alot for more simpler for changing the textures over. basically in quake4, you have to have all the tga and dds files in the same directory and the proper scripts in the right mtr file. or, well, it just wont work. dont try it any other way in q4 edit, it gets really pissy and crashed alot.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p127983" date="Posted: Sun Jan 01, 2006 6:19 am "><author>Neo Striker</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I need a '<span style="font-style: italic">complete</span>' tutorial(notice the emphasis on "complete") on how to create decals for Q4(how to get them to show up right in editor, getting them transparent, making the non-important parts on the image to disappear like the black parts, etc.)
<br />This would be very helpful. All the posts I have read on decals are just not complete enough to explain it well.
<br />Thx.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p127989" date="Posted: Sun Jan 01, 2006 7:47 am "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">assboat wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I would like a ligting tutorial. Not so much a "how" but a "why" one.  WHY do you put lights where you do, and the reasoning behind it (looking purdy vs. r_showLightCount having a fit)<br /><br />As on old-fart Quake 1 mapper, the whole light volume thing is a bit new, so I'm looking to understand it better. <br /><br />My ideal dream tutorial would be taking a map, unlit; and lighting it, with a WHY each one is there. I'll even provide a small map if somebody would do this.</div>
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225131639/http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials/doom_3_lighting.htm">http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials ... ghting.htm</a><!-- m -->
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225131639/http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials/doom_3_lighting_outdoor.htm">http://www.quake3bits.com/htm/tutorials ... utdoor.htm</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p128008" date="Posted: Sun Jan 01, 2006 9:13 am "><author>KungFuSquirrel</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'll see if we can accomodate some of these (decal creation, lighting, etc.) on the q4 sdk site once we get back to work this upcoming week... I've been wanting to do that unlit level step-by-step lighting for a while. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225131639im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p132690" date="Posted: Thu Feb 09, 2006 5:21 pm "><author>nikita.</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i would like a video/toturial of how to guide your npc from scratch.
<br />how to make him talk, how to make him use animation of talking, how to make him fellow you, give you weapons, everything bout npc there is to know</div>]]></body></post><post id="p138210" date="Posted: Mon Mar 27, 2006 4:32 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">a tut on Q4 3d skyboxes would be nice..  a search revieled a ton of threads but no "this is how it's done" posts.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225131639im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p165699" date="Posted: Wed Dec 27, 2006 1:12 am "><author>Vayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Video tuts work best for me rather than text and pics, but I guess either way.
<br /><br />If there could be a tut on Arched doorways as to say like in q3 dm6 that would be awesome.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p197130" date="Posted: Sat Mar 29, 2008 7:50 pm "><author>BloodMuffin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How do you make clouds in the FX editor?<br /><br />After making something in the FX editor, how do you import it into the level editor?</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
