<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="14528"><title>Basilica Q4 texture set</title><posts><post id="p132573" date="Posted: Wed Feb 08, 2006 2:38 am "><author>spacer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.another-world.org.uk/spacer/basilica.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.another-world.org.uk/spacer/basilica2.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Finally finished a textureset \o/. <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.another-world.org.uk/spacer/spa1.zip">http://www.another-world.org.uk/spacer/spa1.zip</a><!-- m -->
<br />Sorta got inspired by the team arena textureset you see all the time in CTF maps for Q3.
<br />Crits welcome, I think I could've done with a few more variations in wall materials..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p132574" date="Posted: Wed Feb 08, 2006 2:50 am "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Not too bad, although it looks like the ambient light you've used in the test map is flattening them out a little bit (I'm assuming there's an ambient light there!).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p132579" date="Posted: Wed Feb 08, 2006 3:39 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Somehow i am not able to get it to work...i can see the textues in the texture browser, but they dont show up in the map...
<br /><br />i see ex's .mtr file in there, but there are no textures from that pack...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p132582" date="Posted: Wed Feb 08, 2006 5:40 am "><author>KungFuSquirrel</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">echoing what kat said, definitely don't use an ambient to showcase textures <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> Get some good two-source directional lighting (preferably with some color variation) to show off those details!
<br /><br />That support also looks eerily like one of my two texture contributions to Natural Selection <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /> Looks like some nice shapes and 'workhorse' tiles, nicely done! Will get back to you when I've had a chance to fiddle with them...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p132590" date="Posted: Wed Feb 08, 2006 1:12 pm "><author>spacer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">_shank wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Somehow i am not able to get it to work...i can see the textues in the texture browser, but they dont show up in the map...<br /><br />i see ex's .mtr file in there, but there are no textures from that pack...</div>
<br /><br />Ah, I thought I deleted that <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_neutral.gif" alt=":|" title="Neutral" />. I'm a total noob at actually getting textures to work in Q4, so I might've messed something up.
<br /><br />Kat: There is ambient lighting on that test map, because the textures were designed to be used somewhat like <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://lvlworld.com/screenshot.php?s=map-13vast">http://lvlworld.com/screenshot.php?s=map-13vast</a><!-- m --> this.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p132596" date="Posted: Wed Feb 08, 2006 2:49 pm "><author>Black Dog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Your material defs are all broken by the inclusion of the addnormals command in the bumpmap line without the expected parameters. This is easily fixed by search/replacing addnormals with whitespace.
<br /><br />Well, I like your textures but am a bit puzzled by the theme. There seems to be a cathedral thing going on, but also some hazard stripes and riveted metal panels? That doesn't seem like a logical match to me.
<br /><br />The set could do with some more colour variation between textures, and a bit more work on the normalmaps. They already have some noisy detail in them, which is good for this kind of surface, but I think they could use an additional subtle heightmap.
<br /><br />I like em though, particularly like the column texture. That rocks the house. More please!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p132620" date="Posted: Wed Feb 08, 2006 8:34 pm "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The textures are nice looking, but try and take full advantage of Doom 3 Engine's greatest feature (lighting) to show off the textures. Even crappy textures can look beautiful in Doom 3, with creative lighting--not that I'm saying your textures are crappy. I love them. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p132727" date="Posted: Thu Feb 09, 2006 9:22 pm "><author>spacer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Been experimenting with Zbrush for making textures, this one was just a quicky to see what it'd look like
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://another-world.org.uk/spacer/skulls.jpg">http://another-world.org.uk/spacer/skulls.jpg</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p139167" date="Posted: Wed Apr 05, 2006 5:27 pm "><author>Tetzlaff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice! I almost overlooked it. Maybe someone can make a sticky thread in the texturing forum collecting all links to all texture packs that are available.
<br /><br />And I would label it a "Doom 3 / Quake 4 texture pack", since it can be used as well in Doom3 and is a great addition to hell themed texture sets.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
