<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="16275"><title>Prey wiki page live</title><posts><post id="p148119" date="Posted: Sat Jul 01, 2006 7:26 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The Prey page on modwiki.net is now live, and I'm populating it with cvars etc from the demo.
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081205224330/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Prey" class="postlink">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Prey</a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p148122" date="Posted: Sat Jul 01, 2006 8:11 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good news!
<br /><br />Moved to news...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p148177" date="Posted: Sun Jul 02, 2006 4:46 am "><author>ViPr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">btw, if you want, i can explain the 2 tricks i believe they used to make people think their engine has gloss mapping when it actually doesn't. i played the demo several times and inspected the texture files.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p148178" date="Posted: Sun Jul 02, 2006 4:53 am "><author>bkt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">oh god... don't start with the gloss mapping again.  They're not trying to deceive anybody. They're simply improving the visuals of the game by increasing the visual pallete of the game wth the inclusion of glossy textures.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p148187" date="Posted: Sun Jul 02, 2006 8:00 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">ViPr wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">btw, if you want, i can explain the 2 tricks i believe they used to make people think their engine has gloss mapping when it actually doesn't. i played the demo several times and inspected the texture files.</div>
<br /><br />No thanks - Don't disturb our circles.
<br /><br />Next annoying post will be your last one on D3W.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p148198" date="Posted: Sun Jul 02, 2006 10:02 am "><author>stabinbac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">ViPr wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">btw, if you want, i can explain the 2 tricks i believe they used to make people think their engine has gloss mapping when it actually doesn't. i played the demo several times and inspected the texture files.</div>
<br /><br />They used a trick to give the illusion that they were using a different trick to get an illusion? Maybe they weren't even thinking about the trick you're so fond of. Isn't that a great concept? Multiple ways to achieve a goal? Amazing!
<br /><br />Meh, couldn't be. It's obvious they're decieving us on purpose. I bet those faked gloss maps tricks are going to lead to billions of sad costumers.
<br /><br />End sarcasm;
<br /><br />What if he wrote it in a way that didn't involve any hint of gloss maps? Just as a "simulating varied specular highlights" guide, or something like that? (Sorry if that title is horribly wrong. I'm not an art person.)
<br /><br />Might be handy for someone. And you do have to admit that it's almost out of character for him to be offering assistance with improving the looks of a non-gloss map engine. Usually he would just be demanding that someone create a gloss map method and send it to Human Head with a message demanding that they toss out the gold master, and recreate all the art to incorporate them.
<br /><br />Would adding gloss maps have a performance impact? Faking them would seem like a great idea then. A minor graphics hit for a performance boost? That sounds wonderful.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p148543" date="Posted: Wed Jul 05, 2006 10:41 am "><author>Enforcer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">... encourager ...
<br /><br />anyway nice job on updating the wiki
<br /><br />i luved prey not sure tho if ill go back to mapping. Blizzard ruined my life <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081205224330im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":-(" title="Sad" /> and i have a new job so. Modding seems almost invisible <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081205224330im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /><br /><br /><br />BTW if you play WoW more than 8hrs aday you have whats called an addiction. You need professional help call 1-800-WOWS (world of warcraft support hotline their there for you and you mage, priest, warlock, warrior, paladin, shaman, ect...)</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
