<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="17490"><title>ingame Gui: How to enter some text?</title><posts><post id="p159373" date="Posted: Wed Oct 11, 2006 7:46 pm "><author>JoeFSG</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I tried to make gui with a textfield inside.
<br />It works fine in mainmenu mode. But if i try to use it ingame like on a terminal, i cant enter text. Is there a way to catch the keyboard input while looking on a ingame terminal gui ??
<br /><br />short: How do i enter some text into a editDef control while standing in front of a terminal?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p159374" date="Posted: Wed Oct 11, 2006 8:35 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You can't. You have no means to engage or disengage keyboard input with the GUI when you're playing the game.
<br /><br />The only way to make this possible is by modifying the SDK. You need a way to tell the game "I'd like my keyboard to work with this GUI right now" or "I'd like my keyboard to control the player right now".</div>]]></body></post><post id="p159382" date="Posted: Wed Oct 11, 2006 10:18 pm "><author>Enforcer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Not true rich remember the doom in doom3 those guys did it kinda hinders alot of time but its possible but just</div>]]></body></post><post id="p159386" date="Posted: Wed Oct 11, 2006 10:44 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Right, he did. And he did exactly what I mentioned in my previous post to do it. He modifed the SDK.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p159390" date="Posted: Thu Oct 12, 2006 12:14 am "><author>Enforcer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">OOPS  srry missed that little section there :-p</div>]]></body></post><post id="p159427" date="Posted: Thu Oct 12, 2006 6:06 pm "><author>JoeFSG</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yes, i nkow this doom terminal mod, but i cant find any email address from the author, any idea??</div>]]></body></post><post id="p159431" date="Posted: Thu Oct 12, 2006 8:32 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well from what I've gathered in about 5 minutes with Google, the guy behind "Terminal Doom" is Bernd Kreimeier. It turns out the guy works in the gaming industry although I can't seem to dig up any clues about with whom currently.
<br /><br />I've found a few email addresses that I believe are his but judging by the date of some of these pages I can't be sure they're still in use.
<br /><br /><!-- e --><a href="mailto:bk@gamers.org">bk@gamers.org</a><!-- e -->
<br /><!-- e --><a href="mailto:Bernd.Kreimeier@NeRo.Uni-Bonn.DE">Bernd.Kreimeier@NeRo.Uni-Bonn.DE</a><!-- e -->
<br /><br />Just a hunch but given the hosting for "Terminal Doom" looks to be a personal page, I'd also try something like...
<br /><br /><!-- e --><a href="mailto:bk@battleteam.net">bk@battleteam.net</a><!-- e -->
<br /><br />... or some variation of it.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
