<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="18015"><title>First Unreal.3 engine (PC)game released</title><posts><post id="p163901" date="Posted: Tue Dec 05, 2006 7:56 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just stumbled upon this:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236/http://www.roboblitz.com/HTML_SITE/main.shtml">http://www.roboblitz.com/HTML_SITE/main.shtml</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />It's the first game running on the Unreal.3 engine released for PC - and it comes with UnrealED 3.
<br /><br />The game can get purchased via Steam.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163903" date="Posted: Tue Dec 05, 2006 8:11 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hmmm... cheap price tag too. I may get it...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163906" date="Posted: Tue Dec 05, 2006 8:26 pm "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Why do most of the screenshots remind me of Unreal Tournament 2004 with a small fraction of Prey's lighting? For being the first game released to use the engine, the game that came the next day sure does make Roboblitz look like sonic the hedgehog.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163910" date="Posted: Tue Dec 05, 2006 9:00 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I really don't like character &amp; levels design. (based on screenshoots)
<br /><br />I think that you better wait for UT2007 to have a real representation of that engine on PC. just my opinion of course.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br />(or maybe PC version of GoW?)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163911" date="Posted: Tue Dec 05, 2006 9:03 pm "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's strange I'm seeing news about this all over, because the game has actually been release for quite some time (2 or 3 weeks). I think the only new thing is that it has been released through Xbox live.
<br /><br />I've bought it (over Steam). This game serves as a bit of a tech demo, IMO. It's kind of simple in terms of architecture, and it uses procedural generation for textures, so the download is quite small. I'm not sure this is actually useful on PC's case, though, as textures are decompressed when the game is installed (it takes a looong time) and some textures didn't really show up for me (only the normal maps). They're of good quality though and for the most part you'd never have guessed they were procedurally designed.
<br /><br />It's also a tech demo for PhysX/Ageia (or whatever's the name). You're even forced to install their drivers, even without specialized hardware. And in theory the game should be a physics puzzle, but on a normal PC (AMD 3700+ Radeon x800 with 2gb) the game physics as a whole are really, really, really crap. The player control seems to lag considerably (not a framerate problem), and collision feels really bad; oftenly I'd get stuck in geometry simply because Blitz's arms managed to touch a corner of a wall or just have some constant bounding box fights until something either breaks or explodes. Fighting the bosses (Meganoeds) was also pretty painful, as I'd waste more time trying to understand what the heck was meant to be done (via some hardcoded script that didn't make much sense most of the times) and fighting the controls than actually solving puzzles or having fun. The user interface is also REALLY slow for some reason (ie, mouse cursor lagging behind, slow framerate). I hope that's not really any indication of how UT2k7 will run.
<br /><br />And just to say something positive, it's a cute little game with some potential and a story that fits together well (even if VERY short) and not your usual grunt FPS shooter. But it's probably only worth the price tag for UnrealEd fans who want to have some intimate time with UED 3 and Kismet before the actual honeymoon (UT2k7) comes (but not for much more since modding on the game is pretty limited now).
<br /><br />I'd say this would be a good game to introduce one's kids to, but it's so frustrating at times that it's probably not a wise idea.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163928" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 1:40 am "><author>c--b</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I downloaded the 400 or so Mb demo of RoboBlitz only to find out that the game requires you to have pixel shader 2.0c support while I have pixel shader 2.0<span style="font-weight: bold">b</span> support and can't play because of it (Why can't I just not use the shaders?!). Sufficed to say I was pissed.
<br /><br />Looks like a neat game though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163929" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 2:14 am "><author>Jehar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, it's apparent that the UE3 engine is being licensed like *mad* crazy, and I'm glad Epic is being smart in that manner... though, if it were my decision, I probably would have held out any licensing until the flagship game comes out that makes good use of the engine's features.
<br /><br />I'm still debating the validity of a decision like that... it might even be that they are using the license money to fund the flagship game itself... heh.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163930" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 2:14 am "><author>ViPr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it has auto-aim stuck on so the designers are retarded and need a beating.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163936" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 2:48 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I was amazed how horribly it ran on my computer.  I never realized how old my computer has grown until I ran that game.  With everything turned on and a screen resolution of 800x600 I was getting around 5 fps.  Looks like my new computer will have to be purchased sooner than expected.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163937" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 3:06 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it won't run on my pc at all.  Need a newer version of Windows &amp; a newer Vid Card.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /><br /><br />I never realize how "portable" id games are until i try another game that won't let me run it on a technicality.  id games just run (regardless of cpu, vid card, etc).  May need a little tweaking though.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p163941" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 3:40 am "><author>ajm113</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Cool, I wana buy! That game looks cool to the detail of the levels look awsome!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p163947" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 6:16 am "><author>pieisgood</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236/http://www.roboblitz.com/RoboBlitzEditorWiki/images/MatEditor.jpg">http://www.roboblitz.com/RoboBlitzEdito ... Editor.jpg</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />If you look closely you can see material texture options "transmission"... sub surface scattering any one?! That's what I am talking about!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163948" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 6:19 am "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I never realize how "portable" id games are until i try another game that won't let me run it on a technicality.  id games just run (regardless of cpu, vid card, etc).  May need a little tweaking though.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>
<br /><br />That's precisely what makes id Software such a great company. Hell, I bought a computer back in January 2001-2002, and it lasted me all the way until Quake 4 for christ sake, and I even got a decent to high (in soft situations) FPS with 800x600 while running on High settings with Doom 3. 
<br /><br />However, I still am holding out and waiting to get a new video card for my newer system so that I will get something worth my money, rather than a card that's good one day, but shoots bird shit all over my wall with a straw and paperclip attached to two pieces of string, with an apple pie hanging from its feet, two fingernails for eyeballs, and a gumball wrapper for a mouth the next day. So, as a result, I'm still holding back while twiddling my thumbs as I sit and deal with this ancient crock of shit that you would call a Nvidia 6200 Turbocache GPU.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163962" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 10:55 am "><author>modern</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The only reason I'm downloading this is to try the editor.  Hasnt anybody got anything to say about that.  This is a modification site after all!
<br /><br />This engine scares me because its the first thing in two years that might cause me to swap over from doom, and just looking at the material editor is making me drool.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163965" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 1:09 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thats mostly why I downloaded it.  I've made a box map for ut2003 before, but since then I almost completely forgot how everything works since then.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163970" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 3:07 pm "><author>ViPr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">they told me to type this into console to disable the auto-aim:
<br /><br />Set RPartFireable bAutoAimShots False
<br /><br />but i still think they need a beating for even considering putting auto-aim in never mind actually putting it to on by default and not making it an official menu option so you could easily switch it off.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163989" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 10:36 pm "><author>mac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">well i think its also avaiable for console hence the auto aim...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163994" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 11:34 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I got this right after the "Unreal Engine 3" logo apears.
<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236/http://img366.imageshack.us/my.php?image=sanstitre1cn9.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://img366.imageshack.us/img366/5061/sanstitre1cn9.th.jpg" alt="Image" /></a>
<br />Can't run the demo.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p163996" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 11:43 pm "><author>ajm113</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Try redownloading it and see if that helps. Just incase if a file went bad when you where downloading it or something..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p163999" date="Posted: Wed Dec 06, 2006 11:55 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it work now, after a defrag+check disc...  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116223236im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
