<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="18088"><title>If you want to say thanks for D3W...</title><posts><post id="p164472" date="Posted: Tue Dec 12, 2006 4:16 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">... then feel free to make me a happy webmaster by sending me something from my Amazon Wishlist <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912/http://www.amazon.de/gp/registry/registry.html/ref=em-si-ht_gotowl/302-9780722-0364046?ie=UTF8&amp;id=3OVUGARA1QXRF">http://www.amazon.de/gp/registry/regist ... UGARA1QXRF</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />Here's the step-by-step order guide from amazon.de in English:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912/http://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=505538">http://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/d ... eId=505538</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />All items with a shopping cart symbol and the text label "Einkaufswagen" are avilable, those with the yellow button saying "Jetzt vorbestellen" will preorder an item for me (and bill you). 
<br /><br />Sorry for the inconvenience, but thanks for even considering to show me your appreciation!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164476" date="Posted: Tue Dec 12, 2006 5:04 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ich kann Deutschen, keine Weise lesen, die Liste im englischen Aufstellungsort zu erhalten, also weiß ich, welche Teile von Amazonas zum zu klicken?
<br /><br />(just in case babel fish didn't translate well: i can't read German, any way to get the list in the English site so i know what parts of Amazon to click?)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164478" date="Posted: Tue Dec 12, 2006 5:39 pm "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I can't see "Pet Imp in a box" on that list.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164479" date="Posted: Tue Dec 12, 2006 5:49 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good point about the language - I thought the list might be amazon-wide available, but unfortunately it's not.
<br /><br />Here's the step-by-step order guide from amazon.de in English:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912/http://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=505538">http://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/d ... eId=505538</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />All items with a shopping cart symbol and the text label "Einkaufswagen" are avilable, those with the yellow button saying "Jetzt vorbestellen" will preorder an item for me (and bill you).
<br /><br />Who would have thought Amazon is introducing such a hurdle...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164480" date="Posted: Tue Dec 12, 2006 5:50 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">kat wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I can't see "Pet Imp in a box" on that list.</div>
<br /><br />I thought they spawn for free right behind you when you're either reloading (picking food from the fridge) or low with health (the minute you got out of bed).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164484" date="Posted: Tue Dec 12, 2006 6:32 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Who would have thought Amazon is introducing such a hurdle...</div>
<br /><br />Merry Christmas anyway!  I think...  I'm ASSUMING it's going to you.  I had to do some "fill in the blanks" on the babelfish translation so we'll see how this goes.  And how much $$ my cc company charges for a currency exchange!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164496" date="Posted: Tue Dec 12, 2006 8:11 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Who would have thought Amazon is introducing such a hurdle...</div><br /><br />Merry Christmas anyway!  I think...  I'm ASSUMING it's going to you.  I had to do some "fill in the blanks" on the babelfish translation so we'll see how this goes.  And how much $$ my cc company charges for a currency exchange!</div>
<br /><br />Greatly appreciated!!!
<br /><br />Yes, it's going to me for strictly fun purposes <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p164531" date="Posted: Wed Dec 13, 2006 12:07 am "><author>mac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol...its not yet april 1st <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br /><br />edit: took a look at the list.. wow pos godfather game is pretty overpriced 70€ for the x360 version where the pc version is already in the bargain bin for 10€ ?!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164748" date="Posted: Fri Dec 15, 2006 2:36 pm "><author>ajm113</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thats a big list.... Alot bigger then mine that I give to my dad! Its usualy 5 items or so... mainly on programming books or games for my PC or my 360.
<br /><br />Mmm did that game sneak pass me?
<br />Its called Lost Planet: Extreme Condition.
<br />I mite get that for you... I dont know yet. 
<br /><br />I did not know you have a Xbox 360! Whats your gamer tag?  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p164755" date="Posted: Fri Dec 15, 2006 5:26 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i tell ya...  it's cheaper to buy stuff in the us then it is in the Germany.  the prices for those things on amazon.de are ~25% higher then the US prices (after conversion).  i honestly thought it would be more like the US-Canada prices where they are pretty similar (which are pretty close to the same after conversion most of the time).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164775" date="Posted: Fri Dec 15, 2006 9:35 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">i tell ya...  it's cheaper to buy stuff in the us then it is in the Germany.  the prices for those things on amazon.de are ~25% higher then the US prices (after conversion).  i honestly thought it would be more like the US-Canada prices where they are pretty similar (which are pretty close to the same after conversion most of the time).</div>
<br /><br />True true, the EURO is on it's all time high against the USD (which on it's now it relatively low).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164782" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 12:27 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yeah, i thought the euro prices would be lower (in euro's) to be near US prices.
<br /><br />currency has never made sense to me outside the US/Canada relation ship.  On the US/CA border, you can buy something in the US for, say $100.  Buy it in CA in Canadian $ for ~$120.  So the value is ~the same in both countries.  US citizens go to CA for sales &amp; vice versa.  Are countries in Europe like that or is there a "big" price difference between countries?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164783" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 12:55 am "><author>mac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">depends what youre considering to buy and in what direction youre heading.. 
<br />in countries with smaller general income, general items like food etc. are cheaper than in germany but usualy in thoose countries electronics and stuff is highly overprices sometimes even higher than in germany so thoose articles are in no way purchaseable by the normal working class.
<br /><br />gas for example is cheaper in poland and austria.. so near border people tend to take a slightly detours to fill their cars with gas. 
<br /><br />as for games EU wide they are all in the same range.
<br /><br />you should also consider that amazon is pretty expensive either. most
<br />local tech stores have better prices than amazon for example lotr trilogy extended edition cost 45,97€ .. whereas in media markt it costs 39 € (saw it yesterday on xmas shopping) .. amazon takes roughly 18% more, thats alot imho..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164796" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 3:23 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">you should also consider that amazon is pretty expensive either... amazon takes roughly 18% more, thats alot imho..</div>
<br /><br />really?  What you learn every day!  The US amazon is normally lower then the average price.  Again, that depends on where you shop, but in general it's eigther the same as or lower then the store prices.  that also depends on your region too...  i live in New York State &amp; unless you're on the far east side (NYC side) everything is relatively cheap, based on the incomes in the area.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164813" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 8:03 am "><author>whatthe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">*drastically thrust hands into pockets and pulls out... the bottom of the pockets* sorry man, don't have any money, but i have christmas spirit if you want it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164817" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 8:31 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">yeah, i thought the euro prices would be lower (in euro's) to be near US prices.<br /><br />currency has never made sense to me outside the US/Canada relation ship.  On the US/CA border, you can buy something in the US for, say $100.  Buy it in CA in Canadian $ for ~$120.  So the value is ~the same in both countries.  US citizens go to CA for sales &amp; vice versa.  Are countries in Europe like that or is there a "big" price difference between countries?</div>
<br /><br />Well, it's not that easy to determine.
<br /><br />Unlike Mac claims, Germany is the country with the ceapest and therefore lowest quality food available in whole Europe when measured against a purchase power adjusted index. All EU countries can unload their cheap food into Germany as no other European country is so price sensitive when it comes to food. Consumers here love bargaining as if we were living under bridges, even tho Germany still is the largest national economy in Europe and the most important trading partner with the best infrastructure. Strange breed of people we are indeed.
<br /><br />Something being cheap or expensive is always a question where you come from and how much you can take advantage of different EU-regional taxation models for a good you want to purchase.
<br />The EU is not to be understood as a region with highly harmonized prices, quite the difference.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164818" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 8:32 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">you should also consider that amazon is pretty expensive either. most<br />local tech stores have better prices than amazon for example lotr trilogy extended edition cost 45,97€ .. whereas in media markt it costs 39 € (saw it yesterday on xmas shopping) .. amazon takes roughly 18% more, thats alot imho..</div>
<br /><br />That's probably true, but I cannot set up a MediMarket wishlist. So adjusted for flight ticket prices it's a bargain <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p164819" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 8:33 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">whatthe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">*drastically thrust hands into pockets and pulls out... the bottom of the pockets* sorry man, don't have any money, but i have christmas spirit if you want it.</div>
<br /><br />Sure, many thanks for your kindness!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164848" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 6:51 pm "><author>mac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">yeah, i thought the euro prices would be lower (in euro's) to be near US prices.<br /><br />currency has never made sense to me outside the US/Canada relation ship.  On the US/CA border, you can buy something in the US for, say $100.  Buy it in CA in Canadian $ for ~$120.  So the value is ~the same in both countries.  US citizens go to CA for sales &amp; vice versa.  Are countries in Europe like that or is there a "big" price difference between countries?</div><br /><br />Well, it's not that easy to determine.<br /><br />Unlike Mac claims, Germany is the country with the ceapest and therefore lowest quality food available in whole Europe when measured against a purchase power adjusted index. All EU countries can unload their cheap food into Germany as no other European country is so price sensitive when it comes to food. Consumers here love bargaining as if we were living under bridges, even tho Germany still is the largest national economy in Europe and the most important trading partner with the best infrastructure. Strange breed of people we are indeed.<br /><br />Something being cheap or expensive is always a question where you come from and how much you can take advantage of different EU-regional taxation models for a good you want to purchase.<br />The EU is not to be understood as a region with highly harmonized prices, quite the difference.</div>
<br /><br />well as for food i meant the general price.. not looking at the purchase power of the peole in the country. in former jugoslavia for example(not EU but europe) you get alot of stuff alot cheaper like vegtables, milk, bread etc. meat is similar to here so its very expensive over there.. electronics are more expensive than here so its exorbitant over there..
<br /><br />and cheap food in germany doesnt always need to be bad food, if i recall right aldi product for example are in average from very good quality and very cheap.. would love to have a aldi near me <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081116222912im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br /><br />as for germans who loves bargains.. well hehe some does some don't people with money like you prolly don't care or understand.. jobless people like my cousing twist every cent dozen times and is still hardly able to get over the month with his kid and wife. from a sucessfull restaurant owner down to harz4 in a couple of years.  if i recall right the general situation in bavaria down there is pretty good compare to berlin/brandenburg so the levels are different. living up here is cheaper since people earn less.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p164888" date="Posted: Sat Dec 16, 2006 11:42 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">as for germans who loves bargains.. well hehe some does some don't people with money like you prolly don't care or understand..</div>
<br /><br />I understand these situations very very well from my personal experience and the majority of people in Germany does not have to squeeze out the last bit of life from a Cent.
<br /><br />I probably know the differences between Bavaria and Berlin/Brandenburg much better than you do, or, to issue a a more drastic example between Southern Bavaria and Mid Mecklenburg Western Pommerania.
<br />Not to be unfair you should know you're calling the author of dozens of studies in demographic development, purchase power, unemployment rate, centrality index ...(insert a few more buzzwords)... , their interconnection / correlation with certain past to present to future postitive / negative growths into the ring.
<br /><br />Berlin for example is purchase power related one of the most expensive cities to live in while Munich is by absolute numbers most expensive but purchase power related only in the upper third.
<br /><br />People here indeed are bargaining in total mindless ways. As a private person it's fine to spend 40k € of earned money after income taxes for a car which will loose 15% value the moment the turn the key for the first time, but they'll try to cut a deal on food which has steroids, pesticides and antibiotics written all over.
<br />10,-€ per quarter doctors practice visiting fee causes a public outrage, but leather seats for their fancy car are a must.
<br />The mentioning of private retirement funds as a base requirement of individual civil responsibility and self care taking are looked at as a "government forced way to screw them over and disallowing of private important spendigs", but the same people happily finance a flat screen TV over 30 months.
<br /><br />I do not comply with the silly HartzIV reforms, issued out by our beloved former show chancellor Gerhard Schröder - quite the difference!
<br />When I travel the country and see how hard people fight to make a living in the former Eastern Germany federal states, then it's so obvious to see how far away from reality politics of all colours act.
<br />Did you know that over 50% of all people employed in Meck-Pomm commute more than 100km a day to work? In absence of proper public transportation they have to go by car, which became considerably more expensive thanks to our Greens and the oh so social Reds. It shall be noted that these two parties preferrably recruit their voters among those commuters.
<br /><br />What should a person like me suggest to an enemployed person in Berlin / Brandenburg? Move to Munich, Frankfurt a.M. or Hamburg and get a job? What's the chance for someone being unemployed in the 2nd generation? How competitive and smart will a person act in a corporate environment after spending every day ever since his 16th birthday in front of a liquor store out of boredom?
<br /><br />I wish politics would wake up, take the power from the unions and finally start subsidizing work instead of unemployment (which is what the unions try to block at all costs).
<br /><br />People like you only love to point at the success of people like me, but they never pay any respect to the awful amount of hard work invested to reach a certain level. What I pay in taxes keeps more than one unemployed family afloat every month and I'd like to see my tax payers money invested in helping these people out of their misery instead of stripping them of all assets they ever owned and leaving the with a cut down social welfare rate assuming they now might miracously feel pressed to find a job in an area where even schools have closed down public service.
<br /><br />Rant end, thanks for your time.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
