<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="18106"><title>Mod watch: Last Man Standing Coop (D3)</title><posts><post id="p164543" date="Posted: Wed Dec 13, 2006 3:16 am "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yet another great Doom 3 mod is <span style="font-weight: bold">Last Man Standing Coop</span>. To quote,
<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Last Man Standing Coop Mod is a Doom 3 Single Player and Multiplayer cooperative modification that aims to bring back the feel of the classic Dooms. Our LMS Mod gametype is survival in nature where you face swarms of attacking monsters to the adrenaline pumping energy of heavy metal soundtracks. We also fully support Cooperative play in the Single Player levels through the SP Coop gametype and the Doom 3 expansion pack ROE through the gametype ROE Coop. Also the Classic Doom for Doom 3 Mod has been integrated into LMS 3.0 to provide cooperative support!</div>
<br /><br />You can see their website <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://lms.d3files.com/" class="postlink">here</a> for more info, and even <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://lms.d3files.com/downloads.php" class="postlink">download</a> version 3.0 of the mod - at a price tag of around 301mb, it features "SP Coop, ROE Coop and Classic Doom for Doom 3 Coop and of course LMS Mod with over 20 intense custom maps!".
<br /><br />The LMS Coop mod is also taking place on ModDB's <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://awards.moddb.com/2006/" class="postlink">Mod of the Year Awards</a> - this time, on the released mods category. You can vote for them <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://mods.moddb.com/3871/last-man-standing-coop/" class="postlink">here</a>, and there's also a nice teaser/trailer video to check on that website with 6 minutes of some fast coop goodness.
<br /><br />See more on the discussion going on on <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=18105" class="postlink">this thread</a>.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
