<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="18346"><title>John Carmack and id software win Emmy Awards.</title><posts><post id="p166963" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 12:15 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I don't know why this hasn't already been posted here but here it is:
<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">JOHN CARMACK AND ID SOFTWARE’S PIONEERING DEVELOPMENT WORK IN 3D GAME ENGINES RECOGNIZED WITH TWO TECHNOLOGY EMMY AWARDS<br /><br />id Software first independent developer to win the award<br /><br />Las Vegas, Jan. 9, 2007 - id Software had the honor of winning two Technology Emmy Awards from the National Academy of Television Arts &amp; Sciences at the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas on January 8, 2007.  The awards were given as part of the Science, Technology &amp; Engineering Emmy® Awards ceremony.  <br /><br />The Pioneering Development Work in 3D Game Engines award was won by John Carmack, co-founder and technical director of id Software, for his cutting edge contributions to rendering technology as the lead programmer on DOOM®.  id Software, a quintessential leader in technology development, was awarded a second Emmy for the company’s technological leadership in rendering breakthroughs with the QUAKE® technology.  <br /><br />The Technology &amp; Engineering Emmy Awards honor achievements in two areas: Science, Engineering &amp; Technology for Broadcast Television, which includes broadcast, cable and satellite distribution, and secondly, Science, Engineering and Technology  for Broadband and Personal Television, encompassing interactive television, gaming technology, and for the first time, the Internet, cell phones, private networks, and personal media players.  This year represents a milestone for the interactive entertainment industry as id Software is the very first independent game developer to be awarded an Emmy since the Academy began honoring technology innovation in 1948.  <br /><br />“This is an incredible honor for John Carmack and id Software,” says Todd Hollenshead, CEO, id Software. “We consistently push the limits of gaming technology, and it’s great to be recognized for the passion and dedication we put into our games.”<br /><br />id Software has long been heralded as the creator of the first person shooter genre of video games with the release of its many franchises including Wolfenstein, DOOM and QUAKE.  The same revolutionary and proprietary graphics engines for PC, consoles and mobile phones, have also been licensed to multiple developers and publishers who have repeatedly harnessed id technology to create top selling and critically acclaimed titles.  Since 1996, id powered games have generated worldwide revenues in excess of $2 Billion.  id’s most recent internally developed title, DOOM 3®, extends a proven track record with over 3.5 million units sold and is id’s most successful game to date. <br /><br />Having co-founded id Software, John Carmack is responsible for the technology behind some of the most compelling and successful PC game titles of all time. Utilizing largely self taught techniques, Carmack has consistently created the most in-demand and technically sophisticated 3D graphics engines in existence.  Carmack continues to work on advancing the technology of game design with new technologies like MegaTexture, which will appear in id Software’s upcoming Enemy Territory:  QUAKE Wars™.  With several of the most recognized games series ever created to his credit, such as Quake and Doom, Carmack is a technological visionary and a cultural trendsetter.<br /><br />For more information, please visit <!-- w --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.emmyonline.tv/">http://www.emmyonline.tv</a><!-- w -->.</div>
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.idsoftware.com/">http://www.idsoftware.com/</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.emmyonline.org/emmy/advmedia_winners_release.html">http://www.emmyonline.org/emmy/advmedia ... lease.html</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p166964" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 12:29 am "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I don't know why this hasn't already been posted here but here it is:</div>
<br /><br />Maybe because it <span style="font-style: italic">has just happened</span>!
<br /><br />Anyhow, thanks for the heads up. Moved to news.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p166970" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 1:01 am "><author>Zenix</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Go the Carmack!
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://bryan-brown.com:16080/emmy07tech/candids/images/2210_0891.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p166973" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 1:48 am "><author>onu</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Woot!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p166976" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 2:03 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Chea!     
<br /><br /><br />btw.. looks like he's gonna go beat people down with them awards...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p166981" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 2:32 am "><author>Tron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Cool, although these awards are a little skewed, since they only goto companies/people that were actually going to be there.
<br /><br />Case in point, Sony getting an award for their Six Axis controller.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /><br /><br />edit: ok, seems that Sony didn't actually win that award like initial reports said, but was an award shared with Nintendo for general controller development.  Never mind the DualShock controller was basically a SNES controller with two N64 analog sticks stuck on.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p166982" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 2:33 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">zeh wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I don't know why this hasn't already been posted here but here it is:</div><br /><br />Maybe because it <span style="font-style: italic">has just happened</span>!<br /><br />Anyhow, thanks for the heads up. Moved to news.</div>
<br /><br />I guess I'm just too used to Doom3World knowing it before me.
<br /><br />And I thought I posted it in News... Whoops.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p166984" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 2:36 am "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">And I thought I posted it in News... Whoops.</div>
<br /><br />Oh um.. well, maybe you did. I didn't check before moving it (it's rare for people to actually post on the news), I just figured I'd do it automatically.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p167030" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 3:33 pm "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Interesting follow-up interview:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.gameinformer.com/News/Story/200701/N07.0109.1737.15034.htm?Page=1">http://www.gameinformer.com/News/Story/ ... htm?Page=1</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">GI: After Enemy Territories: Quake Wars ships with the highly modified Doom 3 engine and the MegaTexture support, is it time for you guys to move on from that engine?<br /><br />Carmack: <span style="font-weight: bold">Yes, the in-house development project that we’ve been working on is all new technology. It still has some roots in the Doom 3 technology, but almost everything is new in there</span>. We’re still not talking about exactly what the project is, but it’s a new IP, it’s diverting a little bit from the standard id formula and it’s not just a first-person shooter. Technically, it’s build around an advancement over the MegaTexture technology from Quake Wars. Where that was applied just to the terrain, the version of the new technology applies it into everything, so we can have that level of rich detail on all the surfaces on the entire world. That’s the push that we’re making with graphics technology. The gameplay is somewhat different from anything that we’ve of done before. The company is pursuing Wolfenstein, Doom and Quake franchises with other partner developers and all, but we’re trying to develop a brand-new franchise with this new one. Hopefully, we’ll be talking about that sometime this year, and we’ll be able to go ahead and come out of our own little cone of silence about it.</div>
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p167031" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 3:44 pm "><author>Tron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">zeh wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Carmack:  <span style="font-weight: bold">The company is pursuing Wolfenstein, Doom and Quake franchises with other partner developers</span> and all, but we’re trying to develop a brand-new franchise with this new one. Hopefully, we’ll be talking about that sometime this year, and we’ll be able to go ahead and come out of our own little cone of silence about it.</div>
<br /><br />Just an offhand comment or the first hint at a new Doom game of some form being planned?
<br /><br />For the next ID project there are three things I am expecting.
<br /><br />Unique texturing.  Still a mystery how they're going to manage this for a whole project without ending up with a multiple-dvd project.
<br /><br />Advanced lighting.
<br /><br />Seamless loading between levels.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p167033" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 4:38 pm "><author>modern</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Tron wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Unique texturing.  Still a mystery how they're going to manage this for a whole project without ending up with a multiple-dvd project.<br /><br />Advanced lighting.<br /><br />Seamless loading between levels.</div>
<br /><br />Carmack said in the QC 2006 keynote that their "new ip" will use unique texturing on everything.  I believe normal maps will be baked into the mega textures, and there might be less spec maps.  So normal maps might not be on the disc(s).  I think he also said that he's going to use light maps.  He also said in general, normal maps will be completely replaced with height maps (eventually).
<br /><br />I guess if all the texures are megatextures then they are going to be streamed, so potentially no loading screens.
<br /><br />You can download the video here. Thanks to onu for the link:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.planetquake4.net/download.php?op=fileid&amp;lid=2336">http://www.planetquake4.net/download.ph ... d&amp;lid=2336</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p167034" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 5:02 pm "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Kevin Cloud also mentioned seamless level loading when announcing "the next chapter of the wolfenstein universe" in development by Ravel Software...
<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">(...) what we are doing is creating this one large environment that is seamlessly loaded to the player as he explores this world.</div>
<br /><br />...so hopefully it's getting added to the engine itself and will show up on id's next-big-thing (<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.rtcw2.de/" class="postlink">source video</a>).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p167044" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 7:55 pm "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">carmack also mentions some interesting things like the new ip "being not just a first person shooter" "outside of what we have done before". Also he mentioned that it was going to be another 4 year development (I guess we could assume that by now). I am really curious though to the statements he made about "not just being a first person shooter". Perhaps RPG elements?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p167045" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 8:00 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">TelMarine wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">carmack also mentions some interesting things like the new ip "being not just a first person shooter" "outside of what we have done before". Also he mentioned that it was going to be another 4 year development (I guess we could assume that by now). I am really curious though to the statements he made about "not just being a first person shooter". Perhaps RPG elements?</div>
<br /><br />Another 4 years starting when?
<br /><br />I'm fine with a high end game to be under development a long time due to the insane amount of artwork created.
<br /><br />Just curious if this 4 years started in 2004 or last year.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p167048" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 8:07 pm "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">TelMarine wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">carmack also mentions some interesting things like the new ip "being not just a first person shooter" "outside of what we have done before". Also he mentioned that it was going to be another 4 year development (I guess we could assume that by now). I am really curious though to the statements he made about "not just being a first person shooter". Perhaps RPG elements?</div><br /><br />Another 4 years starting when?<br /><br />I'm fine with a high end game to be under development a long time due to the insane amount of artwork created.<br /><br />Just curious if this 4 years started in 2004 or last year.</div>
<br /><br />I assume they started as soon as they got doom3 out the door.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p167049" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 9:16 pm "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Just curious if this 4 years started in 2004 or last year.</div>
<br /><br />It started on 2004 (ish). <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.wired.com/news/culture/games/0,72443-0.html" class="postlink">Another new interview at Wired</a> says "the game won't ship for at least another two years".</div>]]></body></post><post id="p167051" date="Posted: Wed Jan 10, 2007 9:23 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There were whispers of it even before D3 was out the door, from what I recall.  I know Carmack already had the engine coding underway before D3 was completed.
<br /><br />Still, since he hinted they "might" mention something by E3, and definitely by QCon 07, that leads me to think we're a year, maybe two away.  When id finally talks about their new project, you can usually add a year, year and 6 months and get kinda close.  Thankfully they're not like other devs and mention it 3 years before their intended release. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
