<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="18344"><title>Imported Model too large</title><posts><post id="p166950" date="Posted: Tue Jan 09, 2007 8:51 pm "><author>Lumpengnom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi,&#13;<br />I read a thread about this problem but can´t find it anymore. I created a new weapon and replaced the doom standard pistol with it. When i imported it it works but it is way too large. What´s the problem here?&#13;<br /><br />&lt;edit&gt;The model was created, rigged and animated in max 8 and it was the same size as the standard pistol. I then exported wit der_tons exporter&lt;/edit&gt;</div>]]></body></post><post id="p166954" date="Posted: Tue Jan 09, 2007 9:44 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Long time ago, in a far... oups, sorry...  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />Usually i got this problem in the past when i rescaled one or more bones/helpers in max after it's creation, even if it was not keyed, even if it was before skinning it to your weapon.&#13;<br /><br />Don't know how, but the exporter know the bone/helper original dimensions, and export it as this dimension (cause exporter don't export scales animations), and so, when the exporter redimension your bone/helper to fit to its original size, it deform your model aswell.&#13;<br /><br />That's the only answer i know for this sort of resulting problem, maybe there are others possibilities.&#13;<br /><br />To solve this (if it's really that, try to remember if you scaled any bone), you MUST create new bones... and so, redo all your anims and vertex skinning.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p171852" date="Posted: Thu Mar 01, 2007 5:12 pm "><author>Marineofuac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah this happens to me many times!&#13;<br />Always remember Size your model to fit the hand first.&#13;<br />THEN rig/skin it up.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
