<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="18725"><title>Why are the spec maps colored?</title><posts><post id="p170279" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 4:34 pm "><author>Displaced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just wondering...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170288" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 5:38 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">because just black wouldn't show any changes in the spec value's.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170290" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 6:20 pm "><author>Lumpengnom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">because just black wouldn't show any changes in the spec value's.</div>&#13;<br /><br />I guess he´s asking why are they colored and not grayscale.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170291" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 6:37 pm "><author>Kamikazee</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Isn't that to give more of a different colour tone to the highlighted parts of the texture?&#13;<br /><br />See <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing#Specular_maps" class="postlink">Modwiki: Specular maps</a>.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170292" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 6:49 pm "><author>Bittoman</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">As far as I know there isn't a requirement for it to be colored but with the right tweaking of the color values you can really bring out the color of a diffusemap with a high quality specularmap.  In my opinion, you can make a texture look better with just a high quality specular than with just a really good normalmap.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170295" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 7:14 pm "><author>BlackArmsShadow</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Bittoman wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">As far as I know there isn't a requirement for it to be colored but with the right tweaking of the color values you can really bring out the color of a diffusemap with a high quality specularmap.  In my opinion, you can make a texture look better with just a high quality specular than with just a really good normalmap.</div>&#13;<br />See Halo 1, for instance.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170303" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 9:37 pm "><author>Displaced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok. Thanks.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170309" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 10:40 pm "><author>parsonsbear</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok, but does anyone know the real reason for the colors involved? It's not really intuitive, but there seems to be an inversion of the diffuse that seems popular. The specular on blood for example has a teal cast... any hints?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170314" date="Posted: Sun Feb 11, 2007 11:14 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Let's take a cherub for exemple, "tail" &amp; "wings" got a cool 'blue fly' effect because of speculars.&#13;<br /><br />Speculars define how the diffuse will be at light, if you just put a full white specular on a red diffuse, lighted zones will be white, but if you put a blue specular, lighted zone will be a blueish red...&#13;<br /><br />But that's not so simple, cause specular define the color, but also the level of intensity of it. you can't have a red diffuse turning to a black specular (lighted zones).&#13;<br />More your specular is dark, less diffuse will "shine".</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170319" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 12:14 am "><author>onu</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Check out the fist models to see just how important colored spec is.  Diffuse is Green and Specular is Purple if I recall correctly.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170351" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 2:07 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">onu wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Check out the fist models to see just how important colored spec is.  Diffuse is Green and Specular is Purple if I recall correctly.</div>&#13;<br />We don't have the same version so, i just checked (D3), and arms in both "berzeker" &amp; "hands" weapons got a pink skin diffuse, but a dark grey/black specular.&#13;<br /><br />Speculars don't need to be the diffuse inverted colors, just the color you choose it to be where it shine.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170355" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 2:16 pm "><author>Black Dog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">The specular on blood for example has a teal cast... any hints?</div>&#13;<br /><br />Somebody explained that to me as "the specular fighting with the diffuse to produce desaturation in highlights".&#13;<br /><br />The idea is that as the specular contribution grows (towards the center of a highlight), it will "fight" the opposite colours of the diffuse and desaturate the highlight more than a pure white specular contribution would.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170365" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 4:34 pm "><author>Displaced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for replies, guys. At first the spec maps appeared to me as basically inverted and tweaked diffuse maps, but I checked them in photoshop and it looks like they're actually totally re-painted, most of the time. Anyhow: Weird, unexpected and quite interesting...&#13;<br /><br />Edit: Typo</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170385" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 10:33 pm "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Displaced wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">it looks like they're actually totally re-painted, most of the time. Anyhow: Weird, unsuspected and quite interesting...</div>&#13;<br /><br />What's so weird about specular maps? I think your question actually is not "why are they colored", but "what are they", right?&#13;<br />In order to produce good specular maps yourself, you should know how they tie in with the lighting model, what they do and why they exist. &#13;<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phong_reflection_model">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phong_reflection_model</a><!-- m -->&#13;<br />This wikipedia article is not a good read for artists, maybe someone has a link to a better article. Also, if you happen to have Max or Maya, their tutorials have some good information too.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170387" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 11:03 pm "><author>Lumpengnom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="quotetitle">3DS Max Reference wrote:</div>
  <div class="quotecontent">Specular mapping is used primarily for special effects such as placing an image in a reflection. The important thing to remember is that, unlike Specular Level or Glossiness mapping, which alter the intensity and location of specular highlights, specular mapping alters the color of specular highlights.</div>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170390" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 11:19 pm "><author>Displaced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">der_ton wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">What's so weird about specular maps? I think your question actually is not "why are they colored", but "what are they", right?</div>&#13;<br /><br />No. The question is what it was. I wondered why it wasn't just greyscale, like a heightmap, where white was 100% specularity and black 0%. Yes, I found it weird and unexpected that color should be a part of the equation, as a specular light is a reflection of a light source and <span style="font-style: italic">that light source's color</span> mixed with the color of the surface reflecting it, or at least that's how it is in the non-virtual world. As the local color of the surface is already given in the diffuse map, I found it kinda weird, but then again I'm an artist, and not a tech wiz... Thanks for the link, anyways!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170394" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 11:42 pm "><author>Displaced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Lumpengnom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">3DS Max Reference wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Specular mapping is used primarily for special effects such as placing an image in a reflection. The important thing to remember is that, unlike Specular Level or Glossiness mapping, which alter the intensity and location of specular highlights, specular mapping alters the color of specular highlights.</div></div>&#13;<br /><br />But specular mapping would here translate from Max to game engine as what is usually used for "simple reflection", right? In other words the faking of world reflection on a surface, for instance water, by the use of a flat image of the world reflected? But the D3 engine uses the one map for two things, specular level as well as the color of the highlights? I still don't quite understand why altering the color of the highlights is needed, because it doesn't translate very well to my understanding of the real world, heh...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170396" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 11:46 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This is another good link.&#13;<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.bencloward.com/shaders_skin.shtml">http://www.bencloward.com/shaders_skin.shtml</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p170397" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 11:53 pm "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Even if it doesn't happen often, there ARE real world materials that reflect a different color in their specular reflection than in their diffuse. Skin for example, or those modern car paints.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p170398" date="Posted: Mon Feb 12, 2007 11:56 pm "><author>Displaced</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Speculars define how the diffuse will be at light, if you just put a full white specular on a red diffuse, lighted zones will be white, but if you put a blue specular, lighted zone will be a blueish red...</div><br /><br />And why would one want that unless the light source was actually blue? To me that sounds like you can only light a model with a blue spec map with a blue light to make the whole thing look correct in according to it's environment?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">But that's not so simple, cause specular define the color, but also the level of intensity of it. you can't have a red diffuse turning to a black specular (lighted zones).<br />More your specular is dark, less diffuse will "shine".</div>&#13;<br /><br />Now this I understand, however, and is basically all I expected spec maps to be about from the beginning.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
