<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="19883"><title>Annoying MD5 mesh problem</title><posts><post id="p181977" date="Posted: Mon Jun 25, 2007 12:08 am "><author>ertenn</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hello,
<br />I have this little, but very annoying, problem, that I cannot figure out a solution for. I am hoping some of you can help me with this.
<br /><br />I have created a weapon model mesh and idle animation (which does not actually contain any animation - it is just a copy of the mesh file for testing) in Maya 6.0. It is rigged, skinned and UV mapped and exports fine using the exportModels command from the ingame console. However, when I view the model ingame a few of the faces look all wrong (see image below).
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.asmuss.dk/shotatj2.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />The lower image is what it looks like when rendered in Maya.
<br /><br />It seems as if the light hits the faces in a weird way. Or the faces may be invisible, so that it is actually the inside of the model showing (hard to see). 
<br /><br />I just tried re-rigging and skinning it again, but it still gives the same result, so I'm thinking it might be the mesh itself that's somehow causing the problem. I prefer not to start all over on the model, so before I do that I would like to hear if anyone else has had similar problems and knows what caused them? Or if anyone has an idea to where the problem could be (model, rigging, skin weights, shader, export, def file...)?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p181979" date="Posted: Mon Jun 25, 2007 12:33 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hard to tell w/o looking at the actual model.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p181982" date="Posted: Mon Jun 25, 2007 1:04 am "><author>ertenn</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kristus wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Hard to tell w/o looking at the actual model.</div>
<br /><br />Yea, I suppose so. I did not want to bother you with file downloads and stuff, but I uploaded the md5 mesh, anim and maya file (v. 6.0) now, in case you (or someone else) could spare a few minutes to have a look at it. Would be much appreciated <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />.
<br /><br />Edit: The problem is not always as obvious as in the images. It is easiest to see if you look down at the ground with a light source directly above.
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.asmuss.dk/models_atj.rar" class="postlink">Download here</a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p181989" date="Posted: Mon Jun 25, 2007 2:27 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I think I know what is causing it, you got polies overlapping eachother at that place of seam on the UV map. It's got quite a few of those places actually, but this one was easiest to spot since it was directly in the viewers direction.
<br /><br />BTW; not to be an jackass about your work or anything. But I really got to say that you really should invest the time to make a hi-poly version of your models and generate the normalmap from that instead. What you've done here pretty much makes the normalmap superfluous.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p181990" date="Posted: Mon Jun 25, 2007 2:56 am "><author>ertenn</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ah, the UV map. Did not think that would cause an effect like that, thank you.
<br /><br />You can be a jackass all you want <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" />; critique (the constructive kind at least) is always welcome. I am still pretty new to Doom 3 modding, and modding in general, so that is why I haven't taken the time to get into hi-poly normalmapping yet - seems like a lot of work, and there's still a lot of other stuff I need to learn. But I'll look into it, thanks for the tip.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
