<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20152"><title>Soft Edged Alpha + Diffuse?</title><posts><post id="p184406" date="Posted: Tue Jul 24, 2007 10:05 pm "><author>ShaZe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">just a little question, is it possible to make a soft edged alpha texture that handle shadows..? <br /><br />Nothing seem to work, each time, the whole model is highlighted.<br /><br />I don't want a Hard edged Alpha (blend diffuseMap)<br /><br />here's my line :<br /><br />textures/cobjects/brushtextures/star<br />{<br />        qer_editorimage gfx/effects/tavern/star_ed.tga<br />        {<br />                blend blend<br />                map gfx/effects/tavern/star_d.tga<br />        }<br />	{<br />		blend add<br />		map gfx/effects/tavern/star_g.tga<br />	}<br /><br />}<br /><br />There's the alpha parameter, a glow map, the editor texture, and nothing else. I tryed to add a diffusemap, it did't worked, and I searched within the differents settings available for materials files and didn't found anything...<br /><br />Did I made a mistake? Or is it just not possible?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184408" date="Posted: Tue Jul 24, 2007 10:43 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's not possible. Read the notes here...<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/AlphaTest_%28Material_stage_keyword%29">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/AlphaTest_% ... keyword%29</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p185002" date="Posted: Thu Aug 02, 2007 9:57 am "><author>Super Happy Cow</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">tgharebvyjra<br /><br />Dammit. I'm supposed to build a tree for a mod, and it's being a pain in the udder for this, and a few other reasons. ; [<br /><br />Since the alphas can't affect the shadow of the tree, I have to make the leaves cast no shadow. Since the leaves can't cast a shadow, the tree casting a shadow by itself would look ridiculous. The entire tree must cast no shadows.<br /><br />The alpha keyword only works with "blend    blend" which isn't affected by light, which would look horrible on a tree in Q4.<br />Alphatest affects diffuse maps, but deform turbulent, when applied to a material with alphatest, only affects the alphamap, causing leaves to become masked and visible areas in the alpha to mask invisible.<br /><br />It's hard as hell to make a decent looking tree in Quake 4. No wonder there weren't any in the game. D:</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185015" date="Posted: Thu Aug 02, 2007 2:55 pm "><author>parsonsbear</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">why not make a projected light/shadow for the tree, and have the tree cast no shadows? unless it's destructable or near a moving light, should work ok (and cheap)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185017" date="Posted: Thu Aug 02, 2007 3:15 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">or even a decal...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185022" date="Posted: Thu Aug 02, 2007 4:48 pm "><author>jcdenton22</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pbmax wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">or even a decal...</div><br /><br />Nope, that wouldn't work. When an object comes under/near tree, it wouldn't be receiving the shadow of the tree, if done that way. So a projected light should do the trick well.<br /><br />Edit:<br />I dont have Doom 3 installed on this PC now, so I am not so sure about this. But it may help. See how hellmagot material shader is written in D3 or even those souls' material shaders. They receive shadows, I dont know whether they could cast one as well.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185046" date="Posted: Fri Aug 03, 2007 3:01 am "><author>Super Happy Cow</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hellmagot? ; [ Someone would have to upload that one for me, since I only have Quake 4, and never played D3. D:<br /><br />A projected light sounds interresting, but then, what if something passes in front of that light, or if the light's radius interacts with other lights? Or is it possible to have a light affect only one object, and nothing else around it?</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
