<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20163"><title>my gun looks like a shadow</title><posts><post id="p184482" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 12:14 am "><author>kingmarty</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm trying to add a weapon to doom 3 however in game the weapons is black and transparent.<br />I don't know how to fix this. I'm not sure if its a texturing problem or what.<br />If ther is a better place to post this would you please tell me.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184488" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 2:01 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it's a texture problem, make sure the material is assigned to it correctly.  What format model is it?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184495" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 3:13 am "><author>kingmarty</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm not sure what format model it is.  The gun is the quake 4 lightninggun.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184503" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 9:37 am "><author>Kamikazee</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If you just ported it from the original Quake 4 models to Doom 3, don't bother. You are not allowed to move official content from one game to another.<br /><br />If it's a custom model, check the material script.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184506" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 12:53 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There is nothing wrong trying this kind of things as long as He won't release any stuff...<br /><br /><br /><br />Some time ago I ported lots of Half life 2 characters into doom just for fun...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200322" date="Posted: Sat Jun 14, 2008 5:25 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey peeps! im having that same problem as kingmarty. except i am using md5 models for doom 3. im working on the hell knight. when i spawn him. he turns all black. like a shadow. like what kingmarty explained. im thinking this is a texture problem . but im not sure. i have posted this problem in my other topics.  <!-- l --><a class="postlink-local" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121121418/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=21624">viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=21624</a><!-- l --><br />if there is a texture editor or something. i would love to know. <br /><br /><br />peace</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200325" date="Posted: Sat Jun 14, 2008 6:48 pm "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">In most of these cases, it is not a wrong material definition, but the connection between the model and the material isn't there in the first place. What's the name of your material definition? What's the name of the material that is referenced in the md5mesh file's "shader" lines (don't tell me you haven't opened it yet)? Where do you store your .mtr file?<br />In a nutshell, and ignoring some details like skin definitions, the connection goes like this: a md5mesh file (its name or folder location is irrelevant for the material to show up) has lines with the keyword "shader", followed by a material name. Doom3 will look through all .mtr files in the "materials" folder and search for a material definition that matches that name. That, by the way, implies that the name of your .mtr file is irrelevant, the important thing is the material names inside of these files.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200342" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 5:01 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok. i dont know what your asking for. lol. i dont know what an .mrt file is but i can make a guess, right? these are all the steps i did for my doom project. ALL!<br /><br />1) i imported my crap in blender<br /><br />2) i made changes with the doom 3 textures i imported. these texture files are .tga   i messed with the spec and ref. and all that jazz.<br /><br />3) then i exported my blend file to the orginall doom 3 mesh. then it came to this.....<img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121121418im_/http://photos-a.ak.facebook.com/photos-ak-sf2p/v289/11/103/690325082/n690325082_3256104_224.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />im wondering if i need to edit the tga file itself. idk guys. im a noob. so sorry<br /><br /><br />peace</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200344" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 5:45 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Given you're working with Blender I'm going to assume you are familiar with it correct? That said, you know how in Blender you have to tell it where your image files are before you can apply a texture to an object? Well when you do that, the images don't become part of the model file. Instead, you're just telling Blender what images you want to use and where they are.<br /><br />This is called a reference and they are used heavily in Doom 3, Quake 4, ect...<br /><br />It's the same problem at play here with Doom 3. You've got a working model but it's black because the "texture" reference is incorrect. There's nothing wrong with the images. The game just doesn't know what images you want to use.<br /><br />In order to correct the problem, you have to edit the reference. And since MD5mesh (and ASE for that matter) files are plain text you can edit them manually with a text editor like notepad. If you're running Windows you can click Start &gt; Programs &gt; Accessories &gt; Notepad to start it.<br /><br />From this point it's simply a matter of opening your MD5mesh file and finding the lines (yes there can be, and in the case of the hellknight there is, more than one) that look like this...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "somethingsomethingsomething"</div><br /><br />In the case of the hellknight there should be four lines like this. What these lines do is reference material shaders which for all intensive purposes are the "textures" in Doom 3, Quake 4, ect... When you have the time you should read about texturing on modwiki to learn more about them. It will answer your questions.<br /><br />For now however, all you're interested in doing is editing each shader line so you have all four of these...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/hellknight"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob2"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/tongue"</div><br /><br />... present in your modified MD5mesh in that order.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200350" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 1:03 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey. i do really know alot about getting around blender and all that jazz. but i have never ever used notepad for this technique. i really hope you'd be kind enough to show me how to accomplish this. <br /><br /><br />peace</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200353" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 3:07 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">RIGHT CLICK on the MD5Mesh file<br /><br />Select OPEN WITH<br /><br />Choose NOTEPAD or WORDPAD</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200354" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 3:37 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok....now what. do i add those codes? if so, how.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200355" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 4:13 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">CTRL+C (copy) <br />CTRL+V (paste)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200356" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 4:23 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol. i know that step. ill try it but........is there a certain place for it....gosh im stupid    sorry</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200357" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 4:44 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok first id like to thank you all for your help. like i said i just pick up this stuff a few months ago so im gonna have alot of questions. heres where i am. i put the code down into notepad. but then this happened.................<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121121418im_/http://photos-c.ak.facebook.com/photos-ak-snc1/v262/11/103/690325082/n690325082_3265322_370.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />i get a box. a small black box. but i can shoot it. and i can kill it. and i can here that burn away effect when i kill it. in that console that i type to spawn my monster. i get a message saying something like "this has no aas file" thats not the exact words.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200360" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 6:09 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmm, weird. <br /><br />My best guess is you did something "wrong", so if you fix it and make it "right", it should all look and work properly.<br /><br />Good luck with that!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200363" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 6:38 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">if only it was that easy <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121121418im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200364" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 6:59 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It is that easy. <br /><br />Proof: I received a nice polite query in my email this morning from a person in this forum named "Kevin Nielsen". He asked for some help with the exact same issue you have now. He sent me the files I requested packed as I suggested, and I sent him back the solution 5 minutes later.<br /><br />I'd help you in the same way but "lol im a noob and im too busy to try to figure ANY of it out by myself so instead i will post a new thread every 10 minutes until someone holds my hand"  totally diminishes any desire to help you, which sucks, because your problem is really easy.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121121418im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200368" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 8:35 pm "><author>wal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I think your making it more complicated than it is.<div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">For now however, all you're interested in doing is editing each shader line so you have all four of these...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/hellknight"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob2"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/tongue"</div><br /><br />... present in your modified MD5mesh in that order.</div>If all you're trying to do is assign materials then if you only change those references you shouldn’t break the mesh (which is probly why you're getting the black box).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200369" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 9:31 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">do i put those codes UNder all the gibberish.lol.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200521" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 10:06 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">omg....please.....why do people have to put people down all the time. our own species hating each other. do you see rabbits doing this?     sry for being a douche bag.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200538" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 4:29 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div>
  <div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">pistonfan92 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">[quote]MD5Version 10<br />commandline ""<br /><br />numJoints 0<br />numMeshes 3<br /><br />joints {<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}[/quote]</div></div><br />So, you didn't exported the hellknight model, as you can see, the MD5 contains 0 joints (bones for animation) and 0 meshes...<br />Try to export it right, then redo the steps to know model's shaders<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200543" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 10:12 am "><author>wal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pistonfan92 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">our own species hating each other. do you see rabbits doing this?</div>How the hell would we know if they were <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /> They could all be bastard bunnies.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200563" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 10:41 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">When I was a child, my family had a pet rabbit that chewed an extension cord and died from electrocution. My mom made stew out of it (the rabbit, not the extension cord). It was fairly tasty, but my mom is a decent cook.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200569" date="Posted: Fri Jun 20, 2008 3:25 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol. wow. interesting. my sister bought a rabbit. but then it dies after 15 days. lol. it just...died.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200613" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 2:35 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">when you guys say shaders...do you mean textures?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200614" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 2:36 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">o yeah    and what md5 mesh file do i save it to. or doesnt it matter. like can i work with a copy of the original hellknight mesh?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200618" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 5:59 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">A <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing#Material_shaders" class="postlink">material shader</a> is a <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Declarations" class="postlink">declaration</a>. It serves the purpose of a "texture" but in technical terms it's a text based definition that can reference multiple images.<br /><br />You can replace assets to simplify things but it's bad practice. You should be creating new assets instead of replacing old ones. In the case of a modified hellknight model, you should...<br /><br /><ul><li>Make your adjustments to the hellknight model and export it to a new MD5mesh.</li><li>Create a new model declaration that inherits from the original and uses your new MD5mesh</li><li>Create a new entity declaration that inherits from the original and uses your new model declaration</li></ul><br />So how do you do these things step by step? Nevermind that. It's too ambitious when you don't know what a declaration is. It's best to walk before you run.<br /><br />So where do you start? Well since you don't know what a declaration is, and it's critical that you learn if you are to follow through with this project of yours, you can read about them here...<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Declarations">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Declarations</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Once you understand that, even if only in part, you should try writing declarations to see if you understand what you've read. Try writing a <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing#Material_shaders" class="postlink">material shader</a> and then test it in a map using the level editor. You don't have to paint images. Just use images that come with the game.<br /><br />Apply what you've learned to writing an entity declaration. Make a new type of Imp that has more health or something stupid like that. Learn what a few of the various key/value pairs do. Learn how you can use the "inherit" key/value pair to spare yourself from copying and pasting necessary key/value pairs that you don't intend to change from a pre-existing declaration.<br /><br />Once you've done those things you should be ready to perform the three steps outlined above.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200620" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 6:14 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">rich_is_bored, or anyone, there was a good "this is connected to that" schematic diagram done up for the various game asset relations. If it could be found, this may be a good thread to repost it in.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200625" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 8:41 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The diagram you're talking about is on the wiki, specifically in the declarations article I linked to. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200642" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 9:22 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey anybody. what exact folder did you place your blender2md5mesh in. and i still get this when i export the blend mesh......<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">MD5Version 10<br />commandline ""<br /><br />numJoints 0<br />numMeshes 3<br /><br />joints {<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br /></div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200882" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 6:32 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok heres the update.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /> i figured it out. it only took me this long because i m busy ok.  i really really appreciate all of your help and time.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200886" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 7:22 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well clue us in. What were you doing? What did you do to correct the problem?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200899" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 10:18 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Happy you finally solved it!<br /><br />What was the mistake?<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121083116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p184482" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 12:14 am "><author>kingmarty</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm trying to add a weapon to doom 3 however in game the weapons is black and transparent.<br />I don't know how to fix this. I'm not sure if its a texturing problem or what.<br />If ther is a better place to post this would you please tell me.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184488" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 2:01 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it's a texture problem, make sure the material is assigned to it correctly.  What format model is it?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184495" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 3:13 am "><author>kingmarty</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm not sure what format model it is.  The gun is the quake 4 lightninggun.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184503" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 9:37 am "><author>Kamikazee</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If you just ported it from the original Quake 4 models to Doom 3, don't bother. You are not allowed to move official content from one game to another.<br /><br />If it's a custom model, check the material script.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p184506" date="Posted: Thu Jul 26, 2007 12:53 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There is nothing wrong trying this kind of things as long as He won't release any stuff...<br /><br /><br /><br />Some time ago I ported lots of Half life 2 characters into doom just for fun...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200322" date="Posted: Sat Jun 14, 2008 5:25 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey peeps! im having that same problem as kingmarty. except i am using md5 models for doom 3. im working on the hell knight. when i spawn him. he turns all black. like a shadow. like what kingmarty explained. im thinking this is a texture problem . but im not sure. i have posted this problem in my other topics.  <!-- l --><a class="postlink-local" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121080529/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=21624">viewtopic.php?f=2&amp;t=21624</a><!-- l --><br />if there is a texture editor or something. i would love to know. <br /><br /><br />peace</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200325" date="Posted: Sat Jun 14, 2008 6:48 pm "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">In most of these cases, it is not a wrong material definition, but the connection between the model and the material isn't there in the first place. What's the name of your material definition? What's the name of the material that is referenced in the md5mesh file's "shader" lines (don't tell me you haven't opened it yet)? Where do you store your .mtr file?<br />In a nutshell, and ignoring some details like skin definitions, the connection goes like this: a md5mesh file (its name or folder location is irrelevant for the material to show up) has lines with the keyword "shader", followed by a material name. Doom3 will look through all .mtr files in the "materials" folder and search for a material definition that matches that name. That, by the way, implies that the name of your .mtr file is irrelevant, the important thing is the material names inside of these files.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200342" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 5:01 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok. i dont know what your asking for. lol. i dont know what an .mrt file is but i can make a guess, right? these are all the steps i did for my doom project. ALL!<br /><br />1) i imported my crap in blender<br /><br />2) i made changes with the doom 3 textures i imported. these texture files are .tga   i messed with the spec and ref. and all that jazz.<br /><br />3) then i exported my blend file to the orginall doom 3 mesh. then it came to this.....<img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121080529im_/http://photos-a.ak.facebook.com/photos-ak-sf2p/v289/11/103/690325082/n690325082_3256104_224.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />im wondering if i need to edit the tga file itself. idk guys. im a noob. so sorry<br /><br /><br />peace</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200344" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 5:45 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Given you're working with Blender I'm going to assume you are familiar with it correct? That said, you know how in Blender you have to tell it where your image files are before you can apply a texture to an object? Well when you do that, the images don't become part of the model file. Instead, you're just telling Blender what images you want to use and where they are.<br /><br />This is called a reference and they are used heavily in Doom 3, Quake 4, ect...<br /><br />It's the same problem at play here with Doom 3. You've got a working model but it's black because the "texture" reference is incorrect. There's nothing wrong with the images. The game just doesn't know what images you want to use.<br /><br />In order to correct the problem, you have to edit the reference. And since MD5mesh (and ASE for that matter) files are plain text you can edit them manually with a text editor like notepad. If you're running Windows you can click Start &gt; Programs &gt; Accessories &gt; Notepad to start it.<br /><br />From this point it's simply a matter of opening your MD5mesh file and finding the lines (yes there can be, and in the case of the hellknight there is, more than one) that look like this...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "somethingsomethingsomething"</div><br /><br />In the case of the hellknight there should be four lines like this. What these lines do is reference material shaders which for all intensive purposes are the "textures" in Doom 3, Quake 4, ect... When you have the time you should read about texturing on modwiki to learn more about them. It will answer your questions.<br /><br />For now however, all you're interested in doing is editing each shader line so you have all four of these...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/hellknight"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob2"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   shader "models/monsters/hellknight/tongue"</div><br /><br />... present in your modified MD5mesh in that order.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200350" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 1:03 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey. i do really know alot about getting around blender and all that jazz. but i have never ever used notepad for this technique. i really hope you'd be kind enough to show me how to accomplish this. <br /><br /><br />peace</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200353" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 3:07 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">RIGHT CLICK on the MD5Mesh file<br /><br />Select OPEN WITH<br /><br />Choose NOTEPAD or WORDPAD</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200354" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 3:37 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok....now what. do i add those codes? if so, how.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200355" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 4:13 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">CTRL+C (copy) <br />CTRL+V (paste)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200356" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 4:23 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol. i know that step. ill try it but........is there a certain place for it....gosh im stupid    sorry</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200357" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 4:44 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok first id like to thank you all for your help. like i said i just pick up this stuff a few months ago so im gonna have alot of questions. heres where i am. i put the code down into notepad. but then this happened.................<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121080529im_/http://photos-c.ak.facebook.com/photos-ak-snc1/v262/11/103/690325082/n690325082_3265322_370.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />i get a box. a small black box. but i can shoot it. and i can kill it. and i can here that burn away effect when i kill it. in that console that i type to spawn my monster. i get a message saying something like "this has no aas file" thats not the exact words.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200360" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 6:09 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmm, weird. <br /><br />My best guess is you did something "wrong", so if you fix it and make it "right", it should all look and work properly.<br /><br />Good luck with that!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200363" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 6:38 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">if only it was that easy <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121080529im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200364" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 6:59 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It is that easy. <br /><br />Proof: I received a nice polite query in my email this morning from a person in this forum named "Kevin Nielsen". He asked for some help with the exact same issue you have now. He sent me the files I requested packed as I suggested, and I sent him back the solution 5 minutes later.<br /><br />I'd help you in the same way but "lol im a noob and im too busy to try to figure ANY of it out by myself so instead i will post a new thread every 10 minutes until someone holds my hand"  totally diminishes any desire to help you, which sucks, because your problem is really easy.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121080529im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200368" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 8:35 pm "><author>wal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I think your making it more complicated than it is.<div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">For now however, all you're interested in doing is editing each shader line so you have all four of these...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/hellknight"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob2"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/gob"</div><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent"> shader "models/monsters/hellknight/tongue"</div><br /><br />... present in your modified MD5mesh in that order.</div>If all you're trying to do is assign materials then if you only change those references you shouldn’t break the mesh (which is probly why you're getting the black box).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200369" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 9:31 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">do i put those codes UNder all the gibberish.lol.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200370" date="Posted: Sun Jun 15, 2008 9:55 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok i did that and i got a message saying <br />"WARNING: couldnt load image: emptyname"<br />"WARNING: idal_monster_demon_hellknight_192 has no AAS file"</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200371" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 12:00 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The text in notepad isn't actually jibberish. It just appears that way because by default notepad has word wrap enabled. To turn it off click Format &gt; Word Wrap.<br /><br /><div class="attachtitle">Attachment:</div><div class="attachcontent">			<span class="genmed">
				<img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/styles/subsilver2/imageset/icon_topic_attach.gif" width="14" height="18" alt="" title="" /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/download/file.php?id=121">Capture-3.gif</a> [33.57 KB]
			</span><br /><span class="gensmall">Downloaded 17 times</span>
		
		<br /></div><br /><br />The shader lines I pointed out earlier go in the place of the four existing shader lines. It should be easy to find them now that the text is more legible. They look like this...<br /><br /><div class="attachtitle">Attachment:</div><div class="attachcontent">			<span class="genmed">
				<img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/styles/subsilver2/imageset/icon_topic_attach.gif" width="14" height="18" alt="" title="" /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/download/file.php?id=122">Capture-5.gif</a> [31.18 KB]
			</span><br /><span class="gensmall">Downloaded 16 times</span>
		
		<br /></div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200375" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 1:01 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok. i did everything you said for me to do. exactly. but when i spawn my mesh the game shuts down and goes to the main menu. do i need all the textures. i only did the ones you posted. here are all the textures i messed with in blender........<br />hellknight.tga<br />hellknight_local.tga<br />tongue.tga<br /><br />i didnt have a gob2 texture. i just made a different color for it. and i deleted gob from the hellknight. do you think i should have left the gob there on the hellknight? do you think i should have all of the textures loaded on him. o and the hellknight objects name is hellknigh    with out the t. lol.<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://photos-c.ak.facebook.com/photos-ak-snc1/v262/11/103/690325082/n690325082_3270866_5779.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200379" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 2:58 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">100% wrong in your execution.<br /><br />Let's go back to an original request:<br /><br />Open your MD5Mesh in Notepad or WordPad.<br /><br />Copy and Paste what it says into this thread, then someone can show you exactly what you need to do with no guessing about what you're trying to tell folks.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200381" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 3:10 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">dude. your no help. at all. so just quick putting me down all the time. seriously.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200384" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 3:36 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You put them all in the same spot. There should be four separate places in your MD5mesh where it says "shader". The idea is to replace each line separately.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200387" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 4:32 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i did it how you showed me in the picture and that didnt work. so i tries something myself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200388" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 4:43 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">holy COW guys. this is FUN. im sorry but i like doing this stuff even though i cant figure it out. ive been googling and everything. ive got you guys. and WOW.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" />. i really hope i can figure out how to do this. because i think after i figure this out. im gonna gather up all my knowledge and make a video tut for all!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200397" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 4:34 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">guys.............i really need help. ive tried EVERYTHIIIING!!!! but i believe in myself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200402" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 6:21 pm "><author>wal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="codetitle">
    <b>Code:</b>
  </div>
  <div class="codecontent">mesh {<br />   // meshes: hellknightmesh<br />   shader "INSERT SHADER HERE"<br />mesh {<br />   // meshes: salivamesh<br />   shader "INSERT SHADER HERE"<br />mesh {<br />   // meshes: droolmesh<br />   shader "INSERT SHADER HERE"<br />mesh {<br />   // meshes: tonguemesh<br />   shader "INSERT SHADER HERE"</div>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200403" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 6:28 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Mmmh! It's my turn!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /><br /><br />Ok, let's rewind!<br />1) Re-export your "new model" (meshsmoothed Hellknight),<br />2) Right-click on you new MD5mesh, then click on "open with..." and select notepad/wordpad/context/whatever,<br />3) In it, CTRL-F (or edit=&gt;found/search) then search for the word "shader" (don't close the window),<br />4) take a pen and write down the entire line! (old school method),<br />5) click on the search's windows' NEXT,<br />6) back to step 4 (many time as it's possible without any prompt message like "no more entries")<br />7) come back here, then post as a reply these writed lines, as CODE (use the button).<br /><br />See you soon young skywalker!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200410" date="Posted: Mon Jun 16, 2008 9:19 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i really hope by when you say shaders, you mean textures. and what if the is more than one texture. these are the textures i used for each mesh. I DELETED GOB. but not gob2.(  i dont know if that would be a problem lol ). here they are<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold">tongue</span>-tongue.tga<br /><span style="font-weight: bold">hellknight</span>-hellknight.tga, hellknight_local.tga<br />i didnt have one for the gob2. also in the notepad. it has all 0's for numverts, numtris, numweights. is this a problem too? <br /><br /><br />o and in blender. for the hellknight OB name its hellknigh    without the T.<br /><br /><br /><br />and this is what i get when i open the mesh in notepad.<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">[quote]MD5Version 10<br />commandline ""<br /><br />numJoints 0<br />numMeshes 3<br /><br />joints {<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}[/quote]</div><br /><br /><br /><br /><br />thanks for your time.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200423" date="Posted: Tue Jun 17, 2008 4:32 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pistonfan92 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">[quote]MD5Version 10<br />commandline ""<br /><br />numJoints 0<br />numMeshes 3<br /><br />joints {<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}[/quote]</div></div><br />So, you didn't exported the hellknight model, as you can see, the MD5 contains 0 joints (bones for animation) and 0 meshes...<br />Try to export it right, then redo the steps to know model's shaders<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200427" date="Posted: Tue Jun 17, 2008 7:53 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What we have here is a case of poor inference due to a lack of general knowledge.<br /><br />Anyone ever do that "How to make a peanut butter and jelly sandwich" writing exercise as a child? It's mentally exhausting because when you give someone instruction, you have to make assumptions about what knowledge they already possess. Only in the case of this exercise, the imaginary person you're giving instruction to has no frame of reference.<br /><br />Case in point, you might start with instructions like this...<br /><br /><ul><li>Spread peanut butter on one piece of bread.</li><li>Spread jelly on the other.</li><li>Put both pieces together.</li></ul><br />But in this case, it's assumed that...<br /><br /><ul><li>You know that a sandwich requires two pieces of bread.</li><li>You know that a "piece of bread" means a slice.</li><li>You know where to find the bread, peanut butter, jelly and knife.</li><li>You're familiar with the packaging for each item and how to open them.</li><li>You know to use the knife for spreading.</li><li>You know how to assemble the bread so the peanut butter and jelly are on the inside.</li><li>etc, etc, etc...</li></ul><br />No offense Pistonfan, but you are the "imaginary person" from this exercise. I don't know you but from our exchange so far it's easy to see that you are well in over your head.<br /><br />And while I don't mind pushing someone over the hump when they get stuck, we're going to be holding hands every step of the way because making the assumption that you know how to do something trivial has proven time and time again to be a mistake.<br /><br />It's clear that the ideal way for you to learn would be if someone could sit physically in a room with you and watch over your shoulder or vice versa. And if you were my neighbor, I'd have no problem doing that because it would be kind of cool to get together with people who have a common interest in modding.<br /><br />But since we both know that's not the case, the only way to progress is to assume that your knowledge is limited to where the power button is on the front of your computer and go from there. I know you're not that ignorant but if that's the starting point from which anyone here is to instruct you, then the back and forth question and answer session we're having has no end in sight and to be frank, I'd rather do something else like play a game because typing is boring.<br /><br />You should look into finding a conference or event in your local area where like-minded individuals meet up or try to organize something yourself. Contrary to popular belief, the real world is a better resource than the internet.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200453" date="Posted: Tue Jun 17, 2008 5:26 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok. first. I JUST STARTED BLENDER 8 MONTHS AGO. and i cant do blender all the time like maybe you guys do. and im pretty smart with computers so don't doubt my skills. ok. ok.   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /> and i have a job.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200460" date="Posted: Tue Jun 17, 2008 6:45 pm "><author>wal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This is a windup. I had my suspicions from the start.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200473" date="Posted: Tue Jun 17, 2008 9:40 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">wow</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200495" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 1:38 pm "><author>Ivan_the_B</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What is a windup?  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br />edit: ok found it, never mind  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042449im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200497" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 1:48 pm "><author>wal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">A type of joke basically. Someone pretending. Sorry to Pistonfan92 if it isn't a joke, but you say you've been working with blender for eight months but you can't export (not that I can but I've never used it) and you say you're pretty smart with computers. Plus other stuff you've said makes it seem like a wind up to me.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200501" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 3:42 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pistonfan92 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">do i put those codes UNder all the gibberish.lol.</div><br />lol rofl lmao! <br /><br />Haha!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200521" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 10:06 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">omg....please.....why do people have to put people down all the time. our own species hating each other. do you see rabbits doing this?     sry for being a douche bag.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200538" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 4:29 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div>
  <div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">pistonfan92 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">[quote]MD5Version 10<br />commandline ""<br /><br />numJoints 0<br />numMeshes 3<br /><br />joints {<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}[/quote]</div></div><br />So, you didn't exported the hellknight model, as you can see, the MD5 contains 0 joints (bones for animation) and 0 meshes...<br />Try to export it right, then redo the steps to know model's shaders<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200543" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 10:12 am "><author>wal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pistonfan92 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">our own species hating each other. do you see rabbits doing this?</div>How the hell would we know if they were <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /> They could all be bastard bunnies.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200563" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 10:41 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">When I was a child, my family had a pet rabbit that chewed an extension cord and died from electrocution. My mom made stew out of it (the rabbit, not the extension cord). It was fairly tasty, but my mom is a decent cook.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200569" date="Posted: Fri Jun 20, 2008 3:25 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol. wow. interesting. my sister bought a rabbit. but then it dies after 15 days. lol. it just...died.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200613" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 2:35 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">when you guys say shaders...do you mean textures?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200614" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 2:36 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">o yeah    and what md5 mesh file do i save it to. or doesnt it matter. like can i work with a copy of the original hellknight mesh?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200618" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 5:59 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">A <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing#Material_shaders" class="postlink">material shader</a> is a <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Declarations" class="postlink">declaration</a>. It serves the purpose of a "texture" but in technical terms it's a text based definition that can reference multiple images.<br /><br />You can replace assets to simplify things but it's bad practice. You should be creating new assets instead of replacing old ones. In the case of a modified hellknight model, you should...<br /><br /><ul><li>Make your adjustments to the hellknight model and export it to a new MD5mesh.</li><li>Create a new model declaration that inherits from the original and uses your new MD5mesh</li><li>Create a new entity declaration that inherits from the original and uses your new model declaration</li></ul><br />So how do you do these things step by step? Nevermind that. It's too ambitious when you don't know what a declaration is. It's best to walk before you run.<br /><br />So where do you start? Well since you don't know what a declaration is, and it's critical that you learn if you are to follow through with this project of yours, you can read about them here...<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Declarations">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Declarations</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Once you understand that, even if only in part, you should try writing declarations to see if you understand what you've read. Try writing a <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Texturing#Material_shaders" class="postlink">material shader</a> and then test it in a map using the level editor. You don't have to paint images. Just use images that come with the game.<br /><br />Apply what you've learned to writing an entity declaration. Make a new type of Imp that has more health or something stupid like that. Learn what a few of the various key/value pairs do. Learn how you can use the "inherit" key/value pair to spare yourself from copying and pasting necessary key/value pairs that you don't intend to change from a pre-existing declaration.<br /><br />Once you've done those things you should be ready to perform the three steps outlined above.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200620" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 6:14 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">rich_is_bored, or anyone, there was a good "this is connected to that" schematic diagram done up for the various game asset relations. If it could be found, this may be a good thread to repost it in.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200625" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 8:41 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The diagram you're talking about is on the wiki, specifically in the declarations article I linked to. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200642" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 9:22 pm "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey anybody. what exact folder did you place your blender2md5mesh in. and i still get this when i export the blend mesh......<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">MD5Version 10<br />commandline ""<br /><br />numJoints 0<br />numMeshes 3<br /><br />joints {<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br />mesh {<br />   shader ""<br /><br />   numverts 0<br /><br />   numtris 0<br /><br />   numweights 0<br />}<br /><br /></div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200882" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 6:32 am "><author>pistonfan92</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok heres the update.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /> i figured it out. it only took me this long because i m busy ok.  i really really appreciate all of your help and time.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200886" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 7:22 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well clue us in. What were you doing? What did you do to correct the problem?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200899" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 10:18 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Happy you finally solved it!<br /><br />What was the mistake?<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121082417im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
