<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20274"><title>Armor and health indicators in the pda ?</title><posts><post id="p185626" date="Posted: Wed Aug 08, 2007 9:31 am "><author>0m1n0u5</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok i've been coming back to d3 editing for some time now and working on a project but i found a problem - i can't add a Health and Armor indicator in the pda ... I mean when I add these lines <br />"<br />windowDef Desktop<br />{<br />	rect	0,0,640,480<br />	visible	1<br />	backcolor	1,1,1,1<br />	windowDef MPHealthBlack<br />	{<br />		rect	91, 438, 39, 32<br />		text	"gui::player_health"<br />		forecolor	0, 0, 0, 0.5<br />		textscale	0.38<br />		textalign	1<br />		font	"fonts/micro"<br />		shear	0, -0.33<br />	}<br />	windowDef MPHealth<br />	{<br />		rect	90, 436, 39, 32<br />		text	"gui::player_health"<br />		forecolor	0.5, 0.7, 0.7, 1<br />		textscale	0.38<br />		textalign	1<br />		font	"fonts/micro"<br />		shear	0, -0.33<br />	}<br />	windowDef MPHealth2<br />	{<br />		rect	90, 437, 39, 32<br />		text	"gui::player_health"<br />		forecolor	0.8, 0.7, 0, (70 - "gui::player_health") / 100<br />		textscale	0.38<br />		textalign	1<br />		font	"fonts/micro"<br />		shear	0, -0.33<br />	}<br />}<br />"<br />to a file named "hud.gui" they work, when I create a file named pda.gui with the same code it doesnt work when I access my pda , all I see is the solid white desktop windowdef .</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185632" date="Posted: Wed Aug 08, 2007 12:13 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The reason hud.gui can access player variables is because it's parented to the player entity via the player_base entity declaration...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">entityDef player_base {<br />   "spawnclass"                  "idPlayer"<br />   "scriptobject"                  "player"<br />                              <br />   "hud"                        "guis/hud.gui"<br />   "mphud"                        "guis/mphud.gui"<br />   "cursor"                     "guis/cursor.gui"<br />...</div><br /><br />No such reference is made to pda.gui so player variables are out of it's scope.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185808" date="Posted: Fri Aug 10, 2007 9:56 am "><author>0m1n0u5</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">10x rich_is_bored now i know where to look at and what to change. If I have any progress I'll post again.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204625" date="Posted: Mon Sep 08, 2008 3:15 pm "><author>0m1n0u5</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm resurrecting this thread to show you my progress. I've been working on my mod "Wrathchild" for more than a year and a holf now (after scrapping everything I had done till then and starting anew). An important part of my mod was the PDA/HUD combo. By the time I started this thread I haven't really realised how much work it would take to make a functional HUD/PDA. When I realized that I started working on level design, texturing, sounds, etc. and did that till about three months when I started working on this part of the mod again. So I can now safely say :<br /><br />Indeed health, armor and stamina indicators and many other assets are possible in the pda! But only if you put the pda in the place of the hud <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> . It may sound strange but it works.<br /><br />Instead of :<br /><br />   "hud"                        "guis/hud.gui"<br />   "mphud"                        "guis/mphud.gui"<br />   "cursor"                     "guis/cursor.gui"<br /><br />I have :<br /><br />   "hud"                        "guis/pda.gui" &lt;---<br />   "mphud"                        "guis/mphud.gui"<br />   "cursor"                     "guis/cursor.gui"<br /><br />in the "Player.def" under "player_base". It's that simple. Ofcorse the hard part is writing a pda file that makes full use of the new freedom this simple change gives.<br /><br /> What my new pda does is:<br /><br /> Give the player ingame control of the information he wants to have. <br />For example if you don't want to see some part of the hud but not all of it, You hit "TAB" and then remove it with a button inside the pda, then when you get back to the hud the indicator is gone.<br /><br /> Creates new gameplay situations. <br />A new "resource" is introduced that is completely gui/script operated, called "Energy" and like in Deus Ex Invisible War it manages the use of some weapons or some software inside the pda.<br /><br /> Gives you information on what weapons and equipment you are wearing. <br />A new weapon type called Mod is incorporated in the game. Through a basic ingame script you get bonuses for having these mods (healing faster hacking, etc.).<br /><br /> Problems:<br /><br /> I am not used to making complicated scripting, even ones in the guis so there are things I cant get right yet. So if anyone likes the project and wants to try and help, please PM me.<br /><br />-First I have no idea how the emails in the original doom 3 work. No idea at all! As a result my logs section is pretty basic and needs a hell of alot "weapon_bla.def" (as weapons turned out to be the best triggers) files to work every one being a log. This leads to the second problem.<br />-Sdk compiling. I just can't do it. I need to increase my weapon count to the max, I try I've got the d3sdk but after I change the line and save it I have no idea what to do next.<br />-I have an idea for a "Research" window (much like System Shock 2) inside the pda which will take some energy to operate, but again I need more weapon defs for this to work. Before that is done there is no point in even starting.<br /><br /> This is the HUD as you see it ingame:<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842/http://img261.imageshack.us/my.php?image=hud1dm6.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842im_/http://img261.imageshack.us/img261/8297/hud1dm6.th.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br /> And this is the PDA that you access by pressing tab.<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842/http://img237.imageshack.us/my.php?image=pdagj8.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842im_/http://img237.imageshack.us/img237/9176/pdagj8.th.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br /> If there is enough interest I'll copy/paste the pda/hud here.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204849" date="Posted: Sat Sep 13, 2008 9:47 am "><author>Tetzlaff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Looks really interesting, also reminded me of System Shock. Fits the Doom3 style well.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204894" date="Posted: Sun Sep 14, 2008 5:49 pm "><author>0m1n0u5</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">10x for the reply Tetzlaff. Indeed I am trying to create a System Shock and Deus Ex feel in my modification "Wrathchild", on which I have a mountain of work to finish. Actually the street shot is from the third level, which is almost done.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204896" date="Posted: Sun Sep 14, 2008 6:59 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The street shot reminds me of Syndicate. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />Looking interesting . Keep it up.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204897" date="Posted: Sun Sep 14, 2008 7:16 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I wrote some stuff about compiling the SDK using Visual Studio.<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842/http://www.the-emz.com/vstudio/">http://www.the-emz.com/vstudio/</a><!-- m --><br /><br />If I were you I'd use VS2008 Express; it's free and easiest to set up. And I'd recommend using the "alternative set of project files" I linked at the start of that article, as it will elimiate huge numbers of warnings.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204909" date="Posted: Mon Sep 15, 2008 10:33 am "><author>bashport</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">that looks totally sweet 0m1!<br />great stuff so far</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204915" date="Posted: Mon Sep 15, 2008 2:43 pm "><author>0m1n0u5</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wow thanks guys. Kristus you nailed it- Syndicate was also a big inspiration. As you can see I'm kind a cyberpunk geek <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /> . ( the thing that really made me start the mod project was a tv show named "Charlie Jade" especially the Alphaverse )<br /><br />I think I wasn't very clear about the SDK part. I did try to learn it on my own, I red alot of information ( including on your site, simulation ) and I still can't get anything working. Another problem is that my windows doesn't seem to like neither VS2008 Express nor VS2005 Express. When I try to install either of them I get an error. Besides that I've got a whole lot of work on level design, gameplay and these damn dialogs...<br /><br />Anyways really thanks for the replies. Btw if you are asking yourselves why don't I just make a topic about that "Wrathchild" thing - here's the answer - I don't like showing unfinished things. I'll make a topic: When it's done. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205730" date="Posted: Sun Oct 05, 2008 2:33 pm "><author>0m1n0u5</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This is the "Wrathchild" modification thread:<br /><br /><!-- l --><a class="postlink-local" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?f=39&amp;t=22030">viewtopic.php?f=39&amp;t=22030</a><!-- l --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p207526" date="Posted: Thu Nov 13, 2008 9:57 am "><author>0m1n0u5</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The Combined HUD/PDA v1.0 system is ready. It works <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103842im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> . When Wrathchild is out you will see. It has such a different feel from vanlia Doom3 pda and hud, I can't really explain it. I don't want to brag but I'm really proud of that project. It became very powerfull, flexible and reliable, not to mention promissing. As much as I've finished on it, I consider it an open ended project, as the potencial for addons is immence.<br />That's it.<br />Ask if you are interested in any aspect of that project!</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
