<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20285"><title>Problem with blend modes in gui</title><posts><post id="p185756" date="Posted: Thu Aug 09, 2007 4:50 pm "><author>Springheel</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Still working on that gui menu....<br /><br />I am trying to add a blend effect to the object images.  What I'd like is something similar to a "hard light" effect in Photoshop.<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.mindplaces.com/save/image_problem2.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />  For some reason, however, when I use blend modes in the material the image is not be transparent.  Instead, there are solid black (or white, depending on the blend mode I use) boxes around the image. <br /><br />The .tga itself is has a transparent background, and f I use blend blend, then the transparency renders properly, but that mode just looks like the object is drawn on top of the parchment--it doesn't actually 'blend' with the parchment at all.<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.mindplaces.com/save/image_problem3.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />Here's the material I'm using atm:<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">guis/assets/purchase_menu/lantern<br /> {<br /><br />    {<br />          blend modulate<br />        map guis/assets/hud/inventory_icons/healthpotion_icon.tga<br />        alpha parm3<br />    }<br />}</div><br /><br />And this is what it looks like:<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.mindplaces.com/save/image_problem1.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Oddly, the black doesn't fill the entire dimensions of the image--it seems to follow the shape of the object in the image.<br /><br />Any ideas why this might be happening, or what blend mode could produce results similar to the one above?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185765" date="Posted: Thu Aug 09, 2007 5:40 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i haven't used blend modes in a while but would it be easier to save a copy of the blended image from photoshop?<br /><br />For the second one it looks like those were selection boxes drug about &amp; weren't part of the alpha.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185796" date="Posted: Fri Aug 10, 2007 5:39 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You guys seem to be missing the point.<br /><br />The whole idea behind transparency and blend modes is to spare the artist from having to bother with compositing images. It affords you the luxury of being able to move elements around without having to re-composite the images.<br /><br />I suggest sticking with "blend blend" and trying to incorporate "translucent". Alternatively, you might be able to adjust the opacity of the GUI element itself instead of relying solely on the material shader.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185857" date="Posted: Fri Aug 10, 2007 8:49 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i get the point but if the object isn't going to move at all why tax the renderer (even if it is slightly) any extra?  Keep it as simple as possible, less change for issues down the road.<br /><br />what I would do, just for reference, is make a different material file for each blend mode on the object &amp; place each one in the GUI.  use the text tool to label each blend mode.  Save.  Then you have a reference for later use to see how they work.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185890" date="Posted: Sat Aug 11, 2007 5:31 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Content in The Dark Mod must be reusable to aid third parties in creating their own missions. Compositing images is an option but ideally it should be a last resort.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
