<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20299"><title>Help importing custom content</title><posts><post id="p185975" date="Posted: Sun Aug 12, 2007 5:44 am "><author>VisualNinja</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have followed several tutorials and searched this and other forums but haven't found the answer yet... I'm trying to load custom content into Doom 3 but am having no luck. Here's what I'm doing:<br /><br /> creating textures in PS and saving them to D:\textures\custom<br />following the naming convention I've called my textures<br />rockwall_d.tga<br />rockwall_s.tga<br />I don't have a normal map: rockwall_normal.tga<br />rockwall_ed.tga<br />I created a folder D:\textures\custom that contains a text file called rockwall.mtr that says<br /><br /><span style="color: #FF0080">textures/custom/rockwall<br />{<br />    qer_editorimage  textures/custom/rockwall_ed.tga       // custom DOOMEdit material preview image<br /><br />    diffusemap       textures/custom/rockwall_d.tga        // color and value information for the material<br />    specularmap      textures/custom/rockwall_s.tga        // specular highlights<br />//    bumpmap          textures/custom/rockwall_local.tga    // normalmap for bumpmapped appearance<br />} </span><br /><br />I then zipped these up with winzip with "preserve directory structure" switched in and saved it into a file called pak006.pk4<br />I put this in the folder D:\Doom3\base and ran the editor (which works fine otherwise) and I am unable to find my textures in the media inspector, in fact I don't even see the "custom" folder in there.<br />Doom3 is installed into my D drive, does that make a difference. That's the only difference I can see. Please help, I've been trying to get this to work for the last 8 hours straight!!!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185976" date="Posted: Sun Aug 12, 2007 6:41 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I had this problem as well when I was trying to get an animated character in-game. For a while, I just worked in the folders, then when I tried to zip'em and make a pak file, I had a problem. I don't remember what I did to fix it, but I remember I went back and forth between the folders and the pak files to fix it.<br /><br />You can't leave it in folders instead of trying to create a new pak file?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185979" date="Posted: Sun Aug 12, 2007 6:58 am "><author>VisualNinja</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's an interesting question... I guess my larger problem is how to get content into the game. I want to add my own textures, models, etc. into the game but can't seem to figure out how. I've never moded a game before but I have a lot of experience with photoshop and 3ds max. Does Doom just look at the pak files when runnin the game or is it possible to just add folders to the /base folder and have them appear in the editor? From what I can tell from various tut's is that it must be made into a pk4. Please point me in the right direction.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p185980" date="Posted: Sun Aug 12, 2007 7:10 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">VisualNinja wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... is it possible to just add folders to the /base folder and have them appear in the editor?</div><br /><br />There ya go! Yes you can do it that way. Make sure you get the folder names correct when you create them as well.... I think that's important... I don't remember how you actually make Doom 3 realize you have new files in it's directory.<br /><br />But I do know, 100% sure that you can just work in folders without having to create pak files. But if you were to give someone else the mod or addons, I think a pak file is necessary. I've never given someone else my own custom content though.<br /><br />Maybe you actually have to create your own separate folder, like a mod folder in order to get your paks to work. Then every time you go in-game you have to launch your mod (or create a shortcut to your mod).<br /><br />But to be honest, I think you should just work in folders until you can't anymore.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p186068" date="Posted: Mon Aug 13, 2007 4:58 am "><author>VisualNinja</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks, that worked, I just had my folders in the wrong  place.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
