<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20574"><title>Zakyrus's Nightmare Mod</title><posts><post id="p189129" date="Posted: Wed Sep 26, 2007 5:16 am "><author>Zakyrus_theOmega</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If you want to know why this mod is called "Zakyrus's Nightmare"... it has nothing to with Nightmare mode, it's because the game will now give you nightmares... watch the video to see what I mean. &gt;:)<br />You guys don't have a clue what you're in for... EVERY time I play this I'm on the edge of my seat (as it should be) AND I am the author. Mwa ha ha ha ha ha! &lt;---- I laugh with sardonic mirth that echoes out across the Universe!<br /><br /><br />In Depth:<br />--------<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540/http://doom3.filefront.com/screenshots/File/83190/3">http://doom3.filefront.com/screenshots/File/83190/3</a><!-- m --><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540/http://doom3.filefront.com/screenshots/File/83190/6">http://doom3.filefront.com/screenshots/File/83190/6</a><!-- m --><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540/http://doom3.filefront.com/screenshots/File/83190/1">http://doom3.filefront.com/screenshots/File/83190/1</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Faked Radiosity<br />-Increased radii of lights and added greater falloff. This makes lights more realistic. You'd *think* that this decreases Doom3's scariness, but actually the highlights on models and actors look scarier than ever before! Scariness due to realism, not "pitch-black" environemets! Also, the environemets are still VERY dark and scary, I assure you that! (you just now see the scariness a little more! he he!)<br /><br />Increasing the lighting is a tedious process. Every light in all maps have to be changed individually (for optimal effect). This is very time consuming (about 3 hours per map if you want to be sure everything looks good!)<br />I am only upto Monorail for completed maps, but the maps have stunning lights now!<br /><br />Also, to enhance this effect. I scaled the light.tga files 2x, and added falloff code to most lights in lights.mtr. To top it off, we use JC_Denton's Faked HDR Bloom shaders, leaving a breathtakingly real lighting system that can't easily be beat!<br /><br />Faked Caustics:<br />Basically a special lighting material used for special effects such as Nukaga, Lightning, Lava, Fire, etc. This animated glow/lighting is cast upon all nearby surfaces. Caustic effects have been attached to roundfire1 and roundfire2 and cause those fire effects to look better than ever! (Much better than that round_flicker light that was used for lava before!)<br /><br />More Destructables:<br />Most moveable objects are now destructable. From Fire extingueshers to laptop computers... I don't have good particle effects done yet, but the basics are there for now (for when I do get time to add them).<br /><br />Also, there are now pipes built into the levels that you can shoot and will explode -- some steam others fire!<br />There's also destructable breaker boxes (effect looks terrible now, but will be improved later) that sometimes can<br />shutoff nearby lights or power if blown out or they can simply damage enemies!<br /><br /><br />Random Monster Triggers<br />Basically, I went through all the maps (only upto Enpro as of now) and added many monsters in places that can jump out at the player, I made all the new monsters hidden until they are called by a randomize script (in the level.script files).<br /><br />The player walks across a hidden trigger and instead of a normal monster (that the player knew about before hand), the random script is run and one of the new nearby monsters appear. Sometimes you could get attacked by 2 imps from ahead of you, sometimes the two imps come from behind, AND sometimes... you get one behind you while another appears ahead of you. Other cases, they could drop on you from the ceiling or climb out of litteraly any nook and cranny, maybe even bust through the wall to get to you!. You know you are going to get attacked in that area, you just don't know where THEY will come from! So everytime you play the maps, it's a totally different experience. ANYTHING can happen!<br />Not EVERY monster event has been randomized, but MANY of them are! Things like meeting a monster for the first time are untouched.<br /><br /><br /><br />Here's the teaser video of my upcoming Nightmare Mod!<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540/http://doom3.filefront.com/file/NightMare_Mod_Teaser_video;83190">http://doom3.filefront.com/file/NightMa ... ideo;83190</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p189139" date="Posted: Wed Sep 26, 2007 10:17 am "><author>Hexen Terzo</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">fantastic! simply fantastic!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p189142" date="Posted: Wed Sep 26, 2007 11:16 am "><author>Hemebond</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Dude, this looks great. Even just the per-materials particles and destructible environment items. Fantastic.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p189143" date="Posted: Wed Sep 26, 2007 11:20 am "><author>Zakyrus_theOmega</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Hemebond wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Dude, this looks great. Even just the per-materials particles and destructible environment items. Fantastic.</div><br /><br />Thanks!<br /><br />I made a modified moveables.def one day and just went to town making most moveables into destructables. Then I used Dentons Enhanced Doom 3 mod's version of the file and just ported everything into it. A few other things I am perfecting with the SDK are burn_lights, debris_lights(flaming chunks of barrel emit light hehe!), as well as the particles for the breaking of the object. Later, objects will be coded to be destructable in virtually any way! For instance, push a cardboard box into a flame and watch it burn up! Or spill that Robo cola and watch the modconsole fry! Ha ha ha ha ha!<br /><br />Yeah, I always wanted that "Gas Tank" in mars_city2 to explode into jet flames!<br /><br />Combined with the enhanced lighting and random monsters (and later random hallucinations! haha!)... brings Doom3 to a whole new level.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p189374" date="Posted: Sun Sep 30, 2007 3:36 am "><author>BuddhaMaster</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Zakyrus_theOmega wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Hemebond wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Dude, this looks great. Even just the per-materials particles and destructible environment items. Fantastic.</div><br /><br />Thanks!<br /><br />I made a modified moveables.def one day and just went to town making most moveables into destructables. Then I used Dentons Enhanced Doom 3 mod's version of the file and just ported everything into it. A few other things I am perfecting with the SDK are burn_lights, debris_lights(flaming chunks of barrel emit light hehe!), as well as the particles for the breaking of the object. Later, objects will be coded to be destructable in virtually any way! For instance, push a cardboard box into a flame and watch it burn up! Or spill that Robo cola and watch the modconsole fry! Ha ha ha ha ha!<br /><br />Yeah, I always wanted that "Gas Tank" in mars_city2 to explode into jet flames!<br /><br />Combined with the enhanced lighting and random monsters (and later random hallucinations! haha!)... brings Doom3 to a whole new level.</div><br /><br />Good stuff, keep it on.<br />I also could use most of these stuff to put into my mod <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br />random hallcinations ? hehe, could be a usefull way to stop taking drugs</div>]]></body></post><post id="p189378" date="Posted: Sun Sep 30, 2007 5:01 am "><author>Hemebond</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Zakyrus_theOmega wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To top it off, we use JC_Denton's Faked HDR Bloom shaders, leaving a breathtakingly real lighting system that can't easily be beat!</div>Dentons mod doesn't work on Linux, will yours? If not, I take back all my praise as I won't get to play it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p189435" date="Posted: Sun Sep 30, 2007 11:46 pm "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It sounds great, and i love the idea of random triggers all over the place. The video was a good demonstration of that <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />Doom 3 will never get old for me  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190208" date="Posted: Wed Oct 17, 2007 1:51 am "><author>Zakyrus_theOmega</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Hemebond wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Zakyrus_theOmega wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To top it off, we use JC_Denton's Faked HDR Bloom shaders, leaving a breathtakingly real lighting system that can't easily be beat!</div>Dentons mod doesn't work on Linux, will yours? If not, I take back all my praise as I won't get to play it.</div><br /><br />I hope to have this compatable with Mac &amp; *nix at some point.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190444" date="Posted: Mon Oct 22, 2007 12:49 am "><author>Zakyrus_theOmega</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here ya go ladies and gentlemen!<br />The 0.4 alpha release of my mod!<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540/http://doom3.filefront.com/file/NightMare_Mod;83827">http://doom3.filefront.com/file/NightMare_Mod;83827</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Enjoy!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165540im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
