<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20628"><title>Help Needed</title><posts><post id="p189738" date="Posted: Sun Oct 07, 2007 2:13 am "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Alright. <br /><br />So I have a project. Basically what I want to do is make a video using Doom 3. The video will be something simple, the doomguy (vd3 or roe or the multiplayer model) running through hell, doing different animations. For lack of better description, think of it like the cdoom beginning cinematic, just a little different. <br /><br />I have a variety of programs ready, and I'm hoping Lightwave will be enough. <br /><br />What I would like to know right now - <br /><br />- Any easy map-making tutorials for maps such as the doom 3 hell maps and rocky-type terrain<br />- How to export models into LW to animate, and how to import them back into d3 to play<br />- How to use cameras and make cutscenes in doom 3 <br /><br />I think that's pretty much it. It's a huge to-do list, and I've been wandering modwiki for the past week now, and was wondering if I could get any up-front assistance. <br /><br />Anyone have advice or help?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190100" date="Posted: Sun Oct 14, 2007 12:47 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It looks like you got a basic idea of what you want to do, but have no idea how anything in Doom3 works... better dig in and examine the engine and resources before doing anything.<br /><br />a few things though.<br /><br />BTW, The hell maps are mostly modeled.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190117" date="Posted: Sun Oct 14, 2007 8:50 pm "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's what I was afraid of. <br /><br />I realized though everything I really need is on modwiki or these forums, so I just gotta do some more looking. <br /><br />A quick question though, for hell-like rocky architecture, would I have to model that and create my own texture for it or is there any way i can re-organize the ones already used in doom3 hell/roe hell?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190198" date="Posted: Tue Oct 16, 2007 6:43 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">you can make your own model and you can use doom 3's textures. all you have to do is alter the models texture once youve exported it.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165525im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />hope all goes well</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190199" date="Posted: Tue Oct 16, 2007 7:44 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">He's using Lightwave, and as such he needs to set the material name inside Lightwave prior to export.<br />It's really simple. <br /><br />You can use the same materials as in Doom3, or you can make new ones using the same textures as Doom3 has used. I've been doing this a lot myself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190224" date="Posted: Wed Oct 17, 2007 3:08 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ah ok.<br />never used lightwave before <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20071024165525im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
