<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20660"><title>Halo Wars? -Strategy Game, Sorry Shooters-</title><posts><post id="p190045" date="Posted: Sat Oct 13, 2007 6:39 am "><author>ajm113</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This looks pretty intense. Though the controls with a 360 seem never to be for a strategy game. I mite get it since I like Strategy Games and Halo!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.halowars.com/images/screenshots/Harvest.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.halowars.com/images/screenshots/UNSCBase.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Website:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.halowars.com/">http://www.halowars.com/</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Videos:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.halowars.com/Media.aspx">http://www.halowars.com/Media.aspx</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190070" date="Posted: Sat Oct 13, 2007 11:51 pm "><author>Paveway</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If they make a good PC port I might do it, I played C&amp;C3 or whatever for xbox and I really just couldn't get used to using a controller for RTS games :/</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190079" date="Posted: Sun Oct 14, 2007 2:24 am "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">blah, nogo. I never liked the idea of it from the beginning. Probably mostly to do with the console.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190091" date="Posted: Sun Oct 14, 2007 7:03 am "><author>bkt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've bought into the whole mythology of halo as it's a pretty cool story, but there's something about this game that just doesn't have me excited what so ever.  I also played CNC3, but the whole time I played it, I just kept thinking about how cool Company of Heroes is, so maybe that's got something to do with it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190121" date="Posted: Sun Oct 14, 2007 9:51 pm "><author>Zombie13</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What the fark! I really like Ensembles games too, but on the 360 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /><br /><br />God damn microsoft they piss me off sometimes <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190123" date="Posted: Sun Oct 14, 2007 10:29 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">so is this a game where you always have to loose?  We know it was the master chief that made all the difference.  Unless it's 1 master chief vs everybody. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p191024" date="Posted: Fri Nov 02, 2007 8:24 am "><author>Infernis</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The idea of having an Spartan army at your control certainly has it's perks <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />Btw, I thought it was being developed for the PC as well. To promote the Games for Vista thingie. No source though <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p191243" date="Posted: Thu Nov 08, 2007 7:04 am "><author>Duff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i remember hearing it was going to be on PC aswell, oh well. I wasn't sold on Age of Empires III so won't be treading Ensembles ground again unless its something awesome; well something awesome according to my friends or people in the internet i trust to know what is actually good.<br /><br />Age of Empires II though, so hot. even now. Conquerers expansion is lame though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p191246" date="Posted: Thu Nov 08, 2007 12:08 pm "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Woah, I never really looked into this post but... Halo Wars is going to be console only!?!? Here I was assuming it was a PC Game!! Why? Because it's RTS.... If I were going to make an RTS game, deving it for the console would be out of the question to me.<br /><br />I guess they know 99% of their fans are console gamers. Of course that 99% probably don't have an interest in RTS games.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p191393" date="Posted: Sun Nov 11, 2007 7:04 pm "><author>Yrt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This isn't coming out for windows cause their making it for the 360, not like C&amp;C where it was just transferred. It should make the controls much easier and more smooth.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p191398" date="Posted: Sun Nov 11, 2007 9:28 pm "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Yrt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">This isn't coming out for windows cause their making it for the 360, not like C&amp;C where it was just transferred. It should make the controls much easier and more smooth.</div><br /><br />I just don't think a game-pad could come anywhere close to as capable as a keyboard and mouse for an RTS game. But then again they could design the game around the game-pad, not just the controls. (Eg. slower gameplay, maybe a real-time pause to make commands ahead of time, etc.)<br /><br />I never liked game-pads though, I don't understand why the console companies don't produce official keyboard and mice for their consoles, because console gamers would probably buy them instead of the game-pads. Err, at least I know a lot that would buy them instead of game-pads, and console gamers would only benefit.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
