<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20735"><title>Crysis singleplayer demo released</title><posts><post id="p190725" date="Posted: Fri Oct 26, 2007 9:23 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">... editor included:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253/http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/49658">http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/49658</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190730" date="Posted: Fri Oct 26, 2007 10:04 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">fast direct download link from EA:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253/http://na.llnet.cdn.ea.com/u/demos/Crysis_SP_Demo.exe">http://na.llnet.cdn.ea.com/u/demos/Crysis_SP_Demo.exe</a><!-- m --><br /><br />i'm getting 500kb/s</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190733" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 2:30 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very nice! Here's a list of mirrors at Crysis-Online! (It also has links provided to the latest nVidia drivers that are recommended as well as "Vista Hotfixes", whatever those are.)<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253/http://www.crysis-online.com/?id=441">http://www.crysis-online.com/?id=441</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Meanwhile I'm downloading at anywhere between 600-800 kb from the EA link that <span style="font-weight: bold">pbmax</span> provided (thank you). I'm running an 8800 GTX, but I don't have Vista so I can't test the DX10 stuff which saddens me a little. Anyone got DX10???<br /><br />This is going to be <span style="font-style: italic">so</span> much more entertaining than the mp beta <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190739" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 4:59 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wow, I just played through the demo and I have to say... This game isn't just all graphics. I don't care if this game looked 5 years old, it's pretty cinematic and fun, the story actually has a presence as well.... I think it's time for me to play the demo again.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190740" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 5:04 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... editor included:</div><br /><br />:O, although I suppose the demo of doom3 had that too. Right?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190743" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 6:25 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Check out the SandBox Manual: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253/http://doc.crymod.com/frames.html?frmname=topic&amp;frmfile=index.html">http://doc.crymod.com/frames.html?frmna ... index.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />"Crymod" website: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253/http://www.crymod.com/portal.php">http://www.crymod.com/portal.php</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><br />EDIT:<br />I tried to follow the Generate Terrain and Generate Texture tutorial, but it worked NOTHING like the tutorial did. I left everything on default, just as the tutorial said and of course, my results are opposite. Instead of creating a scattered island, I get a somewhat big/thick island. And the generate texture tool just makes a brighter gray color hahah.<br /><br />Anyone else have this problem?<br /><br />BTW, you load the editor by installing it. It's in the game directory, in the SandBox2 Installer folder. Then you have to launch the .exe called Editor.exe in the Bin32 folder after installation. More hassle than Doom 3 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190748" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 7:01 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kristus wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... editor included:</div><br />:O, although I suppose the demo of doom3 had that too. Right?</div><br /><br />Actually I don't remember, but how does it relate to Crysis?<br /><br />Plenty of people want to toy around with Crysis, so I guess it's a nice bonus for them.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190754" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 11:50 am "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i'm playing at low settings and it looks pretty bad. tons of LOD popping.<br /><br />it feels a lot like farcry too.<br /><br />i'm gonna crank up the settings just to see what it should look like now...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190758" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:03 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Anyone got DX10???</div><br />i have but i dont have enough RAM at the moment. i ordered 2gb worth that should come next week then i'll be able to play  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190760" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:35 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pbmax wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">i'm gonna crank up the settings just to see what it should look like now...</div><br /><br />10 fps at 800x600, lol!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190762" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:43 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">10 fps at 800x600, lol!</div><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />  what are your system specs?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190768" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 7:51 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">BTW, you load the editor by installing it. It's in the game directory, in the SandBox2 Installer folder. Then you have to launch the .exe called Editor.exe in the Bin32 folder after installation. More hassle than Doom 3 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" />.</div>To launch doom3 editor you need to go online to know all those shortcut settings and this one is just install and launch. Easy.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190777" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 9:58 pm "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good demo. It's Farcry on steroids, but it's fun and runs better than I expected.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190806" date="Posted: Sun Oct 28, 2007 9:12 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I spent some quality time with the demo and am pretty impressed.<br /><br />I run everything on ultra quality on an Intel Q6600, NVIDIA 8800GTX, 2GB RAM, VISTA Ultimate and a resolution of 1680*1050.<br /><br />It runs with borderline performance if 2x AA is enabled, but not at slideshow levels albeit the mouse feels laggy.<br /><br />In any case it looks gorgeous, sometimes like a prerendered movie. There's plenty of post processing going on and it's not a far fetched assumption to declare it the gfx board system seller of 2008. Whatever NVIDIA will sell on the market of their new product line will benefit greatly from Crysis. Like id software a few years ago Crytek has managed to bring one of these "I don't want, no, I need the latest overpriced hardware for this game" alive.<br /><br />If the game AND a 9900Ultra would be available tomorrow I'd line up to get both (after visiting the bank for a third mortgage).<br /><br />I want to say the presentation of the game is surprisingly professional and very cinematic. Fortunately it's not cheesy which lends the game some credibility.<br /><br />It's a nice touch that the enemies speak English on lower difficulty levels, but Korean on higher difficulty. On the other hand I don't know if they have something interesting to say... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />The weapons and suit ingame configuration system is straightforward and has a good accessibility. It seems the developers have put serious thought into the ingame UI. Way to go Crytek!<br /><br />In terms of storyline, gameplay... We'll see how everything holds up over the full race distance...<br /><br />Based on the demo I'd give it a five out of five recommendation stars, assuming you have a system that holds up to the hefty demands in high quality. If you, like me, belong to the people who either want to play something in the best possible quality or not at all - prepare for upgrades.<br /><br />I really want to say it again - this game looks absolutely wow.<br /><br />Have fun!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190809" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 12:03 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">It's a nice touch that the enemies speak English on lower difficulty levels, but Korean on higher difficulty. On the other hand I don't know if they have something interesting to say... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div><br /><br />Yeah I bet they have a lot of funny things to say, but I only played on the hardest difficulty =/. I found the demo to be incredibly easy! If this is how the Koreans -always- are, this easy to avoid and kill then I think we may hear some complaints from fans about that. I found Far Cry a lot more difficult.<br /><br />Though, the AI is pretty amazingly intelligent! Most games that come out now-a-days boast intelligent AI but pretty much never come through, and Crysis was one of them. Of course I was skeptical of this because pretty much every game that ever released boasting realistic AI was just BSing. But they were surprisingly realistic, though they had a few minor weird quirks on making decisions about tactics.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190814" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 4:01 am "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I must say, I was quite excited to try it out, myself. Confident that it'd be just the kind of game I'd enjoy, considering you could charge up and beat your opponents to death with your fists, run quickly behind them and fire a round into the back of their head before they could even react, or sneak up right infront of them with "Cloak" and open up nearly endless possibilities of playstyles and techniques, I downloaded it immediately. To my surprise, Crysis is perhaps the most graphically enhanced game I've ever played in my life - Even beating Unreal Tournament 3, to an extent. At times, I must add, I felt like I was watching an animated show up to par with Shrek and other titles. It was an amazing experience, especially dropping from the airplane.<br /><br />However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same. This was just a demo, though, and I can't forget that.<br /><br />The point is, Crysis didn't impress me with the combat. Not even remotely. The scenery and plantlife were outstanding, but the game also featured a very linear feeling, seeing as the rocks were placed to keep you from going up to high grounds, for example, and the hills were perfectly shaped to create a path through what would naturally be like a maze or dungeon of trees, ferns, grass, vines, and the like. The water was especially beautiful, and I could sit and stare at it for an hour and still find it of high artistic significance. The clouds, the sun - The game, no doubt about it, is the best you'll be seeing for quite awhile, assuming Unreal Tournament 3 sacrifices scenery for gameplay.<br /><br />The objectives are typical, of course, and killing Koreans gets old and boring after you shoot them right between the eyes one after another. Same patrols, same behavior, and too little life-like interaction with the environment. I'd expect someone to quickly pick up a barrel and position it or hide behind one entirely to create a small defense for himself, rather than run to the nearest wall and stand behind it for mediocre cover. I'd also expect them to be sleeping, or just waking up, and not looking into the forest or staring out in a random direction as if expecting some super-suit equipped American soldier to fly out and strangle him to death when they haven't witnessed one, yet. It would also be nice to see them sit down and relax, once in awhile. Get bored, tired, thirsty, hungry. These are humans, and this "battle-hardened, tireless, and ruthless killer" crap is getting old. Infact, judging by how I witnessed one running away with panic, I imagine they're not so tough, at all. Thus, I expect them to show more realistic behavior, not just a high-polygon model with generic AI. Once again, this is just the demo of the first level, and I'm judging too quickly.<br /><br />The game shows elements we've already seen in Far Cry, and while I do find the suit to be quite awesome, I just don't feel that much has changed besides the graphics. Especially the stealth system in the game, which, ever since Far Cry, has been terrible. You could hide between a bunch of trees behind a bush, and suddenly a soldier looks in your direction and spots you, alerts the entire squad he's with, and fires perfect shots at you, just because he quickly turned his head and suddenly saw a millimeter-by-millimeter speck of silver which no human alive would naturally be able to see in a quick glance. I do appreciate their tendancy to give up the chase, but I'd like the game to offer a little more stealth without having to rely on "full invisibility" as a way of cheating their way around it.<br /><br />Since I'm doing nothing but ranting, I'll get to a conclusion...<br />The game is great, very beautiful and it offers a lot, and is quite fun and challenging, but I really feel that I'm just playing a mod for Far Cry. Especially when you consider you're still facing monsters among men, only this time they're aliens with freeze rays. I'll still purchase it, and maybe then I'll leave my final opinion. Plus, traversing the alien ship sounds like it'll be a blast.<br /><br />Also, having difficulties moving because of my left hand took out some of the experience, so that's another reason I didn't have extraordinaire amounts of fun with it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190815" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:04 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same.</div><br /><br />Have to agree with you there. Everyone has been making a big deal over it and I really don't think it's that interesting, it's not original enough to be a big gimmick. I think Crysis's gimmick here is it's beautiful graphics, and also it's fun game-play.<br /><br />But what's wrong with the linear experience? It's supposed to be a cinematic experience, and I really feel they've done an incredible job. It's got the same battle sandbox feel as it did in Far Cry, which is one of the reasons why everyone liked it so much, so it gives some freedom there. Sure it's no exploration game, but that's not what I'm looking for in Crysis.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190816" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:16 am "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same.</div><br /><br />Have to agree with you there. Everyone has been making a big deal over it and I really don't think it's that interesting, it's not original enough to be a big gimmick. I think Crysis's gimmick here is it's beautiful graphics, and also it's fun game-play.<br /><br />But what's wrong with the linear experience? It's supposed to be a cinematic experience, and I really feel they've done an incredible job. It's got the same battle sandbox feel as it did in Far Cry, which is one of the reasons why everyone liked it so much, so it gives some freedom there. Sure it's no exploration game, but that's not what I'm looking for in Crysis.</div><br /><br />That's what gets me <span style="font-style: italic">off</span>, in the same way. I totally agree about the linear part, partly because I guess I was expecting more freedom as a player to be able to make my own decisions, but when I saw what the AI had to offer and the same encounters kept.. encountering.. over and over, I got a very linear feel; especially the mountains and only having one real path to go. I felt like a rat in a maze to some extent. <br /><br />Of course, I was too busy paying attention to all the eyecandy to really care at first. It's just a sort of underlying feel that I hope is creased out in the multiplayer.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190834" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:05 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You know whats incredible in this game? Tornadoes! I love them smashing and raping the island. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /> Helicopter handling is also very well done, much easier to handle than in Arma or Just Cause. Also you whine too much, the game is perfect.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190835" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:06 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">having this game on my hd has been driving me nuts... i havent got enough ram to play it. i ordered more which i should recieve in the next few days. however, seeing the icon on my desktop was driving me nuts so i decided i'll give it a go. because of having vista i was worried about my performance so i went online and found how to run it in direct x 9. still not enough memory but i played on medium settings in anycase. wow. i think the graphics are great even in this mode and the cinematic feel was amazing.what most surprised me was how smooth it ran. the min requirements say that you need atleast 1gb ram and i have just under but it still played smooth.high qaulity has alot of loading pauses which make it unplayable until i get my extra 2gb ram. i do agree it was quite linear but because its the first level you cant really judge how the later ones will play.when i get my RAM this week im going to put this baby up to high settings and give it a spin  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153253im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />cant wait</div>]]></body></post><post id="p194502" date="Posted: Sun Feb 03, 2008 7:37 am "><author>Mon1018</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good demo. It's Farcry on steroids, but it's fun and runs better than I expected.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p194545" date="Posted: Mon Feb 04, 2008 11:26 am "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Heh, same here, coincidentially I decided to try out the demo just yesterday. It runs quite well on medium settings here with my 7600GT. Aside from the eyecandy that I was happily served, the gameplay is also very good and the story with the cutscenes was entertaining. I'm going to buy the game once I get better hardware later this year, and it'll probably be cheaper by then, too. Not that it's not worth its full price. All of it oozes production value, the engine, art, sound and storywriting. It didn't crash on me once, even though I changed the gfx settings alot without restarting the game.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199558" date="Posted: Thu May 29, 2008 3:00 pm "><author>steve0</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Aha, nice !</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199583" date="Posted: Thu May 29, 2008 10:53 pm "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">steve0 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Aha, nice !</div><br /><br />Anticlimax!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190725" date="Posted: Fri Oct 26, 2007 9:23 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">... editor included:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355/http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/49658">http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/49658</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190730" date="Posted: Fri Oct 26, 2007 10:04 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">fast direct download link from EA:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355/http://na.llnet.cdn.ea.com/u/demos/Crysis_SP_Demo.exe">http://na.llnet.cdn.ea.com/u/demos/Crysis_SP_Demo.exe</a><!-- m --><br /><br />i'm getting 500kb/s</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190733" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 2:30 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very nice! Here's a list of mirrors at Crysis-Online! (It also has links provided to the latest nVidia drivers that are recommended as well as "Vista Hotfixes", whatever those are.)<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355/http://www.crysis-online.com/?id=441">http://www.crysis-online.com/?id=441</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Meanwhile I'm downloading at anywhere between 600-800 kb from the EA link that <span style="font-weight: bold">pbmax</span> provided (thank you). I'm running an 8800 GTX, but I don't have Vista so I can't test the DX10 stuff which saddens me a little. Anyone got DX10???<br /><br />This is going to be <span style="font-style: italic">so</span> much more entertaining than the mp beta <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190739" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 4:59 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wow, I just played through the demo and I have to say... This game isn't just all graphics. I don't care if this game looked 5 years old, it's pretty cinematic and fun, the story actually has a presence as well.... I think it's time for me to play the demo again.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190740" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 5:04 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... editor included:</div><br /><br />:O, although I suppose the demo of doom3 had that too. Right?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190743" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 6:25 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Check out the SandBox Manual: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355/http://doc.crymod.com/frames.html?frmname=topic&amp;frmfile=index.html">http://doc.crymod.com/frames.html?frmna ... index.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />"Crymod" website: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355/http://www.crymod.com/portal.php">http://www.crymod.com/portal.php</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><br />EDIT:<br />I tried to follow the Generate Terrain and Generate Texture tutorial, but it worked NOTHING like the tutorial did. I left everything on default, just as the tutorial said and of course, my results are opposite. Instead of creating a scattered island, I get a somewhat big/thick island. And the generate texture tool just makes a brighter gray color hahah.<br /><br />Anyone else have this problem?<br /><br />BTW, you load the editor by installing it. It's in the game directory, in the SandBox2 Installer folder. Then you have to launch the .exe called Editor.exe in the Bin32 folder after installation. More hassle than Doom 3 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190748" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 7:01 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kristus wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... editor included:</div><br />:O, although I suppose the demo of doom3 had that too. Right?</div><br /><br />Actually I don't remember, but how does it relate to Crysis?<br /><br />Plenty of people want to toy around with Crysis, so I guess it's a nice bonus for them.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190754" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 11:50 am "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i'm playing at low settings and it looks pretty bad. tons of LOD popping.<br /><br />it feels a lot like farcry too.<br /><br />i'm gonna crank up the settings just to see what it should look like now...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190758" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:03 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Anyone got DX10???</div><br />i have but i dont have enough RAM at the moment. i ordered 2gb worth that should come next week then i'll be able to play  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190760" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:35 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pbmax wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">i'm gonna crank up the settings just to see what it should look like now...</div><br /><br />10 fps at 800x600, lol!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190762" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:43 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">10 fps at 800x600, lol!</div><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />  what are your system specs?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190768" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 7:51 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">BTW, you load the editor by installing it. It's in the game directory, in the SandBox2 Installer folder. Then you have to launch the .exe called Editor.exe in the Bin32 folder after installation. More hassle than Doom 3 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" />.</div>To launch doom3 editor you need to go online to know all those shortcut settings and this one is just install and launch. Easy.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190777" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 9:58 pm "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good demo. It's Farcry on steroids, but it's fun and runs better than I expected.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190806" date="Posted: Sun Oct 28, 2007 9:12 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I spent some quality time with the demo and am pretty impressed.<br /><br />I run everything on ultra quality on an Intel Q6600, NVIDIA 8800GTX, 2GB RAM, VISTA Ultimate and a resolution of 1680*1050.<br /><br />It runs with borderline performance if 2x AA is enabled, but not at slideshow levels albeit the mouse feels laggy.<br /><br />In any case it looks gorgeous, sometimes like a prerendered movie. There's plenty of post processing going on and it's not a far fetched assumption to declare it the gfx board system seller of 2008. Whatever NVIDIA will sell on the market of their new product line will benefit greatly from Crysis. Like id software a few years ago Crytek has managed to bring one of these "I don't want, no, I need the latest overpriced hardware for this game" alive.<br /><br />If the game AND a 9900Ultra would be available tomorrow I'd line up to get both (after visiting the bank for a third mortgage).<br /><br />I want to say the presentation of the game is surprisingly professional and very cinematic. Fortunately it's not cheesy which lends the game some credibility.<br /><br />It's a nice touch that the enemies speak English on lower difficulty levels, but Korean on higher difficulty. On the other hand I don't know if they have something interesting to say... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />The weapons and suit ingame configuration system is straightforward and has a good accessibility. It seems the developers have put serious thought into the ingame UI. Way to go Crytek!<br /><br />In terms of storyline, gameplay... We'll see how everything holds up over the full race distance...<br /><br />Based on the demo I'd give it a five out of five recommendation stars, assuming you have a system that holds up to the hefty demands in high quality. If you, like me, belong to the people who either want to play something in the best possible quality or not at all - prepare for upgrades.<br /><br />I really want to say it again - this game looks absolutely wow.<br /><br />Have fun!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190809" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 12:03 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">It's a nice touch that the enemies speak English on lower difficulty levels, but Korean on higher difficulty. On the other hand I don't know if they have something interesting to say... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div><br /><br />Yeah I bet they have a lot of funny things to say, but I only played on the hardest difficulty =/. I found the demo to be incredibly easy! If this is how the Koreans -always- are, this easy to avoid and kill then I think we may hear some complaints from fans about that. I found Far Cry a lot more difficult.<br /><br />Though, the AI is pretty amazingly intelligent! Most games that come out now-a-days boast intelligent AI but pretty much never come through, and Crysis was one of them. Of course I was skeptical of this because pretty much every game that ever released boasting realistic AI was just BSing. But they were surprisingly realistic, though they had a few minor weird quirks on making decisions about tactics.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190814" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 4:01 am "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I must say, I was quite excited to try it out, myself. Confident that it'd be just the kind of game I'd enjoy, considering you could charge up and beat your opponents to death with your fists, run quickly behind them and fire a round into the back of their head before they could even react, or sneak up right infront of them with "Cloak" and open up nearly endless possibilities of playstyles and techniques, I downloaded it immediately. To my surprise, Crysis is perhaps the most graphically enhanced game I've ever played in my life - Even beating Unreal Tournament 3, to an extent. At times, I must add, I felt like I was watching an animated show up to par with Shrek and other titles. It was an amazing experience, especially dropping from the airplane.<br /><br />However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same. This was just a demo, though, and I can't forget that.<br /><br />The point is, Crysis didn't impress me with the combat. Not even remotely. The scenery and plantlife were outstanding, but the game also featured a very linear feeling, seeing as the rocks were placed to keep you from going up to high grounds, for example, and the hills were perfectly shaped to create a path through what would naturally be like a maze or dungeon of trees, ferns, grass, vines, and the like. The water was especially beautiful, and I could sit and stare at it for an hour and still find it of high artistic significance. The clouds, the sun - The game, no doubt about it, is the best you'll be seeing for quite awhile, assuming Unreal Tournament 3 sacrifices scenery for gameplay.<br /><br />The objectives are typical, of course, and killing Koreans gets old and boring after you shoot them right between the eyes one after another. Same patrols, same behavior, and too little life-like interaction with the environment. I'd expect someone to quickly pick up a barrel and position it or hide behind one entirely to create a small defense for himself, rather than run to the nearest wall and stand behind it for mediocre cover. I'd also expect them to be sleeping, or just waking up, and not looking into the forest or staring out in a random direction as if expecting some super-suit equipped American soldier to fly out and strangle him to death when they haven't witnessed one, yet. It would also be nice to see them sit down and relax, once in awhile. Get bored, tired, thirsty, hungry. These are humans, and this "battle-hardened, tireless, and ruthless killer" crap is getting old. Infact, judging by how I witnessed one running away with panic, I imagine they're not so tough, at all. Thus, I expect them to show more realistic behavior, not just a high-polygon model with generic AI. Once again, this is just the demo of the first level, and I'm judging too quickly.<br /><br />The game shows elements we've already seen in Far Cry, and while I do find the suit to be quite awesome, I just don't feel that much has changed besides the graphics. Especially the stealth system in the game, which, ever since Far Cry, has been terrible. You could hide between a bunch of trees behind a bush, and suddenly a soldier looks in your direction and spots you, alerts the entire squad he's with, and fires perfect shots at you, just because he quickly turned his head and suddenly saw a millimeter-by-millimeter speck of silver which no human alive would naturally be able to see in a quick glance. I do appreciate their tendancy to give up the chase, but I'd like the game to offer a little more stealth without having to rely on "full invisibility" as a way of cheating their way around it.<br /><br />Since I'm doing nothing but ranting, I'll get to a conclusion...<br />The game is great, very beautiful and it offers a lot, and is quite fun and challenging, but I really feel that I'm just playing a mod for Far Cry. Especially when you consider you're still facing monsters among men, only this time they're aliens with freeze rays. I'll still purchase it, and maybe then I'll leave my final opinion. Plus, traversing the alien ship sounds like it'll be a blast.<br /><br />Also, having difficulties moving because of my left hand took out some of the experience, so that's another reason I didn't have extraordinaire amounts of fun with it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190815" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:04 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same.</div><br /><br />Have to agree with you there. Everyone has been making a big deal over it and I really don't think it's that interesting, it's not original enough to be a big gimmick. I think Crysis's gimmick here is it's beautiful graphics, and also it's fun game-play.<br /><br />But what's wrong with the linear experience? It's supposed to be a cinematic experience, and I really feel they've done an incredible job. It's got the same battle sandbox feel as it did in Far Cry, which is one of the reasons why everyone liked it so much, so it gives some freedom there. Sure it's no exploration game, but that's not what I'm looking for in Crysis.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190816" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:16 am "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same.</div><br /><br />Have to agree with you there. Everyone has been making a big deal over it and I really don't think it's that interesting, it's not original enough to be a big gimmick. I think Crysis's gimmick here is it's beautiful graphics, and also it's fun game-play.<br /><br />But what's wrong with the linear experience? It's supposed to be a cinematic experience, and I really feel they've done an incredible job. It's got the same battle sandbox feel as it did in Far Cry, which is one of the reasons why everyone liked it so much, so it gives some freedom there. Sure it's no exploration game, but that's not what I'm looking for in Crysis.</div><br /><br />That's what gets me <span style="font-style: italic">off</span>, in the same way. I totally agree about the linear part, partly because I guess I was expecting more freedom as a player to be able to make my own decisions, but when I saw what the AI had to offer and the same encounters kept.. encountering.. over and over, I got a very linear feel; especially the mountains and only having one real path to go. I felt like a rat in a maze to some extent. <br /><br />Of course, I was too busy paying attention to all the eyecandy to really care at first. It's just a sort of underlying feel that I hope is creased out in the multiplayer.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190834" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:05 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You know whats incredible in this game? Tornadoes! I love them smashing and raping the island. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /> Helicopter handling is also very well done, much easier to handle than in Arma or Just Cause. Also you whine too much, the game is perfect.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190835" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:06 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">having this game on my hd has been driving me nuts... i havent got enough ram to play it. i ordered more which i should recieve in the next few days. however, seeing the icon on my desktop was driving me nuts so i decided i'll give it a go. because of having vista i was worried about my performance so i went online and found how to run it in direct x 9. still not enough memory but i played on medium settings in anycase. wow. i think the graphics are great even in this mode and the cinematic feel was amazing.what most surprised me was how smooth it ran. the min requirements say that you need atleast 1gb ram and i have just under but it still played smooth.high qaulity has alot of loading pauses which make it unplayable until i get my extra 2gb ram. i do agree it was quite linear but because its the first level you cant really judge how the later ones will play.when i get my RAM this week im going to put this baby up to high settings and give it a spin  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119153355im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />cant wait</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190844" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 8:16 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hostyle, stop living up to your namesake.  The first half of your post was fine.  But there's no need to add a personal insult in your last sentence.  <br /><br />Let's keep the thread civil and on topic, folks.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190848" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 8:28 pm "><author>Paveway</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Hostyle wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... the game is perfect.</div><br /><br />No such thing.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190851" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 8:41 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">-- &gt; You can get all the fancy DX10/Vista effects with DX9/XP !<br /><br />read thru this thread. it appears that you just need to edit a config file.<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://www.crysis-online.com/forum/index.php?topic=11837.0#msg203789">http://www.crysis-online.com/forum/inde ... #msg203789</a><!-- m --><br /><br />God rays, 3d waves on the water, displacement mapping, everything...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190853" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 9:02 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Paveway wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Hostyle wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... the game is perfect.</div>No such thing.</div>I think Crysis will be perfect as a game. I have a feeling, you know, and I'm sure I'm right. I just dont see any downsides of it except having an expensive high end rig to run on max, but that is required by the complexity of the game[big levels, phys trees+tornado, dyn freeze, AI, nuke, 3d ocean etc. etc.].</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190858" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 12:04 am "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Hostyle wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Paveway wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Hostyle wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... the game is perfect.</div>No such thing.</div>I think Crysis will be perfect as a game. I have a feeling, you know, and I'm sure I'm right. I just dont see any downsides of it except having an expensive high end rig to run on max, but that is required by the complexity of the game[big levels, phys trees+tornado, dyn freeze, AI, nuke, 3d ocean etc. etc.].</div><br /><br />&gt;.&gt;<br /><br />Moving on... <br /><br />Yeah I was hoping for dx9 myself. I loved ETQW for the somewhat volumetric effects via the beauty of OpenGL, but I still only have a geforce 7 series card. Apparently, it's enough  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190859" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 12:19 am "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-weight: bold">"[big levels, phys trees+tornado, dyn freeze, AI, nuke, 3d ocean etc. etc.]"</span><br /><br />That's odd. You're saying this game will be perfect based off of graphical gimmicks that have virtually no impact on what really makes a game good - The actual gameplay, itself. Right now, Crysis is looking more like a tour through a tropical forest within a mountainous landscape with life-sized dummy soldiers that you can shoot for pleasure or just ignore, entirely, with the inclusion of large alien dolls, courtesy of Disney.<br /><br />I'm not saying the game is bad, I'm simply pointing out that Crysis is ridiculously far from perfect. Also, as a side note, does anyone else find it a shame that you can't blow bullet holes through metal structures? Most of them fall right from what's supporting them, which appears to be holding them up with threads of string, which relates to every building in general. It would appear that there's a much larger supply of metal sheets and perfectly cut wood that seal together seemingly perfectly than logs and rope, on a tropical island. <br /><br />Again, this was just a demo.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190863" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 1:12 am "><author>=NoMercy=</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Define a perfect game... Crysis</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190866" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 4:36 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Excellent editor, not my type of game, but very cool modding potential.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190871" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 8:01 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Amazing! <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=GNRvYqTKqFY" class="postlink">LifeLike Intelligence found in Crysis!!</a>.<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190873" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 8:43 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's so bad I almost feel guilty for laughing.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190875" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 8:48 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, my experiences weren't *that* bad. I did find a way to most easily pass by anything. The cloak is a real cheat. Cloack... crouch.. recharge.. cloak.. crouch.. repeat. I walked through the demo without any kills this way. Took me a while though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190876" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 9:38 am "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><span style="font-weight: bold">"[big levels, phys trees+tornado, dyn freeze, AI, nuke, 3d ocean etc. etc.]"</span>That's odd. You're saying this game will be perfect based off of graphical gimmicks that have virtually no impact on what really makes a game good - The actual gameplay, itself.</div>Nah, these things directly impact the gameplay, except maybe 3d ocean.<br /><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Crysis is looking more like a tour through a tropical forest within a mountainous landscape with life-sized dummy soldiers that you can shoot for pleasure or just ignore, entirely, with the inclusion of large alien dolls, courtesy of Disney.</div>I love freedom in games. "...freedom is the only way...". I love to choose what I want to do: either to sneak or annihilate the whole island. I hate when they force me to fight by spawning shit in front of me in a small room and the only choice you can make is which weapon you shoot with.<br /><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Also, as a side note, does anyone else find it a shame that you can't blow bullet holes through metal structures?</div>You want to see bulletholes on objects? They can put it, but they wont, because your computer would die. Your computer would die even if they wouldnt put the time limit on decals probably.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190878" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 9:44 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok, that's not good advertising for the game, but very much fun!<br />(hey - isn't fun supposed to be a vital part of the game?)<br /><br />Well, now we know how "perfect games" are supposed to handle AI <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190889" date="Posted: Tue Oct 30, 2007 4:36 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BloodRayne wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Amazing! <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=GNRvYqTKqFY" class="postlink">LifeLike Intelligence found in Crysis!!</a>.<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div><br /><br />ha ha.<br /><br />here's another one. its just like farcry's AI.<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=glQZBEN_Xjc&amp;NR=1">http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=glQZBEN_Xjc&amp;NR=1</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190908" date="Posted: Wed Oct 31, 2007 1:03 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This one is the best...<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=LJkCWQcZYKo&amp;NR=1">http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=LJkCWQcZYKo&amp;NR=1</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190909" date="Posted: Wed Oct 31, 2007 5:33 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">This one is the best...<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=LJkCWQcZYKo&amp;NR=1">http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=LJkCWQcZYKo&amp;NR=1</a><!-- m --></div><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /><br /><br />Actually, these videos motivate me even more to play the game!<br />I don't care if humor is intentional or not, as long as it makes me smile <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p191159" date="Posted: Mon Nov 05, 2007 12:30 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">With the Crysis SP Demo installation comes more than one hour of high quality cinematic in-game score! It seems to be close to the soundtrack of the whole game!<br /><br />Just extract Music.pak from \Crysis SP Demo\Game\Music.pak with WinRAR...should be ~141MB of Ogg Vorbis files.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p191189" date="Posted: Mon Nov 05, 2007 6:04 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">well, i finished the demo finally over the weekend and here's my one sentence review: <span style="font-weight: bold">its farcry 2.0</span>.<br /><br />some things have improved (graphics, overall production value...), but the gameplay and AI are exactly the same as farcry. not really impressed with the demo...<br /><br />here's another funny AI vid:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://youtube.com/watch?v=OOeL_cOWHa0">http://youtube.com/watch?v=OOeL_cOWHa0</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p191232" date="Posted: Wed Nov 07, 2007 5:21 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">this might be old news, but i guess you can unlock a ton of stuff in the demo (for example, the whole script for the game). check this link out to unlock all the weapons and vehicles...<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851/http://www.rockpapershotgun.com/?p=522">http://www.rockpapershotgun.com/?p=522</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p194465" date="Posted: Sat Feb 02, 2008 2:32 am "><author>ltx11</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152851im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif" alt=":o" title="Surprised" />
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p194502" date="Posted: Sun Feb 03, 2008 7:37 am "><author>Mon1018</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good demo. It's Farcry on steroids, but it's fun and runs better than I expected.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p194545" date="Posted: Mon Feb 04, 2008 11:26 am "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Heh, same here, coincidentially I decided to try out the demo just yesterday. It runs quite well on medium settings here with my 7600GT. Aside from the eyecandy that I was happily served, the gameplay is also very good and the story with the cutscenes was entertaining. I'm going to buy the game once I get better hardware later this year, and it'll probably be cheaper by then, too. Not that it's not worth its full price. All of it oozes production value, the engine, art, sound and storywriting. It didn't crash on me once, even though I changed the gfx settings alot without restarting the game.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199558" date="Posted: Thu May 29, 2008 3:00 pm "><author>steve0</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Aha, nice !</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199583" date="Posted: Thu May 29, 2008 10:53 pm "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">steve0 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Aha, nice !</div><br /><br />Anticlimax!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190725" date="Posted: Fri Oct 26, 2007 9:23 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">... editor included:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607/http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/49658">http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/49658</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190730" date="Posted: Fri Oct 26, 2007 10:04 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">fast direct download link from EA:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607/http://na.llnet.cdn.ea.com/u/demos/Crysis_SP_Demo.exe">http://na.llnet.cdn.ea.com/u/demos/Crysis_SP_Demo.exe</a><!-- m --><br /><br />i'm getting 500kb/s</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190733" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 2:30 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very nice! Here's a list of mirrors at Crysis-Online! (It also has links provided to the latest nVidia drivers that are recommended as well as "Vista Hotfixes", whatever those are.)<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607/http://www.crysis-online.com/?id=441">http://www.crysis-online.com/?id=441</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Meanwhile I'm downloading at anywhere between 600-800 kb from the EA link that <span style="font-weight: bold">pbmax</span> provided (thank you). I'm running an 8800 GTX, but I don't have Vista so I can't test the DX10 stuff which saddens me a little. Anyone got DX10???<br /><br />This is going to be <span style="font-style: italic">so</span> much more entertaining than the mp beta <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190739" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 4:59 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wow, I just played through the demo and I have to say... This game isn't just all graphics. I don't care if this game looked 5 years old, it's pretty cinematic and fun, the story actually has a presence as well.... I think it's time for me to play the demo again.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190740" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 5:04 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... editor included:</div><br /><br />:O, although I suppose the demo of doom3 had that too. Right?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190743" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 6:25 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Check out the SandBox Manual: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607/http://doc.crymod.com/frames.html?frmname=topic&amp;frmfile=index.html">http://doc.crymod.com/frames.html?frmna ... index.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />"Crymod" website: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607/http://www.crymod.com/portal.php">http://www.crymod.com/portal.php</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><br />EDIT:<br />I tried to follow the Generate Terrain and Generate Texture tutorial, but it worked NOTHING like the tutorial did. I left everything on default, just as the tutorial said and of course, my results are opposite. Instead of creating a scattered island, I get a somewhat big/thick island. And the generate texture tool just makes a brighter gray color hahah.<br /><br />Anyone else have this problem?<br /><br />BTW, you load the editor by installing it. It's in the game directory, in the SandBox2 Installer folder. Then you have to launch the .exe called Editor.exe in the Bin32 folder after installation. More hassle than Doom 3 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190748" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 7:01 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kristus wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">... editor included:</div><br />:O, although I suppose the demo of doom3 had that too. Right?</div><br /><br />Actually I don't remember, but how does it relate to Crysis?<br /><br />Plenty of people want to toy around with Crysis, so I guess it's a nice bonus for them.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190754" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 11:50 am "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i'm playing at low settings and it looks pretty bad. tons of LOD popping.<br /><br />it feels a lot like farcry too.<br /><br />i'm gonna crank up the settings just to see what it should look like now...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190758" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:03 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Anyone got DX10???</div><br />i have but i dont have enough RAM at the moment. i ordered 2gb worth that should come next week then i'll be able to play  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p190760" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:35 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">pbmax wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">i'm gonna crank up the settings just to see what it should look like now...</div><br /><br />10 fps at 800x600, lol!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190762" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 1:43 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">10 fps at 800x600, lol!</div><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />  what are your system specs?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190768" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 7:51 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">BTW, you load the editor by installing it. It's in the game directory, in the SandBox2 Installer folder. Then you have to launch the .exe called Editor.exe in the Bin32 folder after installation. More hassle than Doom 3 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" />.</div>To launch doom3 editor you need to go online to know all those shortcut settings and this one is just install and launch. Easy.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190777" date="Posted: Sat Oct 27, 2007 9:58 pm "><author>zeh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good demo. It's Farcry on steroids, but it's fun and runs better than I expected.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190806" date="Posted: Sun Oct 28, 2007 9:12 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I spent some quality time with the demo and am pretty impressed.<br /><br />I run everything on ultra quality on an Intel Q6600, NVIDIA 8800GTX, 2GB RAM, VISTA Ultimate and a resolution of 1680*1050.<br /><br />It runs with borderline performance if 2x AA is enabled, but not at slideshow levels albeit the mouse feels laggy.<br /><br />In any case it looks gorgeous, sometimes like a prerendered movie. There's plenty of post processing going on and it's not a far fetched assumption to declare it the gfx board system seller of 2008. Whatever NVIDIA will sell on the market of their new product line will benefit greatly from Crysis. Like id software a few years ago Crytek has managed to bring one of these "I don't want, no, I need the latest overpriced hardware for this game" alive.<br /><br />If the game AND a 9900Ultra would be available tomorrow I'd line up to get both (after visiting the bank for a third mortgage).<br /><br />I want to say the presentation of the game is surprisingly professional and very cinematic. Fortunately it's not cheesy which lends the game some credibility.<br /><br />It's a nice touch that the enemies speak English on lower difficulty levels, but Korean on higher difficulty. On the other hand I don't know if they have something interesting to say... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />The weapons and suit ingame configuration system is straightforward and has a good accessibility. It seems the developers have put serious thought into the ingame UI. Way to go Crytek!<br /><br />In terms of storyline, gameplay... We'll see how everything holds up over the full race distance...<br /><br />Based on the demo I'd give it a five out of five recommendation stars, assuming you have a system that holds up to the hefty demands in high quality. If you, like me, belong to the people who either want to play something in the best possible quality or not at all - prepare for upgrades.<br /><br />I really want to say it again - this game looks absolutely wow.<br /><br />Have fun!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190809" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 12:03 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">It's a nice touch that the enemies speak English on lower difficulty levels, but Korean on higher difficulty. On the other hand I don't know if they have something interesting to say... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div><br /><br />Yeah I bet they have a lot of funny things to say, but I only played on the hardest difficulty =/. I found the demo to be incredibly easy! If this is how the Koreans -always- are, this easy to avoid and kill then I think we may hear some complaints from fans about that. I found Far Cry a lot more difficult.<br /><br />Though, the AI is pretty amazingly intelligent! Most games that come out now-a-days boast intelligent AI but pretty much never come through, and Crysis was one of them. Of course I was skeptical of this because pretty much every game that ever released boasting realistic AI was just BSing. But they were surprisingly realistic, though they had a few minor weird quirks on making decisions about tactics.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190814" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 4:01 am "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I must say, I was quite excited to try it out, myself. Confident that it'd be just the kind of game I'd enjoy, considering you could charge up and beat your opponents to death with your fists, run quickly behind them and fire a round into the back of their head before they could even react, or sneak up right infront of them with "Cloak" and open up nearly endless possibilities of playstyles and techniques, I downloaded it immediately. To my surprise, Crysis is perhaps the most graphically enhanced game I've ever played in my life - Even beating Unreal Tournament 3, to an extent. At times, I must add, I felt like I was watching an animated show up to par with Shrek and other titles. It was an amazing experience, especially dropping from the airplane.<br /><br />However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same. This was just a demo, though, and I can't forget that.<br /><br />The point is, Crysis didn't impress me with the combat. Not even remotely. The scenery and plantlife were outstanding, but the game also featured a very linear feeling, seeing as the rocks were placed to keep you from going up to high grounds, for example, and the hills were perfectly shaped to create a path through what would naturally be like a maze or dungeon of trees, ferns, grass, vines, and the like. The water was especially beautiful, and I could sit and stare at it for an hour and still find it of high artistic significance. The clouds, the sun - The game, no doubt about it, is the best you'll be seeing for quite awhile, assuming Unreal Tournament 3 sacrifices scenery for gameplay.<br /><br />The objectives are typical, of course, and killing Koreans gets old and boring after you shoot them right between the eyes one after another. Same patrols, same behavior, and too little life-like interaction with the environment. I'd expect someone to quickly pick up a barrel and position it or hide behind one entirely to create a small defense for himself, rather than run to the nearest wall and stand behind it for mediocre cover. I'd also expect them to be sleeping, or just waking up, and not looking into the forest or staring out in a random direction as if expecting some super-suit equipped American soldier to fly out and strangle him to death when they haven't witnessed one, yet. It would also be nice to see them sit down and relax, once in awhile. Get bored, tired, thirsty, hungry. These are humans, and this "battle-hardened, tireless, and ruthless killer" crap is getting old. Infact, judging by how I witnessed one running away with panic, I imagine they're not so tough, at all. Thus, I expect them to show more realistic behavior, not just a high-polygon model with generic AI. Once again, this is just the demo of the first level, and I'm judging too quickly.<br /><br />The game shows elements we've already seen in Far Cry, and while I do find the suit to be quite awesome, I just don't feel that much has changed besides the graphics. Especially the stealth system in the game, which, ever since Far Cry, has been terrible. You could hide between a bunch of trees behind a bush, and suddenly a soldier looks in your direction and spots you, alerts the entire squad he's with, and fires perfect shots at you, just because he quickly turned his head and suddenly saw a millimeter-by-millimeter speck of silver which no human alive would naturally be able to see in a quick glance. I do appreciate their tendancy to give up the chase, but I'd like the game to offer a little more stealth without having to rely on "full invisibility" as a way of cheating their way around it.<br /><br />Since I'm doing nothing but ranting, I'll get to a conclusion...<br />The game is great, very beautiful and it offers a lot, and is quite fun and challenging, but I really feel that I'm just playing a mod for Far Cry. Especially when you consider you're still facing monsters among men, only this time they're aliens with freeze rays. I'll still purchase it, and maybe then I'll leave my final opinion. Plus, traversing the alien ship sounds like it'll be a blast.<br /><br />Also, having difficulties moving because of my left hand took out some of the experience, so that's another reason I didn't have extraordinaire amounts of fun with it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190815" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:04 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same.</div><br /><br />Have to agree with you there. Everyone has been making a big deal over it and I really don't think it's that interesting, it's not original enough to be a big gimmick. I think Crysis's gimmick here is it's beautiful graphics, and also it's fun game-play.<br /><br />But what's wrong with the linear experience? It's supposed to be a cinematic experience, and I really feel they've done an incredible job. It's got the same battle sandbox feel as it did in Far Cry, which is one of the reasons why everyone liked it so much, so it gives some freedom there. Sure it's no exploration game, but that's not what I'm looking for in Crysis.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190816" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:16 am "><author>Phobos</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Dinky wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">However, once I landed, I was smacked in the back of the head with the unfortunate truth about Crysis. It's a first person shooter, at heart, and no matter what "super cool" things they add to it, it's still just a first person shooter, and all of these things have been done before. I've seen super-high jumping in Alien vs. Predator 2, I've ran inhumanly-fast in S.T.A.L.K.E.R., I've punched with superhuman strength in Doom 3, I've turned invisible and had enhanced armor in countless games, and modifying your weapon with unnecessary trinkets doesn't make it anymore pleasing than an unmodified rifle, from what I've experienced. The outcome is usually the same.</div><br /><br />Have to agree with you there. Everyone has been making a big deal over it and I really don't think it's that interesting, it's not original enough to be a big gimmick. I think Crysis's gimmick here is it's beautiful graphics, and also it's fun game-play.<br /><br />But what's wrong with the linear experience? It's supposed to be a cinematic experience, and I really feel they've done an incredible job. It's got the same battle sandbox feel as it did in Far Cry, which is one of the reasons why everyone liked it so much, so it gives some freedom there. Sure it's no exploration game, but that's not what I'm looking for in Crysis.</div><br /><br />That's what gets me <span style="font-style: italic">off</span>, in the same way. I totally agree about the linear part, partly because I guess I was expecting more freedom as a player to be able to make my own decisions, but when I saw what the AI had to offer and the same encounters kept.. encountering.. over and over, I got a very linear feel; especially the mountains and only having one real path to go. I felt like a rat in a maze to some extent. <br /><br />Of course, I was too busy paying attention to all the eyecandy to really care at first. It's just a sort of underlying feel that I hope is creased out in the multiplayer.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190834" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:05 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You know whats incredible in this game? Tornadoes! I love them smashing and raping the island. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /> Helicopter handling is also very well done, much easier to handle than in Arma or Just Cause. Also you whine too much, the game is perfect.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p190835" date="Posted: Mon Oct 29, 2007 5:06 pm "><author>Bo$bevok</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">having this game on my hd has been driving me nuts... i havent got enough ram to play it. i ordered more which i should recieve in the next few days. however, seeing the icon on my desktop was driving me nuts so i decided i'll give it a go. because of having vista i was worried about my performance so i went online and found how to run it in direct x 9. still not enough memory but i played on medium settings in anycase. wow. i think the graphics are great even in this mode and the cinematic feel was amazing.what most surprised me was how smooth it ran. the min requirements say that you need atleast 1gb ram and i have just under but it still played smooth.high qaulity has alot of loading pauses which make it unplayable until i get my extra 2gb ram. i do agree it was quite linear but because its the first level you cant really judge how the later ones will play.when i get my RAM this week im going to put this baby up to high settings and give it a spin  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081115003607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />cant wait</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
