<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20811"><title>[Release] Fine Detail Mapper (DOT3 / DuDv)</title><posts><post id="p191539" date="Posted: Fri Nov 16, 2007 2:36 am "><author>LiX</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://ethocybin.com/utilities/finedetailmaps.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold">Quote Ethocybin.com </span>"This tool produces DOT3 and DuDv bump maps, with a wide range of customizability options. This smart utility will even detect when a source heightmap contains more than one colour channel and will ask you which colour channel you would like to be sampled for the heightmap data.<br /><br />The particular utility focuses on increasing the detail levels in the produced bump map, even utilizing resize algorithms from the Retro Emulation scene.<br /><br />It's a strange new feat in normal mapping technology, merging technology from unexpected scenes into a pleasing new product for a brave new world of 3D artists."<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold">Download Link:</span><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://ethocybin.com/files/finedetailmaps.zip">http://ethocybin.com/files/finedetailmaps.zip</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><br />Definatly interested in constructive feedback - although keep in mind this is what it is, it's unlikly i'll be updating it. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p191547" date="Posted: Fri Nov 16, 2007 5:17 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Starting out I needed the msvcr70.dll file, once downloaded and place in the folder it ran fine.  It works great but always ends up rotating my image 90 degrees.  Also even though it takes little time to compile a bump map, I tihnk a little progress bar would be user friendly.  Other than that it works perfectly.  Automatically exports a separate .tga file with the bump name attached.   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
