<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20851"><title>Blending alpha textures into non-alpha textures</title><posts><post id="p191874" date="Posted: Sun Nov 25, 2007 11:11 pm "><author>Springheel</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've been running some tests without success. Maybe someone can tell me if this is possible.<br /><br />I'm currently making skins for AI models.  What I'd like to do is create, for example, two textures, a blue and a green tunic texture. Then I'd like to create an 'emblem' texture that is transparent, except for the emblem part. I was hoping to then add that texture into the material using a blend stage.  By mixing and matching, I could combine each emblem with each colour tunic without having to bake it into the texture file itself.<br /><br />The trick is, I don't know if it's possible to 'blend' one diffusemap that uses an alpha stage with a diffusemap that doesn't. So far I haven't had any luck...if either diffusemap has a transparent part, it renders as transparent in game (so I wind up with an invisible tunic except for the emblem).<br /><br />Anyone know if there's a way to do this?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p191882" date="Posted: Mon Nov 26, 2007 5:23 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">A material shader can only have one diffuse stage. So if you want the tunic and the emblem to be separate, they will require separate material shaders.<br /><br />That said, the way to handle this problem is to treat the emblem like a decal. And that means you'll need a separate surface to apply the decal to.<br /><br />This means you'll need one of your modelers to add a bit of extra floating geometry wherever an emblem needs to reside. And the end result will be a character model that makes use of more than one material shader. This is actually pretty commonplace if you look at the stock Doom 3 assets.<br /><br />And one other thing to keep in mind, only alphatested transparency works in conjunction with illumination. So if you want the emblem to be lit, it must make use of a diffuse stage coupled with the alphatest keyword rather than a blend blend stage.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
