<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20905"><title>smoothing and der_tons exporter</title><posts><post id="p192378" date="Posted: Sun Dec 09, 2007 3:10 am "><author>Baddcog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Another issue.<br /><br />My mesh was smoothed before I exported it. At some point part of the mesh decided to unsmooth itself.<br /><br />Has anyone had these issues with the exporter?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192391" date="Posted: Sun Dec 09, 2007 10:00 pm "><author>LDAsh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I had some issues like this too, solving it by selecting all triangles belonging to a certain texture (material ID) and clicking "unify" in the surface properties of the editable mesh.  I'm not entirely sure what I was doing though and also tried some other stuff like the "clear all"/"auto smooth" button, but I wasn't relying on any smoothing anyway because of the round cartoonish shape I was working with.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192392" date="Posted: Sun Dec 09, 2007 10:17 pm "><author>Baddcog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Coll, thanks. I'll give it a try.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192393" date="Posted: Mon Dec 10, 2007 1:11 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I noticed on a mesh it was the same smooth breaks as the UV seams (the textures cuts on the mesh)... don't know if that's that 100%.<br />(side note: Hi all, it's been a loooong time!)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192394" date="Posted: Mon Dec 10, 2007 2:24 am "><author>Baddcog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Didn't have much luck with the unify command.<br /><br />I ended up just selecting polys for sections that I wanted smoothed seperately (sharp edges) and apllied the same texture from a different texture slot. So when it exported it made that a seperate mesh.<br />Basically what 6th venom said.<br /><br />Then I applied a smooth modifier and ramped it up to 180.<br /><br />Still have a little issue left but it's not too noticable, might also be caused by my unfinished normal map.<br /> I can live with it though. I only noticed when I slayed the bot and dragged him, it was right in my face.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192395" date="Posted: Mon Dec 10, 2007 3:06 am "><author>LDAsh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><a href="/web/20070509181516/http://www.violationentertainment.com/files/video/SHclobberMD5071128.wmv" class="postlink">http://www.violationentertainment.com/files/video/SHclobberMD5071128.wmv</a><br />Originally I had sharp seams along parts of the model where I had first attached things together in MilkShape exporting Quake 3 Arena.  It always exported fine as ASE but when I tried MD5 all those old pieces became unsmoothed in-game even though I had applied smoothing.  So somehow the smoothing information had been deeply hidden in the model all that time even though I smoothed it.  It wasn't until I toyed around with surface properties that I could export a good MD5, so I'm certain the answer is there, for my case at least.  The UV layout on this is the same from 2002, a horrible mess in different pieces, but no problem concerning that since it has a (crap but) proper normalmap.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192396" date="Posted: Mon Dec 10, 2007 5:07 am "><author>Baddcog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice clown! Like how he smacks himself in the nose and laughs.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192501" date="Posted: Thu Dec 13, 2007 1:10 pm "><author>der_ton</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The md5 format doesn't hold any normalvectors for vertices, or an equivalent of "smoothgroups" for triangles. My 3dsmax exporter doesn't create unsmoothed edges on purpose, it tries to export a mesh as smooth as possible (which means with the smallest number of cloned vertices), but there are situations where a vertex has to be split before it goes into the md5. That's for example if it is on a UV-seam or material seam.<br /><br />As an alternative, when you run into such problems you can always try Berserker's exporter. It behaves differently in some aspects and might produce different results in some situations.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192505" date="Posted: Thu Dec 13, 2007 3:50 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Or work like this:<br />1-Create your low &amp; high poly models.<br />2-Create your low poly custom UVW map.<br />3-Export it with der_ton md5exporter &amp; reimport it into max.<br />(doing this first your model will have ' "cuts" on uvw edges)<br />4-then do your high to low(the imported one) models projection (create the normals+diffuse+specular)<br /><br />Doing like this is the best way to be sure your normalmap take care of "cuts", and so the normalmap will correct this itself.  <img src="/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
