<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="20907"><title>transparent door problem</title><posts><post id="p192408" date="Posted: Mon Dec 10, 2007 3:42 pm "><author>Pan-</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If i stay in front of a closed transparent door there is a hole in the map at the top, left, right and bottom brushface of the func_door brush. I placed a visportal into the door.<br />Any idea how to fix that?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192409" date="Posted: Mon Dec 10, 2007 3:44 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Why would you place a visportal in a transparent door?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192410" date="Posted: Mon Dec 10, 2007 4:02 pm "><author>Pan-</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">cause the hole gets bigger and bigger if you move the visportal somewhere else.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192420" date="Posted: Tue Dec 11, 2007 2:41 am "><author>Sikkpin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Since the door is transparent, there is no need for a visportal. Just delete it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192421" date="Posted: Tue Dec 11, 2007 7:16 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, he's not entirely off the mark. A visportal will scale off anything that isn't viewable through it's frame, even if it's open. But if you place it inside a door with a glass screen in it, it will close when the door closes, and that will lead to undesired effects. So, a big nono to put visportals in see through doors.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192452" date="Posted: Wed Dec 12, 2007 7:52 am "><author>Pan-</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i also get that bug if the visportal is in front of the door for example 64 units.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p192472" date="Posted: Wed Dec 12, 2007 11:47 pm "><author>Sikkpin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If you haven't already, read <a href="/web/20071227193906/http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/visportals.php" class="postlink">this</a> and <a href="/web/20071227193906/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Visportal" class="postlink">this</a> to get a better understanding what visportals do. This is just a guess as I don't know the geometry layout you are working with but you probably don't need a visportal at all where you are wanting to use it.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
