<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="21510"><title>z1corvette and the md5Scale.exe</title><posts><post id="p198781" date="Posted: Fri May 09, 2008 9:30 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">z1corvette created a very under-mentioned EXE found in the now-defunct Chex Trek mod. This EXE allowed me to scale existing md5meshes via rescaling their animations. Afterwards, all that was required was a new model.def and a new AF. <br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20110527211912im_/http://www.trepaning.com/pics/dn/dn-scale.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />I feel this EXE has potential that has been overlooked, so I am bringing it to the forefront in hopes z1corvette posts it and any information regarding it in this thread.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p198782" date="Posted: Fri May 09, 2008 9:58 pm "><author>Marineofuac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">oh man thats awsome!!!<br />when rescaling, i always had to rerig the model in max!<br /><br />your saying with this you just pop the model in then bam? insta big?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p198787" date="Posted: Fri May 09, 2008 11:42 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Like all things, there are issues, but with my rigging, it worked perfectly every time and was as simple as writing the required .BAT file, which creates x.md5anim from y.md5anim with a specified xyz scale (xyz are independent). As it is, however, it does not rework the mesh itself, so the mesh gets squashed or stretched, not rescaled proportionately. Only the "bones" get resized. Still, knowing the limits and planning to work with them allows for this to be a really cool tool.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p198791" date="Posted: Sat May 10, 2008 12:28 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20110527211912/http://www.trepaning.com/md5Scale/md5ScaleEXE.zip" class="postlink">Here is a link to a ZIP of the files  10k</a><br /><br />It says scale_biped  but I used my own bone rigging.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p198793" date="Posted: Sat May 10, 2008 1:54 am "><author>revility</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Would this allow to scale up a hellknight?  If so, i could do that to the barons of hell for demon xp 2 and ruiner.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p198799" date="Posted: Sat May 10, 2008 6:08 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just a thought: Use md5scale.exe to rescale the anims by x%, then scale the rigged-mesh in a 3d program by same x% and export a proportionately scaled md5mesh to fit the anims. I can see an issue that may not work already (scaling rigged-mesh bones but may not be an issue, being the export is an md5mesh), but it's just an idea I don't have time to test beyond this.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p198800" date="Posted: Sat May 10, 2008 6:35 am "><author>zl1corvette</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hehe you've drawn me out of lurking<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">Marineofuac wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">when rescaling, i always had to rerig the model in max!</div><br />Yeah that's what I wrote this, mostly because I could not figure out how to do it at all in max.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">revility wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Would this allow to scale up a hellknight? If so, i could do that to the barons of hell for demon xp 2 and ruiner.</div><br />I tried it and it crashed.  The code behind the program isn't so good, looking back at it I found myself saying wtf a lot... But I managed to update the code fixing other bugs too and now it works <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20110527211912im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> I made hellknights 5x in size and they looked pretty good still.<br /><br />@Brain<br />glad you found the tool useful.  It can scale meshes too not just the animations, so it shouldn't make things look deformed.  If you scale more in one axis then another it can start to look bad fast though.<br /><br />Another thing you have to watch out for is if the def file has an offset for the model (because origin bone is offset) you need to scale that by the same amount otherwise it'll be all off center.<br /><br />There is another mode to md5scale that reorders the joints in a mesh file.  I don't even remember why I wanted to do this, I think I had changed something in a mesh file and then max had the order exported different order not matching the anim files.  Anyway it's there, should still work.<br /><br />I uploaded the updated code to this post.  I included the source code, the exe, and two scripts for running it.  One is the batch script Brain had, and the other is a shell script.  Both are for scaling a model and it's animations.<br /><br />Usually to convert a whole set of animations and models copy them to a subdirectory called backup or something like that.  Then from the subdirectory you could do something like this to scale a mesh by 1.5x<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">md5scale -s 1.5 1.5 1.5 -m mymodel.md5mesh &gt; ..\mymodel.md5mesh</div><br />animation<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">md5scale -s 1.5 1.5 1.5 -a mymodelidle.md5anim &gt; ..\mymodelidle.md5anim</div><br />best way is to use a script otherwise you'll go crazy with all the files.<br /><br />edit:<br />das big hellknight<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20110527211912im_/http://i127.photobucket.com/albums/p150/OldCigarette/shot00003.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />without an updated AF he goes pretty crazy when he dies though :/</div>]]></body></post><post id="p198805" date="Posted: Sat May 10, 2008 7:46 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That is awesome, thanks for the updates!<br /><br />I will make a fantasy wishlist in the event of any future development:<br /><br />1. GUI<br /><br />2. Scale ASE/LWO<br /><br />btw, a new AF and DEF file for scaled monsters take about 10 minutes to make, a small amount of time once the original model is in place. Add some SKIN files and the character numbers grow very quickly.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
