<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="21591"><title>DNF footage</title><posts><post id="p199879" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 7:58 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just saw this on Kotaku<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945/http://kotaku.com/5013638/first-duke-nukem-forever-gameplay-video">http://kotaku.com/5013638/first-duke-nu ... play-video</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Btw...the game i was working on <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945/http://www.ageofconan.com/">http://www.ageofconan.com/</a><!-- m --> is out now and if anyone is playing it (eu servers) ...let me know.<br /><br />I should also take this time to thank Berni for this forum <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> THX</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199880" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 8:37 am "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it looks good, like Duke3D</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199882" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 9:26 am "><author>aaa111</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">what is duke.............<br /><br />duke nukem..<br />duke nukem...... <br /><br />oh God i remember now,its duke nukem forever.<br /><br />Hope my grand grand grand children will able to play it at 2090.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199883" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 9:37 am "><author>shaviro</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wow. That looks almost exactly like Duke3d <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p199893" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 4:08 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here are some quotes by George Broussard regarding this footage with some comments/questions for context. First one is before the release of the footage but is included because it seems to confirm a certain feature:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">That crate can't be in game. Too low res and no ambient occlusion.</div><br /><br />The rest are after the release of and about the footage:<br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">I hope this isn't Doom 3 (indoors and dark).</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">It's not. This was a snippet from one level inside hoover dam, for a few mins. there are large outdoor environments, too, and tons of stuff not seen here. I wasn't even sure they were going to show game footage as the original deal was to just film jason playing the game, and a reaction. They cut in a few scenese here and there. Much much more to see and come.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We only let jason play a small section of one level. rest assured there are large ooutdoor open areas and much much more to come. this is but a small taste.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">You're looking at it from a scientific angle, only analyzing a few seconds of gameplay. Most people look at it as confirmation that the game they want to play is alive, breathing, and coming...<br /><br />There is so much more to show, it's silly. And it still won't be enough for lots of people, and that's ok.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Never fear, there are bright, daylight levels, as well. I'd say all times of day and mood are represented at some point. There is a mixture of corridor crawls, and larger more open areas (indoor and out).</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Any voice in there was added by HD Films and isn't in game.</div><br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">That EDF supply crate is one of the worst crates in the history of crates. But otherwise... /throws confetti!</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"> Been replaced for quite a while now. That footage is 6 months old and lots of things are updated or tweaked/different now.</div><br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">oh yeah, the points thing that pops up definitly needs to go</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Programmer art and temp, which is why footage was never really intended to be shown, and why we're not quite doing "official" releases of in game stuff. It's in progress but about to have another polish pass.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We do polish passes on things all the time. It just depends what the focus is. Some people are polishing and others are building new things, and it all changes all the time. There are times when we lock down for 3-4 weeks and virtually everyone works on polish as a core goal, too.</div><br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">so does this video count as "stay tuned" material?</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Not really. It was kind of random.</div><br /><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"> The particle effects in this video are about 6 months old and most of the combat fx have been replaced by now with new hotness.</div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p199908" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 6:13 pm "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how sad is it that game designers have to go out of their way to say "big outdoor/sunny/brightly lit areas". Just..unbelievable. Go outside if you want to bask in the sun.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199912" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 8:27 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@_shank: What did you do on "Age of Conan"? <br /><br />Giant Monsters + Conan = WIN (imo)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199932" date="Posted: Sat Jun 07, 2008 10:14 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">@_shank: What did you do on "Age of Conan"? <br /><br />Giant Monsters + Conan = WIN (imo)</div><br /><br />Level design...for 1-20, 20-40, 60-80 level ranges...few Raid Dungeons.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199934" date="Posted: Sat Jun 07, 2008 12:22 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">shaviro wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Wow. That looks almost exactly like Duke3d <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div><br /><br />I just saw the footage &amp; 100% agree.  it's like Duke3d, but all new.  Like a REAL seuqel &amp; not something that has nothing to do with the previous besides a character name.<br /><br />I'd say that's how it's not doom 3.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />I hope they release it soon.  looks really really nice &amp; unless it's a joke &amp; a mod in Prey, i'd assume they're on the "almost ready!" part of the game.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p199936" date="Posted: Sat Jun 07, 2008 1:32 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The game footage reminds me of Alpha Prime, Doom3 and Prey abit. Which is not a good sign.<div class="quotetitle">TelMarine wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">how sad is it that game designers have to go out of their way to say "big outdoor/sunny/brightly lit areas". Just..unbelievable. Go outside if you want to bask in the sun.</div> lol post of the century.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200043" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 2:47 pm "><author>Argoon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What in that footage reminds of Prey or Doom3? Just because it uses normal mapping and a similar shadow tech? By the way What the looks have to do with the game play and why is it a bad Thing?? <br />To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. <br />Is strange you guys saying this when you are members of a ID Tech4 fan forum.<br /><br />Now about the footage, to me it looks as any other game that uses normal mapping and real time shadows but with better ambient lighting, about the game play, we only have a small part so i can't really say much about it only that some of the Duke cool stuff is in there like the shrink ray the mighty boot the 3 barrel gun the pipe bomb and a new thing to Duke, now we can see its full body  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" />  .  Oh and don't forget BIG and MEAN pig cops.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" />  (let them come)<br /> What i saw that i didn't like was the almost total lack of gore what is a sacrilege for a DN game, but they already said this are 6 months old footage and that many things have changed and been added since them.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200047" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 5:06 pm "><author>Arklon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Argoon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. </div>I remember reading somewhere they switched to UE3. Not sure, though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200051" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 6:32 pm "><author>Argoon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Arklon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Argoon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. </div>I remember reading somewhere they switched to UE3. Not sure, though.</div><br /><br />No they didn't it is still UE2 but they made a totally new nextgen render system (among other things) for the engine, as features is concerned this new render is as capable as the UE3 engine one.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200057" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 10:11 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Argoon is correct: <br /><br />Question:<br /><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Seriously, though. What version of the Unreal Engine is DNF going to be using? Unreal Engine 2.5 or 3.0?</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Neither. We broke off many moons ago. About all we use from Unreal now is the editor, networking and Unreal Script.</div> - George Broussard, November 16nd, 2005.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">I think we split off around Unreal 2 level tech and wrote our own rendering, and a lot of other things.</div> - George Broussard, February 15nd, 2005.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">If you already support 2.0 then 3.0 is easy to support. It's nice that 3.0 is here to develop on, but most developers aren't even using 2.0 at the moment, so the 3.0 stuff is likely here too early.<br /><br />DNF has a full HLSL pipe and we can pretty much support any rendering mode or feature that cards can do.</div> - George Broussard, May <br />12th, 2004.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We've completely gutted and written our own AI system, rendering, particles, skeletal animation and more so it won't look/feel like an Unreal game at all I don't think</div> - George Broussard, January 7nd, 2004.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">No reason to freeze, as we have time to trickle in features until the game ships. But it's complete enough now that we could ship with no excuses and be happy.<br /><br />But just like in Duke 3D, when that engine was done, we still added small features like slopes and went back and retrofit the levels. We will still add things to the engine, as we can, where they make sense, and most importantly - where they won't delay us. We will add things if they are cool and don't impact things, but we will not add features that will cause big delays or mass reworking of exisiting content. </div> - George Broussard, January 17nd, 2004.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Don't worry. When I say tech complete, I mean we could ship if all the content were done.<br />It's fairly easy to add and update shaders and we do so all the time.<br />The graphics guys are ahead and always have time to add in bells and whistles.<br />Many things like per pixel blur, depth of field etc, have zero impact on game content and drop in, in a few days.</div> - George Broussard, March 30th, 2006.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200058" date="Posted: Tue Jun 10, 2008 12:23 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Arklon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Argoon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. </div>I remember reading somewhere they switched to UE3. Not sure, though.</div><br /><br />I heard the same thing. But I remember I heard it from Journalists like IGN or something - and those guys are usually wrong 90% of the time about the technology in games, so I took it with a grain of salt, like I do everything whenever they mention the technology behind the games, or for that matter, most subjects completely. Like for example, the mix up with id software and other company's to leave the ESA, it seemed like all those so-called "Reasons" these developers left were completely made up by the media.<br /><br />Journalists are bad source for tech info, definitely.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200256" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 3:41 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I saw the footage and it was nice and all, but frankly, I'm very tired of the, "Oh, we could ship and be happy"  (note the dates on those quotes) on the one hand, and the "our masterpiece needs more polish--no wait, let's rip apart the entire game and start over again--let's adopt a 'when it's done' attitude!" on the other... <br /><br />11 years and counting... it's time to put up or shut up, in my opinion.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200258" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 4:18 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i'd say it's annoying too, but 99% of all game companies say that too.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200260" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 4:22 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah but they release their games in 2-4 years max!<br /><br />It's told that after DNF 3drealms will start a ShadowWarrior's sequel that will be released in... let's count... 2020!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200266" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 5:10 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Yeah but they release their games in 2-4 years max!</div><br /><br />Half Life 2 &amp; TF2 are examples of not being released anywhere near when they said they're ready to go.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155945im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200271" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 5:57 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">goliathvt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I saw the footage and it was nice and all, but frankly, I'm very tired of the, "Oh, we could ship and be happy"  (note the dates on those quotes) on the one hand, and the "our masterpiece needs more polish--no wait, let's rip apart the entire game and start over again--let's adopt a 'when it's done' attitude!" on the other... <br /><br />11 years and counting... it's time to put up or shut up, in my opinion.</div><br /><br />In the quote you are talking about he said that could ship and be happy if all the content was done, but it wasn't that is the thing. He was only talking about the status of the engine, their technology always being in a state of constant flux and them being unable to finish the engine has been one of the main reasons for the long development time, that issue has been completely fixed since late 2002/early 2003 when the last restart took place. The new renderer was done in November 2002 and there have been no engine switches or restarts since then. <br /><br />HL2 took like 6 years to make, so if this version of DNF is to take as long then that puts us into 2009. The "When it's done" attitude is far superior to giving out release dates you can't keep. But remember WID is a PR stance to take regarding release dates and it is not really connected to scheduling as such(As a matter of fact they recently hired Brian Hook as Producer, responsible for amongst other things <span style="font-weight: bold">scheduling</span>). You can use WID as a tagline to the press and still have fairly strict internal deadlines and from the Dallas Business Journal interview with Scott Miller it seems that there is a strong internal push to release this game this year or early next year. Polish is certainly far from throwing everything out and restarting the game so there really is no "let's rip apart the entire game and start over" attitude any longer and there hasn't been since 2002.<br /><br />"11 years and counting... it's time to put up or shut up, in my opinion"<br /><br />This is their exact attitude to hype/media, they could have shown the game in 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005 or 2006 and they didn't. They didn't show ANYTHING at all from the current version of the game until 2007 when they showed two 200x150 thumbnails for job ads and a small 1 minute teaser trailer at the VERY VERY end of the year. Since they ditched the 1998-2001 version of the game they have always maintained that they are against hyping games too early and that has been one of the biggest mistakes they have done. They have been pretty adamant about wanting to start the hype train <span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="text-decoration: underline">approximately</span></span></span> 6 months - 1 year from release and their actions have been virtually 100% consistent with that stance.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205660" date="Posted: Fri Oct 03, 2008 4:33 pm "><author>=NoMercy=</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I didn't start that, he did.   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117204113im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />I was just saying that I am (and I'm sure most gamers out there) are much more excited to see a screenshot of DN4E vs anything from id.  Id went from a company that had a lot of excitement &amp; vision in their early days to a company that goes by sales since Q3A.  Yeah, sales make $$ but there's already enough companies that put out boring stuff to make $$.  many of them do it really really well, but, honestly, those games are a dime a dozen.  I'd rather see Doom 4 continue after Doom 2 with the same graphics &amp; gameplay vs following Doom 3 with the same boring scripted sequences &amp; predictable story elements/situations as every other game out there.  Duke hopefully doesn't do any of that &amp; tries new things.</div><br /><br />The only thing I would be excited to see from ID atm would be Doom 4 and a new Quake. Rage doesn't seem to interest me much, but I'll probably get it. <br /><br />I am excited for DNF, just finished Duke Nukem 3D on the 360, what a great game.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199879" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 7:58 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just saw this on Kotaku<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419/http://kotaku.com/5013638/first-duke-nukem-forever-gameplay-video">http://kotaku.com/5013638/first-duke-nu ... play-video</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Btw...the game i was working on <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419/http://www.ageofconan.com/">http://www.ageofconan.com/</a><!-- m --> is out now and if anyone is playing it (eu servers) ...let me know.<br /><br />I should also take this time to thank Berni for this forum <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> THX</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199880" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 8:37 am "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it looks good, like Duke3D</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199882" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 9:26 am "><author>aaa111</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">what is duke.............<br /><br />duke nukem..<br />duke nukem...... <br /><br />oh God i remember now,its duke nukem forever.<br /><br />Hope my grand grand grand children will able to play it at 2090.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199883" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 9:37 am "><author>shaviro</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wow. That looks almost exactly like Duke3d <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p199893" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 4:08 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here are some quotes by George Broussard regarding this footage with some comments/questions for context. First one is before the release of the footage but is included because it seems to confirm a certain feature:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">That crate can't be in game. Too low res and no ambient occlusion.</div><br /><br />The rest are after the release of and about the footage:<br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">I hope this isn't Doom 3 (indoors and dark).</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">It's not. This was a snippet from one level inside hoover dam, for a few mins. there are large outdoor environments, too, and tons of stuff not seen here. I wasn't even sure they were going to show game footage as the original deal was to just film jason playing the game, and a reaction. They cut in a few scenese here and there. Much much more to see and come.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We only let jason play a small section of one level. rest assured there are large ooutdoor open areas and much much more to come. this is but a small taste.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">You're looking at it from a scientific angle, only analyzing a few seconds of gameplay. Most people look at it as confirmation that the game they want to play is alive, breathing, and coming...<br /><br />There is so much more to show, it's silly. And it still won't be enough for lots of people, and that's ok.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Never fear, there are bright, daylight levels, as well. I'd say all times of day and mood are represented at some point. There is a mixture of corridor crawls, and larger more open areas (indoor and out).</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Any voice in there was added by HD Films and isn't in game.</div><br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">That EDF supply crate is one of the worst crates in the history of crates. But otherwise... /throws confetti!</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"> Been replaced for quite a while now. That footage is 6 months old and lots of things are updated or tweaked/different now.</div><br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">oh yeah, the points thing that pops up definitly needs to go</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Programmer art and temp, which is why footage was never really intended to be shown, and why we're not quite doing "official" releases of in game stuff. It's in progress but about to have another polish pass.</div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We do polish passes on things all the time. It just depends what the focus is. Some people are polishing and others are building new things, and it all changes all the time. There are times when we lock down for 3-4 weeks and virtually everyone works on polish as a core goal, too.</div><br /><br />Comment:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">so does this video count as "stay tuned" material?</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Not really. It was kind of random.</div><br /><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"> The particle effects in this video are about 6 months old and most of the combat fx have been replaced by now with new hotness.</div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p199908" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 6:13 pm "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how sad is it that game designers have to go out of their way to say "big outdoor/sunny/brightly lit areas". Just..unbelievable. Go outside if you want to bask in the sun.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199912" date="Posted: Fri Jun 06, 2008 8:27 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@_shank: What did you do on "Age of Conan"? <br /><br />Giant Monsters + Conan = WIN (imo)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199932" date="Posted: Sat Jun 07, 2008 10:14 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">@_shank: What did you do on "Age of Conan"? <br /><br />Giant Monsters + Conan = WIN (imo)</div><br /><br />Level design...for 1-20, 20-40, 60-80 level ranges...few Raid Dungeons.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p199934" date="Posted: Sat Jun 07, 2008 12:22 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">shaviro wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Wow. That looks almost exactly like Duke3d <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div><br /><br />I just saw the footage &amp; 100% agree.  it's like Duke3d, but all new.  Like a REAL seuqel &amp; not something that has nothing to do with the previous besides a character name.<br /><br />I'd say that's how it's not doom 3.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />I hope they release it soon.  looks really really nice &amp; unless it's a joke &amp; a mod in Prey, i'd assume they're on the "almost ready!" part of the game.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p199936" date="Posted: Sat Jun 07, 2008 1:32 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The game footage reminds me of Alpha Prime, Doom3 and Prey abit. Which is not a good sign.<div class="quotetitle">TelMarine wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">how sad is it that game designers have to go out of their way to say "big outdoor/sunny/brightly lit areas". Just..unbelievable. Go outside if you want to bask in the sun.</div> lol post of the century.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200043" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 2:47 pm "><author>Argoon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What in that footage reminds of Prey or Doom3? Just because it uses normal mapping and a similar shadow tech? By the way What the looks have to do with the game play and why is it a bad Thing?? <br />To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. <br />Is strange you guys saying this when you are members of a ID Tech4 fan forum.<br /><br />Now about the footage, to me it looks as any other game that uses normal mapping and real time shadows but with better ambient lighting, about the game play, we only have a small part so i can't really say much about it only that some of the Duke cool stuff is in there like the shrink ray the mighty boot the 3 barrel gun the pipe bomb and a new thing to Duke, now we can see its full body  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" />  .  Oh and don't forget BIG and MEAN pig cops.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" />  (let them come)<br /> What i saw that i didn't like was the almost total lack of gore what is a sacrilege for a DN game, but they already said this are 6 months old footage and that many things have changed and been added since them.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200047" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 5:06 pm "><author>Arklon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Argoon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. </div>I remember reading somewhere they switched to UE3. Not sure, though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200051" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 6:32 pm "><author>Argoon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Arklon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Argoon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. </div>I remember reading somewhere they switched to UE3. Not sure, though.</div><br /><br />No they didn't it is still UE2 but they made a totally new nextgen render system (among other things) for the engine, as features is concerned this new render is as capable as the UE3 engine one.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200057" date="Posted: Mon Jun 09, 2008 10:11 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Argoon is correct: <br /><br />Question:<br /><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Seriously, though. What version of the Unreal Engine is DNF going to be using? Unreal Engine 2.5 or 3.0?</div><br /><br />Answer:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Neither. We broke off many moons ago. About all we use from Unreal now is the editor, networking and Unreal Script.</div> - George Broussard, November 16nd, 2005.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">I think we split off around Unreal 2 level tech and wrote our own rendering, and a lot of other things.</div> - George Broussard, February 15nd, 2005.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">If you already support 2.0 then 3.0 is easy to support. It's nice that 3.0 is here to develop on, but most developers aren't even using 2.0 at the moment, so the 3.0 stuff is likely here too early.<br /><br />DNF has a full HLSL pipe and we can pretty much support any rendering mode or feature that cards can do.</div> - George Broussard, May <br />12th, 2004.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We've completely gutted and written our own AI system, rendering, particles, skeletal animation and more so it won't look/feel like an Unreal game at all I don't think</div> - George Broussard, January 7nd, 2004.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">No reason to freeze, as we have time to trickle in features until the game ships. But it's complete enough now that we could ship with no excuses and be happy.<br /><br />But just like in Duke 3D, when that engine was done, we still added small features like slopes and went back and retrofit the levels. We will still add things to the engine, as we can, where they make sense, and most importantly - where they won't delay us. We will add things if they are cool and don't impact things, but we will not add features that will cause big delays or mass reworking of exisiting content. </div> - George Broussard, January 17nd, 2004.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Don't worry. When I say tech complete, I mean we could ship if all the content were done.<br />It's fairly easy to add and update shaders and we do so all the time.<br />The graphics guys are ahead and always have time to add in bells and whistles.<br />Many things like per pixel blur, depth of field etc, have zero impact on game content and drop in, in a few days.</div> - George Broussard, March 30th, 2006.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200058" date="Posted: Tue Jun 10, 2008 12:23 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Arklon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Argoon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the ones that don't know, DNF uses a heavily modified version of the UnrealEngine 2. </div>I remember reading somewhere they switched to UE3. Not sure, though.</div><br /><br />I heard the same thing. But I remember I heard it from Journalists like IGN or something - and those guys are usually wrong 90% of the time about the technology in games, so I took it with a grain of salt, like I do everything whenever they mention the technology behind the games, or for that matter, most subjects completely. Like for example, the mix up with id software and other company's to leave the ESA, it seemed like all those so-called "Reasons" these developers left were completely made up by the media.<br /><br />Journalists are bad source for tech info, definitely.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200256" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 3:41 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I saw the footage and it was nice and all, but frankly, I'm very tired of the, "Oh, we could ship and be happy"  (note the dates on those quotes) on the one hand, and the "our masterpiece needs more polish--no wait, let's rip apart the entire game and start over again--let's adopt a 'when it's done' attitude!" on the other... <br /><br />11 years and counting... it's time to put up or shut up, in my opinion.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200258" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 4:18 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i'd say it's annoying too, but 99% of all game companies say that too.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200260" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 4:22 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah but they release their games in 2-4 years max!<br /><br />It's told that after DNF 3drealms will start a ShadowWarrior's sequel that will be released in... let's count... 2020!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200266" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 5:10 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Yeah but they release their games in 2-4 years max!</div><br /><br />Half Life 2 &amp; TF2 are examples of not being released anywhere near when they said they're ready to go.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117161419im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200271" date="Posted: Fri Jun 13, 2008 5:57 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">goliathvt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I saw the footage and it was nice and all, but frankly, I'm very tired of the, "Oh, we could ship and be happy"  (note the dates on those quotes) on the one hand, and the "our masterpiece needs more polish--no wait, let's rip apart the entire game and start over again--let's adopt a 'when it's done' attitude!" on the other... <br /><br />11 years and counting... it's time to put up or shut up, in my opinion.</div><br /><br />In the quote you are talking about he said that could ship and be happy if all the content was done, but it wasn't that is the thing. He was only talking about the status of the engine, their technology always being in a state of constant flux and them being unable to finish the engine has been one of the main reasons for the long development time, that issue has been completely fixed since late 2002/early 2003 when the last restart took place. The new renderer was done in November 2002 and there have been no engine switches or restarts since then. <br /><br />HL2 took like 6 years to make, so if this version of DNF is to take as long then that puts us into 2009. The "When it's done" attitude is far superior to giving out release dates you can't keep. But remember WID is a PR stance to take regarding release dates and it is not really connected to scheduling as such(As a matter of fact they recently hired Brian Hook as Producer, responsible for amongst other things <span style="font-weight: bold">scheduling</span>). You can use WID as a tagline to the press and still have fairly strict internal deadlines and from the Dallas Business Journal interview with Scott Miller it seems that there is a strong internal push to release this game this year or early next year. Polish is certainly far from throwing everything out and restarting the game so there really is no "let's rip apart the entire game and start over" attitude any longer and there hasn't been since 2002.<br /><br />"11 years and counting... it's time to put up or shut up, in my opinion"<br /><br />This is their exact attitude to hype/media, they could have shown the game in 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005 or 2006 and they didn't. They didn't show ANYTHING at all from the current version of the game until 2007 when they showed two 200x150 thumbnails for job ads and a small 1 minute teaser trailer at the VERY VERY end of the year. Since they ditched the 1998-2001 version of the game they have always maintained that they are against hyping games too early and that has been one of the biggest mistakes they have done. They have been pretty adamant about wanting to start the hype train <span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="text-decoration: underline">approximately</span></span></span> 6 months - 1 year from release and their actions have been virtually 100% consistent with that stance.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200308" date="Posted: Sat Jun 14, 2008 10:54 am "><author>aaa111</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Yeah but they release their games in 2-4 years max!<br /><br />It's told that after DNF 3drealms will start a ShadowWarrior's sequel that will be released in... let's count... 2020!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div><br /><br />Shadowarrior in 2020.<br /><br />Huh,that would be DNF release date.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205531" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 1:51 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I didn't see it posted here yet, but 2 new hi res screens were released for DNF<br /><br /><!-- w --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702/http://www.3drealms.com/">http://www.3drealms.com</a><!-- w --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205533" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 2:51 pm "><author>Ivan_the_B</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wow Duke still lives  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><br />It the only fps that I'm waiting for (other than Rage  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" />  ).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205535" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 3:04 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Gfx looks outdated and low quality, but I'm waiting to see the strippers, heck I'm waiting to see the strippers in GTA4[PC] also. High-def-pussy-gaming lol.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205537" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 5:13 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">nice!  Doesn't look dated to me, looks great!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />but let's not forget id won't do a game that takes more then ~2-3 years after Doom 3.   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205541" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 6:14 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Please keep repeating that every chance you get Friar.  It's relevant. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br />Over a decade of development resulting in screenshots of an unfinished game versus developing, releasing, patching and partnering with other companies on at least 6 AAA titles in the same amount of time....  Yah.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205544" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 6:47 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">goliathvt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Over a decade of development resulting in screenshots of an unfinished game versus developing, releasing, patching and partnering with other companies on at least 6 AAA titles in the same amount of time....  Yah.</div><br /><br />I'm not making excuses for anyone, but just like id, 3d is using their own $$ to do this.  Id said ~2 years per game after D3.  They're @ year 4 (going on 5) now.  That's 2x longer then expected.  id did the same thing 3d did with their new game: scrapped all the old stuff &amp; started new.<br /><br />but I'm more excited to see a new duke nukem then anything id has announced.  At lease since Doom 3 (that counds q4, et:qw, d4, rage &amp; quake live)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205558" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 11:54 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Friar, yeah. But they scrapped it all to take it into a new direction. Not because they took too long to produce it that it got outdated.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205562" date="Posted: Wed Oct 01, 2008 1:46 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how do we know that?  Nobody who can say anything knows what id's old project actuatly was.  The few people I know can't say.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205570" date="Posted: Wed Oct 01, 2008 6:53 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I know some people who can say what the project was, and if id "Little Bitches" Software cared about their fan base, they would quit pandering to the sick desires of John "Choke "em Out" Carmack and get on this damned forum and give us a bloody bit of insight.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205576" date="Posted: Wed Oct 01, 2008 12:25 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205583" date="Posted: Wed Oct 01, 2008 2:32 pm "><author>lowdragon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Indeed <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />We can still just guess  - i too would like to have more info/images of the prototypes (basically) they do have some kind of coolness factor just like "what if or could had been". I had the pleasure to watch four or five prototypes (videos) of released titles but imho the real game was allways better. The "mother brain" things (Octobrain) are looking quit good -&gt; greasy = win. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205626" date="Posted: Thu Oct 02, 2008 4:41 am "><author>Gabrobot</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">how do we know that?</div><br /><br />Because they said so? I mean we could spin crazy conspiracy theories, but their description of their next game right after Doom 3 came out was that it'd be another dark horror corridor shooter which is exactly in line with the game "Darkness" that they later talked about after Rage was announced. I'd say it's pretty obvious they had a major shift in design focus. The only other option is a big conspiracy where they knew they'd be restarting their project so they intentionally mis-described it way back in 2004/5. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205628" date="Posted: Thu Oct 02, 2008 5:03 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">not trying to get in to conspiracy theory's (if you want one: hollendstead claims that PC hardware industry promotes piracy by putting out the best hardware &amp; making people want new games that use it.  id makes those games.  If they know they'll get pirated &amp; loose $$ why not make an old tech game??? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /> )<br /><br />I'm just saying that there's no reason to believe that 3d realms didn't do what they did for a VERY good reason.  We assume id did.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205635" date="Posted: Thu Oct 02, 2008 12:50 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">id has also produced more than some video footage and low-res screenshots in the last decade.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />I guess I'm just skeptical any time I see anything about DNF because it's just been far too long and had far too many revisions to hold my interest.  That, and I'm far less interested in getting my hands on polygonal boobs these days when the real things are available to me now and are far more fun. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205648" date="Posted: Fri Oct 03, 2008 12:34 am "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm looking forward to the new DNF game no matter how long they take to make it. I'll play many other games in the meantime just like 3DRealms does themselves as well. When it is finally done, I'll be at the store with cash in hand to pick up my copy and will enjoy it I'm sure no doubt. They're making it fun, they're making it fully interactive and they're making it right. They should take all the time they want to make a game that is great and not half assed.<br /><br />You think you're automatically gonna have money to pay a stripper at the club? Hellz no.....you're gonna have to earn it if you want the show or some information! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205651" date="Posted: Fri Oct 03, 2008 2:30 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">goliathvt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">id has also produced more than some video footage and low-res screenshots in the last decade.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div><br /><br />Only 2 games: quake 3 &amp; doom 3.  I think 3d realms has dev'ed ~the same (not counting produced, just dev'ed).<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">That, and I'm far less interested in getting my hands on polygonal boobs these days when the real things are available to me now and are far more fun. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div><br /><br />That's one of the last things I think of when I think of duke.  I think of shrink ray, big guns, attitude, pig cops.....  Boobies is WAY down the list!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205652" date="Posted: Fri Oct 03, 2008 4:50 am "><author>Destroyer_of_Senses</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">and a shit load of awesome ass explosions.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205655" date="Posted: Fri Oct 03, 2008 8:49 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">goliathvt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">id has also produced more than some video footage and low-res screenshots in the last decade.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div><br /><br />Only 2 games: quake 3 &amp; doom 3.  I think 3d realms has dev'ed ~the same (not counting produced, just dev'ed).</div><br /><br />In the last decade id software came up this row of titles:<br />Q3A, Q3TA, D3 - first hand development<br />RTCW, D3ROE, SoF, Prey, Q4, ETQW, Array of Q3 powered games, Array of Q2 powered games - provider of technology / franchise / production assistance <br /><br />3d realms had their share of games out, but DNF still is a disaster. They're aiming for the ultimate game, but technology will outrun them each time they come closer, so they switch engines and start over again.<br /><br />Also I didn't know we have to have a discussion on who puts out more games in a decade - none of these points de- or increases the value of either company. There is nothing to defend about 3drealms. If they come up with a cool game I'll sing their praises, if not I'll be disappointed - just as with any other product.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205656" date="Posted: Fri Oct 03, 2008 1:49 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I didn't start that, he did.   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117160702im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />I was just saying that I am (and I'm sure most gamers out there) are much more excited to see a screenshot of DN4E vs anything from id.  Id went from a company that had a lot of excitement &amp; vision in their early days to a company that goes by sales since Q3A.  Yeah, sales make $$ but there's already enough companies that put out boring stuff to make $$.  many of them do it really really well, but, honestly, those games are a dime a dozen.  I'd rather see Doom 4 continue after Doom 2 with the same graphics &amp; gameplay vs following Doom 3 with the same boring scripted sequences &amp; predictable story elements/situations as every other game out there.  Duke hopefully doesn't do any of that &amp; tries new things.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205660" date="Posted: Fri Oct 03, 2008 4:33 pm "><author>=NoMercy=</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I didn't start that, he did.   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081117155826im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />I was just saying that I am (and I'm sure most gamers out there) are much more excited to see a screenshot of DN4E vs anything from id.  Id went from a company that had a lot of excitement &amp; vision in their early days to a company that goes by sales since Q3A.  Yeah, sales make $$ but there's already enough companies that put out boring stuff to make $$.  many of them do it really really well, but, honestly, those games are a dime a dozen.  I'd rather see Doom 4 continue after Doom 2 with the same graphics &amp; gameplay vs following Doom 3 with the same boring scripted sequences &amp; predictable story elements/situations as every other game out there.  Duke hopefully doesn't do any of that &amp; tries new things.</div><br /><br />The only thing I would be excited to see from ID atm would be Doom 4 and a new Quake. Rage doesn't seem to interest me much, but I'll probably get it. <br /><br />I am excited for DNF, just finished Duke Nukem 3D on the 360, what a great game.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
