<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="21637"><title>Crysis expansion, "Crysis Warhead" announced</title><posts><post id="p200471" date="Posted: Tue Jun 17, 2008 9:14 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"><span style="font-weight: bold">EA AND CRYTEK ANNOUNCE CRYSIS WARHEAD</span><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715im_/http://www.crytek.com/fileadmin/user_upload/news/2008/news_20080605.gif" alt="Image" /><br />Jun 05, 2008<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold">EA AND CRYTEK ANNOUNCE DEVELOPMENT OF CRYSIS WARHEAD<br /><br />The Next Installment of One of the Highest Rated Games of 2007 Blasts its way onto PCs this Fall</span><br /><br />Maximum freedom, maximum explosions and maximum Psycho!  Electronic Arts Inc. (NASDAQ: ERTS) and award-winning independent studio Crytek today announced Crysis Warhead® – the parallel story to Crysis, one of the most critically-acclaimed first person shooters and PC games of 2007.  Shipping exclusively for the PC this fall, Crysis Warhead is the first title to be developed at Crytek´s Budapest studio, and is built on a new, enhanced and optimized version of Crytek’s CryENGINE® 2 technology.<br /><br /><br /><br />“We were very pleased with the reception of Crysis from both gamers and media after our launch last year,” said Cevat Yerli, CEO and President of Crytek.  “That being said, one of the key principles of our studio is to always raise the bar.  With Warhead, we are focusing on refining our storytelling and game performance, while also delivering more of the visually stunning graphics and immersive, free-roaming gameplay everyone loved in Crysis.”<br /><br /><br /><br />“The best result of a partnership that we can ask for in the EA Partners program is when a world class independent studio like Crytek chooses to continue to work with us,” said David DeMartini, Vice President and Global General Manager, EA Partners.  “Crysis was an amazing game and is going to be a blockbuster franchise.  We could not be more excited to be working with Crytek to launch another hit with Crysis Warhead this year.”<br /><br /><br /><br />In Crysis Warhead, players will don the Nanosuit of Sergeant Sykes, also known as ‘Psycho’, one of the most memorable characters from Crysis.  More brash and aggressive than his Delta Force squadmate Nomad, players will experience Psycho’s parallel story during the events of the original game, finding that life on the other side of the island is even more intense and explosive than they ever could have imagined.  Luckily, Psycho’s Nanosuit is just as capable and he’s equipped with an even bigger arsenal of fully customizable weapons and new vehicles, giving players access to the tools they need to dominate any situation.  Aside from this new, exciting single player campaign, Crysis Warhead will also feature new multiplayer content.  Stay tuned for more details this summer.<br /><br /><br /><br />Crysis Warhead has not yet been rated by the ESRB or PEGI.  For more information about the game, please visit <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715/http://www.crysisthegame.com/">http://www.crysisthegame.com</a><!-- m -->.</div><br />Source: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715/http://www.crytek.com/news/news/?tx_ttnews">http://www.crytek.com/news/news/?tx_ttnews</a><!-- m -->[tt_news]=116&amp;tx_ttnews[backPid]=1&amp;cHash=7733199cd1<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715im_/http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/86/Crysis_Warhead.jpg/424px-Crysis_Warhead.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />embiggen: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715/http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/86/Crysis_Warhead.jpg">http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/e ... arhead.jpg</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200503" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 4:02 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Actually Crysis Warhead is a standalone game of its own.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200518" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 9:12 pm "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah, it's stand-alone game, not an expansion pack.<br /><br />The guys over at <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715/http://www.pcgamerpodcast.com/" class="postlink">PCGamerPodcast</a> have said that one of their next PC Gamer magazine issues are going to have the debut screenshots. And from what they said on the podcast, the game is being changed in certain ways to run better on crappier PCs. They even said it looks different, but they didn't talk much about it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200528" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 1:06 am "><author>Arklon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wait. Games for Windows Live? This is bad.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200529" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 1:08 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Arklon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Wait. Games for Windows Live? This is bad.</div><br /><br />I agree.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200549" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:04 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Eurogamer said it will be a "standalone expansion": <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715/http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062">http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062</a><!-- m --><br /><br />So i will remove the "pack" from the thread title.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200550" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:41 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Burrito wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Eurogamer said it will be a "standalone expansion": <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715/http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062">http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062</a><!-- m --><br /><br />So i will remove the "pack" from the thread title.</div><br /><br />doesn't that mean "sequel" if it's standalone?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200551" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:43 pm "><author>=NoMercy=</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well I guess you can kind of think of it as Episode 1 and 2 for HL2.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200552" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:51 pm "><author>ViPr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">if you ask me, this is a big ripoff. in my opinion it's essentially just a patch of crysis which they decided to charge for instead of releasing it free like they should have, and they will probably not even charge the price of an expansion pack but the price of a full game, which makes it even worse. <br /><br />the story of crysis is dumb because first of all we have nothing against koreans and we already knew the whole story before the game was even released and now we are going to know it again so it's going to be even more boring. <br /><br />plus if the character is memorable then obviously wouldn't it be more interesting to be watching him instead of being him. <br /><br />in conclusion. Crysis Warhead consists of juinormus feil.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200555" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 7:21 pm "><author>TRSGM</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Dude. Dunn looks like a douche. Assuming that's him on the cover.<br /><br /><br />Art is nice and crisp, though. Suit looks... real.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200561" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 9:10 pm "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">ViPr wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">first of all we have nothing against koreans</div><br /><br />I'm not going to hijack the thread, but I'm curious if you're American. If you need to know anything about our relationship with Korea, go look it up on the internet or, better yet, play Splinter Cell Chaos Theory. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /> (Very fun game... Do NOT play Double Agent though, that game sucks ass.)<br /><br />But I do think this is a ripoff. It's a ripoff of what Valve did with Half-Life 1 and their expansion packs. There's one where you play as a soldier (I always forget the name of that one) and then Blue Shift, the one where you play as Barney the security guard. It was pretty fun, but I enjoyed HL1 more than I enjoyed Crysis. (Not that I didn't enjoy Crysis, I thought Crysis was very fun.)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200581" date="Posted: Fri Jun 20, 2008 1:10 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">At first, this is no sequel because a sequel is about a story that follows events that happened sometime earlier. This would be called a parallel.<br /><br />I don't know how this can be a ripoff - i'm currently playing Crysis and its a very fun game. I want more, thats for sure. If you don't want it, don't buy it. They also don't waste time on this as they outsourced it to another team.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200629" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 11:41 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"<br />So even if i recognize that Crysis is a top game, just for the open environment, and assets quality, about storyline it's a shame...<br />I'm tired about the "i'm a über american soldier against bad guyz of the world" ala hollywood.<br /><br />About WarFare, it's going to be "Games for windows" because of the LIVE option, as ms want to enable PCvs360 multiplayer games.<br />So, i suppose the PS3 and 360 versions of the Crysis game will be based on this "new, enhanced and optimized version of Crytek’s CryENGINE® 2 technology" (original Crysis is far than optimized), and will have the 2 stories in the game.<br /><br />What do you think about it?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200632" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 1:35 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"</div><br /><br />I thought the story is supposed to span over three installments in total.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200903" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 12:01 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">CRYSIS [standalone] [story begins] [part 1 of the trilogy]<br />+--Warhead [addon] [episodic] [expansion] [standalone]<br />CRYSIS 2 [standalone] [story continues] [part 2 of the trilogy]<br />+--?<br />CRYSIS 3 [standalone] [story ends] [part 3 of the trilogy]<br />+--?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200935" date="Posted: Sun Jun 29, 2008 5:57 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"</div><br /><br />I thought the story is supposed to span over three installments in total.</div><br /><br />It is, but still, the ending in the first game was a sudden shock of ass-y suckness. Don't get me wrong, the game was good and I've played it over and over again. It's just that the ending really wasn't all that great. (And the MP sucks in my opinion. But I'm picky when it comes to MP; I still prefer Q3 above all.)<br /><br />Cevat Yerli, CEO of Crytek, gives a pretty interesting interview at IGN. <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715/http://pc.ign.com/articles/884/884757p1.html">http://pc.ign.com/articles/884/884757p1.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Just from seeing the way Cevat speaks about developing games on the PC, you can tell that this guy is not only a hardcore PC Gamer, but a hardcore PC Developer. He loves this platform, and wants nothing but the best for it. It's unfortunate he's going through what he is with his company - he sincerely wants to develop PC Exclusive titles, but he just doesn't see the profit in it. Personally, I wouldn't mind if they developed games for consoles as well as the PC - just as long as they continue to give PC the full deserved support. But it does suck that developers <span style="font-style: italic">have</span> to develop for multiple platforms in order to make a serious profit - or just develop for the consoles and not the PC at all. That shouldn't have to be the way of game development with the PC; and it's obvious Cevat feels strongly about this. He's my hero.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203630" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 5:22 pm "><author>aardwolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"<br />So even if i recognize that Crysis is a top game, just for the open environment, and assets quality, about storyline it's a shame...<br />I'm tired about the "i'm a über american soldier against bad guyz of the world" ala hollywood.<br /><br />About WarFare, it's going to be "Games for windows" because of the LIVE option, as ms want to enable PCvs360 multiplayer games.<br />So, i suppose the PS3 and 360 versions of the Crysis game will be based on this "new, enhanced and optimized version of Crytek’s CryENGINE® 2 technology" (original Crysis is far than optimized), and will have the 2 stories in the game.<br /><br />What do you think about it?</div><br /><br />Thats what sells in the us market, man.  It's just crytek catering to their target audience.  Do you think they would be able to sell their game if you played some rogue north korean soldier who sympathizes with dear leader il?  it'd be the same as if activision had you playing as an axis soldier in cod.  The projected sales would drop to - 10.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203633" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 5:57 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">aardwolf wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Thats what sells in the us market, man.  It's just crytek catering to their target audience.  Do you think they would be able to sell their game if you played some rogue north korean soldier who sympathizes with dear leader il?  it'd be the same as if activision had you playing as an axis soldier in cod.  The projected sales would drop to - 10.</div><br /><br />Yes, it sells - however not everyone feels like being the ultimate US soldier 24/7, especially not after all the international warmth radiated by Rumsfeld, Chaney, Bush or of course McCain and his lovely "fawning Germans" remark two weeks ago.<br /><br />There still is an alternative - like playing a highly decadent avatar as Duke Nukem (who sort of resembles an Austrian California Governor) who cut's the pseudo-moral and drills directly into the heart of the well hidden cravings of a player. At least you don't get caught in the public with your pants off while stuffing a stripper with greenbacks. A mouseclick can be so satisfying if it doesn't roll out a national flag every time you perform it.<br /><br />Disclosure: If I'd develop a computer game I'd make sure it'd become the most pathetic "good hero" game ever since I want my time and development budget to get reimbursed properly. Logic would drive me anytime over riding on a false moral high horse, therefore I'd insert the hypocritical high morals into a game and give consumers an excuse to run around as a walking gun blasting away. After all it boils down to playing is fun and fun is more fun than the fun of pretending to have fun by admitting not to have fun while having fun. This was a funny sentence you'll only be able the squeeze out from a foreign language speaker who tries to be funny.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203645" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:37 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">aardwolf wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">  it'd be the same as if activision had you playing as an axis soldier in cod.  The projected sales would drop to - 10.</div><br /><br />You did play Axis in COH; Opposing fronts.. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152715im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200471" date="Posted: Tue Jun 17, 2008 9:14 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"><span style="font-weight: bold">EA AND CRYTEK ANNOUNCE CRYSIS WARHEAD</span><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836im_/http://www.crytek.com/fileadmin/user_upload/news/2008/news_20080605.gif" alt="Image" /><br />Jun 05, 2008<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold">EA AND CRYTEK ANNOUNCE DEVELOPMENT OF CRYSIS WARHEAD<br /><br />The Next Installment of One of the Highest Rated Games of 2007 Blasts its way onto PCs this Fall</span><br /><br />Maximum freedom, maximum explosions and maximum Psycho!  Electronic Arts Inc. (NASDAQ: ERTS) and award-winning independent studio Crytek today announced Crysis Warhead® – the parallel story to Crysis, one of the most critically-acclaimed first person shooters and PC games of 2007.  Shipping exclusively for the PC this fall, Crysis Warhead is the first title to be developed at Crytek´s Budapest studio, and is built on a new, enhanced and optimized version of Crytek’s CryENGINE® 2 technology.<br /><br /><br /><br />“We were very pleased with the reception of Crysis from both gamers and media after our launch last year,” said Cevat Yerli, CEO and President of Crytek.  “That being said, one of the key principles of our studio is to always raise the bar.  With Warhead, we are focusing on refining our storytelling and game performance, while also delivering more of the visually stunning graphics and immersive, free-roaming gameplay everyone loved in Crysis.”<br /><br /><br /><br />“The best result of a partnership that we can ask for in the EA Partners program is when a world class independent studio like Crytek chooses to continue to work with us,” said David DeMartini, Vice President and Global General Manager, EA Partners.  “Crysis was an amazing game and is going to be a blockbuster franchise.  We could not be more excited to be working with Crytek to launch another hit with Crysis Warhead this year.”<br /><br /><br /><br />In Crysis Warhead, players will don the Nanosuit of Sergeant Sykes, also known as ‘Psycho’, one of the most memorable characters from Crysis.  More brash and aggressive than his Delta Force squadmate Nomad, players will experience Psycho’s parallel story during the events of the original game, finding that life on the other side of the island is even more intense and explosive than they ever could have imagined.  Luckily, Psycho’s Nanosuit is just as capable and he’s equipped with an even bigger arsenal of fully customizable weapons and new vehicles, giving players access to the tools they need to dominate any situation.  Aside from this new, exciting single player campaign, Crysis Warhead will also feature new multiplayer content.  Stay tuned for more details this summer.<br /><br /><br /><br />Crysis Warhead has not yet been rated by the ESRB or PEGI.  For more information about the game, please visit <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836/http://www.crysisthegame.com/">http://www.crysisthegame.com</a><!-- m -->.</div><br />Source: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836/http://www.crytek.com/news/news/?tx_ttnews">http://www.crytek.com/news/news/?tx_ttnews</a><!-- m -->[tt_news]=116&amp;tx_ttnews[backPid]=1&amp;cHash=7733199cd1<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836im_/http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/8/86/Crysis_Warhead.jpg/424px-Crysis_Warhead.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />embiggen: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836/http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/86/Crysis_Warhead.jpg">http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/e ... arhead.jpg</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p200503" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 4:02 pm "><author>Kristian Joensen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Actually Crysis Warhead is a standalone game of its own.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200518" date="Posted: Wed Jun 18, 2008 9:12 pm "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah, it's stand-alone game, not an expansion pack.<br /><br />The guys over at <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836/http://www.pcgamerpodcast.com/" class="postlink">PCGamerPodcast</a> have said that one of their next PC Gamer magazine issues are going to have the debut screenshots. And from what they said on the podcast, the game is being changed in certain ways to run better on crappier PCs. They even said it looks different, but they didn't talk much about it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200528" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 1:06 am "><author>Arklon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Wait. Games for Windows Live? This is bad.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200529" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 1:08 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Arklon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Wait. Games for Windows Live? This is bad.</div><br /><br />I agree.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200549" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:04 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Eurogamer said it will be a "standalone expansion": <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836/http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062">http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062</a><!-- m --><br /><br />So i will remove the "pack" from the thread title.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200550" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:41 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Burrito wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Eurogamer said it will be a "standalone expansion": <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836/http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062">http://www.eurogamer.net/article.php?article_id=146062</a><!-- m --><br /><br />So i will remove the "pack" from the thread title.</div><br /><br />doesn't that mean "sequel" if it's standalone?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200551" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:43 pm "><author>=NoMercy=</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well I guess you can kind of think of it as Episode 1 and 2 for HL2.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200552" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 3:51 pm "><author>ViPr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">if you ask me, this is a big ripoff. in my opinion it's essentially just a patch of crysis which they decided to charge for instead of releasing it free like they should have, and they will probably not even charge the price of an expansion pack but the price of a full game, which makes it even worse. <br /><br />the story of crysis is dumb because first of all we have nothing against koreans and we already knew the whole story before the game was even released and now we are going to know it again so it's going to be even more boring. <br /><br />plus if the character is memorable then obviously wouldn't it be more interesting to be watching him instead of being him. <br /><br />in conclusion. Crysis Warhead consists of juinormus feil.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200555" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 7:21 pm "><author>TRSGM</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Dude. Dunn looks like a douche. Assuming that's him on the cover.<br /><br /><br />Art is nice and crisp, though. Suit looks... real.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200561" date="Posted: Thu Jun 19, 2008 9:10 pm "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">ViPr wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">first of all we have nothing against koreans</div><br /><br />I'm not going to hijack the thread, but I'm curious if you're American. If you need to know anything about our relationship with Korea, go look it up on the internet or, better yet, play Splinter Cell Chaos Theory. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /> (Very fun game... Do NOT play Double Agent though, that game sucks ass.)<br /><br />But I do think this is a ripoff. It's a ripoff of what Valve did with Half-Life 1 and their expansion packs. There's one where you play as a soldier (I always forget the name of that one) and then Blue Shift, the one where you play as Barney the security guard. It was pretty fun, but I enjoyed HL1 more than I enjoyed Crysis. (Not that I didn't enjoy Crysis, I thought Crysis was very fun.)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200581" date="Posted: Fri Jun 20, 2008 1:10 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">At first, this is no sequel because a sequel is about a story that follows events that happened sometime earlier. This would be called a parallel.<br /><br />I don't know how this can be a ripoff - i'm currently playing Crysis and its a very fun game. I want more, thats for sure. If you don't want it, don't buy it. They also don't waste time on this as they outsourced it to another team.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200629" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 11:41 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"<br />So even if i recognize that Crysis is a top game, just for the open environment, and assets quality, about storyline it's a shame...<br />I'm tired about the "i'm a über american soldier against bad guyz of the world" ala hollywood.<br /><br />About WarFare, it's going to be "Games for windows" because of the LIVE option, as ms want to enable PCvs360 multiplayer games.<br />So, i suppose the PS3 and 360 versions of the Crysis game will be based on this "new, enhanced and optimized version of Crytek’s CryENGINE® 2 technology" (original Crysis is far than optimized), and will have the 2 stories in the game.<br /><br />What do you think about it?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200632" date="Posted: Sat Jun 21, 2008 1:35 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"</div><br /><br />I thought the story is supposed to span over three installments in total.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200903" date="Posted: Sat Jun 28, 2008 12:01 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">CRYSIS [standalone] [story begins] [part 1 of the trilogy]<br />+--Warhead [addon] [episodic] [expansion] [standalone]<br />CRYSIS 2 [standalone] [story continues] [part 2 of the trilogy]<br />+--?<br />CRYSIS 3 [standalone] [story ends] [part 3 of the trilogy]<br />+--?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p200935" date="Posted: Sun Jun 29, 2008 5:57 am "><author>Dinky</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"</div><br /><br />I thought the story is supposed to span over three installments in total.</div><br /><br />It is, but still, the ending in the first game was a sudden shock of ass-y suckness. Don't get me wrong, the game was good and I've played it over and over again. It's just that the ending really wasn't all that great. (And the MP sucks in my opinion. But I'm picky when it comes to MP; I still prefer Q3 above all.)<br /><br />Cevat Yerli, CEO of Crytek, gives a pretty interesting interview at IGN. <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836/http://pc.ign.com/articles/884/884757p1.html">http://pc.ign.com/articles/884/884757p1.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Just from seeing the way Cevat speaks about developing games on the PC, you can tell that this guy is not only a hardcore PC Gamer, but a hardcore PC Developer. He loves this platform, and wants nothing but the best for it. It's unfortunate he's going through what he is with his company - he sincerely wants to develop PC Exclusive titles, but he just doesn't see the profit in it. Personally, I wouldn't mind if they developed games for consoles as well as the PC - just as long as they continue to give PC the full deserved support. But it does suck that developers <span style="font-style: italic">have</span> to develop for multiple platforms in order to make a serious profit - or just develop for the consoles and not the PC at all. That shouldn't have to be the way of game development with the PC; and it's obvious Cevat feels strongly about this. He's my hero.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203630" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 5:22 pm "><author>aardwolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">6th Venom wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I finished it (Crysis), and i had a strange feel that the story was really cutted... i mean, the end don't look like a "game ending", i really was like: "what?!? it's over? ...impossible!"<br />So even if i recognize that Crysis is a top game, just for the open environment, and assets quality, about storyline it's a shame...<br />I'm tired about the "i'm a über american soldier against bad guyz of the world" ala hollywood.<br /><br />About WarFare, it's going to be "Games for windows" because of the LIVE option, as ms want to enable PCvs360 multiplayer games.<br />So, i suppose the PS3 and 360 versions of the Crysis game will be based on this "new, enhanced and optimized version of Crytek’s CryENGINE® 2 technology" (original Crysis is far than optimized), and will have the 2 stories in the game.<br /><br />What do you think about it?</div><br /><br />Thats what sells in the us market, man.  It's just crytek catering to their target audience.  Do you think they would be able to sell their game if you played some rogue north korean soldier who sympathizes with dear leader il?  it'd be the same as if activision had you playing as an axis soldier in cod.  The projected sales would drop to - 10.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203633" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 5:57 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">aardwolf wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Thats what sells in the us market, man.  It's just crytek catering to their target audience.  Do you think they would be able to sell their game if you played some rogue north korean soldier who sympathizes with dear leader il?  it'd be the same as if activision had you playing as an axis soldier in cod.  The projected sales would drop to - 10.</div><br /><br />Yes, it sells - however not everyone feels like being the ultimate US soldier 24/7, especially not after all the international warmth radiated by Rumsfeld, Chaney, Bush or of course McCain and his lovely "fawning Germans" remark two weeks ago.<br /><br />There still is an alternative - like playing a highly decadent avatar as Duke Nukem (who sort of resembles an Austrian California Governor) who cut's the pseudo-moral and drills directly into the heart of the well hidden cravings of a player. At least you don't get caught in the public with your pants off while stuffing a stripper with greenbacks. A mouseclick can be so satisfying if it doesn't roll out a national flag every time you perform it.<br /><br />Disclosure: If I'd develop a computer game I'd make sure it'd become the most pathetic "good hero" game ever since I want my time and development budget to get reimbursed properly. Logic would drive me anytime over riding on a false moral high horse, therefore I'd insert the hypocritical high morals into a game and give consumers an excuse to run around as a walking gun blasting away. After all it boils down to playing is fun and fun is more fun than the fun of pretending to have fun by admitting not to have fun while having fun. This was a funny sentence you'll only be able the squeeze out from a foreign language speaker who tries to be funny.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203645" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:37 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">aardwolf wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">  it'd be the same as if activision had you playing as an axis soldier in cod.  The projected sales would drop to - 10.</div><br /><br />You did play Axis in COH; Opposing fronts.. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081119152836im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
