<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="21831"><title>multiple textures on single imported model?</title><posts><post id="p203106" date="Posted: Mon Aug 04, 2008 4:22 pm "><author>Gripper666</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hi, ive finally worked out how to import a model into doom3 that has a single texture but my problem is how can i import a single model with multiple textures? everytime i try it only shows up with a single texture in the editor &amp; game, is there anything special i should be doing or does it work on the same principle as the single texture method?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203129" date="Posted: Mon Aug 04, 2008 11:53 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's possible to use multiple material shaders on a single model. The models that come with the game prove as much.<br /><br />However, what changes you need to make in order to be successful is dependant on your workflow. What model format are you working with, LWO, ASE, MD5? What's your toolset? What import/export utilites are you using?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203131" date="Posted: Tue Aug 05, 2008 12:12 am "><author>Gripper666</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">well i downloaded some free models that are .3ds format from a free website &amp; i load them into 3ds max 9 &amp; after adding textures &amp; adding a multires &amp; uv map i export them to an .ase file, then i open the exported model in notepad &amp; make afew changes to the texture paths so the doom editor can find them.<br />this method works fine if i use just 1 texture but if i add more they never show up, im pretty new to using 3d modelling programs so im kinda lost at the moment.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203136" date="Posted: Tue Aug 05, 2008 1:25 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">For ASE objects you must keep 1 texture by object (no multimaterials) BUT you can export severals objects into only one model/ASE with the "export selected' command.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203142" date="Posted: Tue Aug 05, 2008 7:46 am "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Erm, no its not impossible... Its pretty damn easy?<br /><br />Just set up different surfaces is your model file that point to different textures...? I've been doing it for years. I think its something like 16 max surfaces in a model file.<br /><br />EDIT: Wow, bit early in the morning for me... I could of sworn everybody said it was impossible then lol.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203550" date="Posted: Tue Aug 12, 2008 12:44 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">when u adjust the path name in ur .ASE does the bitmap path have to be "Purgatory\Purgatory\Doom\base\textures\custom\your_file.tga ?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203554" date="Posted: Tue Aug 12, 2008 2:47 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="codetitle">
    <b>Code:</b>
  </div>
  <div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\yourMaterialName"</div>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203558" date="Posted: Tue Aug 12, 2008 3:57 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok just base\mymaterialname thanks brian</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203615" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 7:24 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">by material do u mean my texture or .mtr file and wouldnt the paths be *BITMAP "\\base\materials\mymaterialname?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203617" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 9:19 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">yourMaterialName<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage   textures/anyFolder/whatever_ed.tga<br />   diffusemap   textures/anyFolder/whatever_d.tga<br />}<br /></div><br /><br />will use<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />but if you NAME your material<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">materials\yourMaterialName<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage   textures/anyFolder/whatever_ed.tga<br />   diffusemap   textures/anyFolder/whatever_d.tga<br />}<br /></div><br /><br />then the ASE Bitmap would be<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\materials\yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />because<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">\\base\<br /></div><br /><br />is the only part that is an actual PATH and<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">materials\yourMaterialName<br /></div><br /><br />is just a NAME.<br /><br />HOWEVER, by calling your material <br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">materials\yourMaterialName<br /></div><br /><br />You will find yourMaterialName in a subfolder called MATERIALS in the editor, as the folder will be automatically created IN THE EDITOR</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203618" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 9:34 am "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thats not correct...?<br /><br />It should point to the surface used by your model, NOT the material. The material is just a file to store all other materials in.<br /><br />So, if your "material" looks like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">models/weapons/pie/pie_hat<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage   models/weapons/pie/pie_hat_d.tga<br />   diffusemap   models/weapons/pie/pie_hat_d.tga<br />}</div><br /><br />Then of course your actual ".md5mesh" file should read like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\models\weapons\pie\pie_hat"</div><br /><br />See why this is different? Its because its linking to the SURFACE, not the material file.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203640" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 10:23 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Dude, I have no idea what you're talking about, but we're talking about ASE models, not MD5MESH models, and I have over 1500 working examples within my released mods to prove my info is proper and functional.<br /><br />For an MD5MESh, all that is required is<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">shader "yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />So, please don't confuse the issue unless you have something accurate to post.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203641" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 10:36 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">its true, his models work but IM having an issue with textures, in any case thanks <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203659" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 11:06 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I have over 1500 working examples within my released mods to prove my info is proper and functional.</div><br />***FREE PUB HERE***<br /><br />Really?!? And what are those released mods?<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203662" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:45 pm "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Dude, I have no idea what you're talking about, but we're talking about ASE models, not MD5MESH models, and I have over 1500 working examples within my released mods to prove my info is proper and functional.<br /><br />For an MD5MESh, all that is required is<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">shader "yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />So, please don't confuse the issue unless you have something accurate to post.</div><br /><br />As do I, and have been working with .ase models professionally for years now.<br /><br />What you posted, is wrong. There are no two ways about it. Whatever mod you have these thousands (lol) of models for, must really hate you, because you dont know the basics. You are linking the shader in the .ase file to the MATERIAL, which is wrong. You should be point to a specific TEXTURE, which the material itself will handle.<br /><br />Take another look at your post. You tell him this:<br /><br />*BITMAP "\\base\materials\yourMaterialName"<br /><br />Which is clearly WRONG for what should be in the .ase file. Thats telling him to point to his .mtr file and NOT to his surface.<br /><br />So please, dont try and school me on the basics kid, I've been working far too long with them. Re-read our post, and see where you made the mistake.<br /><br />EDIT: Remember, hes trying to get this working ingame, with no textures showing up. No textures show up because the .ase file is pointing to a material, not a surface. If we were to take this ingame, its the wrong way to go about things because it will never render correctly and will fill the console with errors.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203664" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:58 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Seriously, dude, show us your portfolio or shut up.<br /><br />As for mine, download them from my site and tell me I am wrong and my stuff doesn't work. I never said to point to the WHATEVER.MTR, I said to point to the name of his MATERIAL. What you said was <br /><br />"The material is just a file to store all other materials in."<br /><br />What is that supposed to mean? Then you went on the mention MD5MESH and that had nothing to do with what was being discussed. Kid.<br /><br />@ 6th Venom: By example, Bubba Lego-Tep has over 1470 ASE models, so add the contents of the other mods to it, and it's actually quite a bit more than 1500, and they all work as I described with no errors in consoles.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203665" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:59 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">gavavva wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">EDIT: Remember, hes trying to get this working ingame, with no textures showing up. No textures show up because the .ase file is pointing to a material, not a surface. If we were to take this ingame, its the wrong way to go about things because it will never render correctly and will fill the console with errors.</div><br />In terms of doom3 you are totally, and absolutely, 100% <span style="font-weight: bold">WRONG</span>. And don't diss BrainTrepaning because he's proven himself over and over to the community, giving us countless of tutorials and mods, what he posted is correct.<br /><br />There are no 'surfaces' in Doom3, only material decls, popularly named 'materials' that define which texture files to use. I suggest you head on over to <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252/http://www.iddevnet.com/">http://www.iddevnet.com</a><!-- m --> and educate yourself, before shaming yourself further with your arrogant tone. I don't mind if people make mistakes, we make them to learn from them, but your arrogance is staggering considering the fact that you are plain wrong.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203666" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 1:20 pm "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The point I'm trying to make is you are telling him that BITMAP in his .ase file needs to point to a .mtr file. Go back and re-read the post. That should point to an actual surface CONTAINED inside the .mtr file, otherwise it wont know what surface to look for.<br /><br />I've uploaded an example model, below. Notice that it points to the surface:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "//base/models/proj/nail.tga"</div><br /><br />This means that, regardless of the name of the material file (which can be called anything), it will search inside all available material .mtr files for this surface. Which would look like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">base/models/proj/nail<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage       base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br /><br />   bumpMap      base/models/proj/nail_local.tga<br />   diffuseMap      base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br />   specularMap      base/models/proj/nail_s.tga<br />}</div><br /><br />Download the model, and tell me I'm wrong? Because if I am wrong, then I honestly dont see how its worked in the few retail games I've shipped.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203667" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 1:26 pm "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm not the type of guy who cant admit when hes wrong, but to be quite honest it appears just because this guy posted a few tutorials you take his word as gods, but wont listen to the guy wit ha few posts. Fair enough. But lose the attitude gents, its not called for, not here. The end result from all of us is the same, and that is to help this chap, yeah?<br /><br />So whatever way we get there, and whoever is wrong, doesnt matter. If I am wrong, then thats perfectly fine, I'm wrong. I'm not a wimp, and I can take a beating on an online forum <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />But come on gents, dont turn this into a slanging match just because I'm not somebody else, eh? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203668" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 1:41 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">gavavva wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">The point I'm trying to make is you are telling him that BITMAP in his .ase file needs to point to a .mtr file. Go back and re-read the post. That should point to an actual surface CONTAINED inside the .mtr file, otherwise it wont know what surface to look for.<br /><br />I've uploaded an example model, below. Notice that it points to the surface:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "//base/models/proj/nail.tga"</div></div><br />This works, because it's a hack that works inside doom, but it's wrong. You need to specify the material declaration, like this:<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "//base/materials/myybox"<br /></div><br /><br />No additions.<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">This means that, regardless of the name of the material file (which can be called anything), it will search inside all available material .mtr files for this surface. Which would look like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">base/models/proj/nail<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage       base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br /><br />   bumpMap      base/models/proj/nail_local.tga<br />   diffuseMap      base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br />   specularMap      base/models/proj/nail_s.tga<br />}</div></div><br />This is also wrong. It does not search inside all available materials, in fact it ignores anything after the material decl, so you can point to mybox or mybox.tga but it still points to the mybox decl. Or in your case, if you simply point to nail it will also work. <br /><br />From <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252/http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/modelexport.php">http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/modelexport.php</a><!-- m --><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"><span style="font-weight: bold">Static Models</span><br />Getting a static model (like a trash can or a shrubery) in to the game is really easy. Doom 3 reads lwo (lightwave) and ase (3dsmax) files natively so you simply save out the model in one of those two formats and you can use it in the game.<br /><br />The material that is used in game is the diffuse texture specified in the model.<br /><br />The relative material name is determined by searching for "base" in the texture path. For example, if the texture specified in the .ase is "C:\Doom\base\textures\base_trim\red1.tga" Then it would use the material named "textures\base_trim\red1"<br /><br />If you are running a custom mod, then it will look for the mod name if it can't find "base" so "C:\Doom\jailbreak\textures\base_trim\red1.tga" would also work in the jailbreak mod.<br /><br />The path cannot have spaces in it. Doom 3 should be installed in "C:\Doom\" or some other place without spaces. If Doom 3 is in the default location of "C:\Program Files\Doom 3\" it will not work because of the space in "Program Files" and the space in "Doom 3"<br /><br />Generally speaking, as long as you keep all your assets in the final directory that it will be in, then you should just be able to use it in game without having to touch anything. Problems tend to arise if you edit your assets in one directory, then move them in to the base directory or your mod directory after you export.<br /><br />If you are working on a new chair, you should work on it in<br />C:\Doom3\mymod\models\mapobjects\chairs\mychair\<br />rather than working on it in<br />C:\My Stuff\Models\Cool Models\Stuff For My Mod\Chair<br />then moving to the proper directory after it's been exported.<br /><br />Spaces in file names are bad.<br /><br />For more information on exporting from 3dstudio max, click here <br /></div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">gavavva wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I'm not the type of guy who cant admit when hes wrong, but to be quite honest it appears just because this guy posted a few tutorials you take his word as gods, but wont listen to the guy wit ha few posts...<br /><br />But come on gents, dont turn this into a slanging match just because I'm not somebody else, eh? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041252im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div><br />I'm sorry but these two statements just don't match, you just blatently dismissed my initial reply because you assume that I'm taking Brain Trepaning's word on it. I have years of experience here on this board and with my own mods and base my knowledge on my experiences alone.<br />I don't know if you see it or not, but the only one making this a slanging match is you, and people (including myself) get riled up because that doesn't help the TS at all; plus the fact that your wild assumptions are belittling.<br /><br />For the record, BT never said anywhere in this forum to point to a material file, he's always been very specific in explaining to point towards the material decl itself. The rule of thumb is very simple: never, ever, use the 4 letter combination '.tga' in any .ase file.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203681" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 6:18 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Things are simple really, don't need to flame over no more!<br /><br />Bitmap's line in ASE usually reference to images, cause it's defined in a Material's definition... but, it's a 3d program's Material's definition.<br />Doom3's way to "read" the ASE, and its Doom3 material reference are not the same as 3d programs.<br /><br />That's basicly why you can't define specular or bumpmap in an ASE for Doom3, and you got to reference to the right Doom3 material definition that define specularmap, bumpmap, etc.<br /><br />So yeah, you're right too. But we're not talking about a general way to handle/read/write a common ASE, we're talking about a Doom3 ASE.<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203684" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 11:08 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok that is it!!! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><br /><br />idk wtf i did wrong but i followed brian's tut exactly so here are my file, wtf did i do wrong.<br /><br />texture names: armchair_d.tga<br />                     armchair_ed.tga<br /><br /><br />.mtr file: <br /><br />textures/chair/armchair<br />{<br />    qer_editorimage	textures/chair/armchair_ed.tga<br /><br />         diffusemap	textures/chair/armchair_d.tga<br />}<br /><br />and ASE BITMAP path: *BITMAP "\\Purgatory\Purgatory\Doom\base\textures\chair\armchair.tga"<br /><br />plz help me <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203698" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 7:51 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">textures/chair/armchair<br />{<br />qer_editorimage textures/chair/armchair_ed.tga<br />diffusemap textures/chair/armchair_d.tga<br />}</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">ASE BITMAP path: *BITMAP "\\base\textures\chair\armchair"</div><br /><br />Notice the SLASHES face different ways. <br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">textures/chair/armchair</div> MATERIAL NAME<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">BITMAP "\\base\textures\chair\armchair</div> ASE BITMAP REFERENCE TO MATERIAL NAME<br /><br />Not always a problem, but sometimes it is, like when the SLASH is actually used as a letter in a material name.<br /><br />Anyway, if you're following my tutorial exactly, then name the stuff exactly as I did and it will work.<br /><br />If it does not work, then you did not follow the tutorial exactly.<br /><br />By the way, I do not care if I am right or wrong, I only care that my information is correct.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203699" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 7:56 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Doomguy87 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">ok that is it!!! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><br /><br />idk wtf i did wrong but i followed brian's tut exactly so here are my file, wtf did i do wrong.<br /><br />texture names: armchair_d.tga<br />                     armchair_ed.tga<br /><br /><br />.mtr file: <br /><br />textures/chair/armchair<br />{<br />    qer_editorimage	textures/chair/armchair_ed.tga<br /><br />         diffusemap	textures/chair/armchair_d.tga<br />}<br /><br />and ASE BITMAP path: *BITMAP "\\Purgatory\Purgatory\Doom\base\textures\chair\armchair.tga"<br /><br />plz help me <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div><br />Your ASE bitmap path should read:<br /><br />*BITMAP "\\base\textures/chair/armchair"<br />or<br />*BITMAP "\\base\textures\chair\armchair"<br /><br />Both will work fine.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203737" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 8:58 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">also y is *BITMAP path suddenly "\\<span style="text-decoration: underline">base</span>\textures\chair\armchair<br /><br />btw nothing worked<br /><br />EDIT:ok i did everything exactly with the taurus knot and everything and the fucking thing absolutley refuses to apply a texture, W T F <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><br /><br />also i cant rename it to .pk4 with winzip becuz when i save it it shows up as pak666 and not pak666.zip <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203742" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 10:40 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You're way greener with computers than I originally thought.<br /><br />Your computer is set to "retard-proof", or as the politically correct like to say, "French-Canadian Proof".<br /><br />You have to set your computer's preferences to show file extensions. <br /><br />I suggest downloading my mini-mod "Bob Sapp UFC Battle" and extracting it to its own folder and see how it's laid out. I made it specifically to be a drag-and-drop template for single-player Doom 3 mods.<br /><br />Good luck and have fun. For me, getting pissed off and finally getting stuff to work was what kept me going, but I can understand how it would also drive others away.<br /><br />As a second suggestion, post a link to your tutorial file ZIP that does not work so someone can download it and take a look.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203744" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 11:45 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey i did not know that i hardly use things like winzip but in anycase i finally got it to work by taking a llok at some scripts. and brain seriously u dont have to be like that, i just started this kinda stuff last year so im not the best but i am taking computer engineering so i should learn faster. but in any case i don't wanna fight so thanks for ur help everyone <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />and lastly.....how do i get to the system preferences i cant find it on my comp.DONT SAY ANYTHING. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203753" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 2:40 am "><author>LDAsh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Maybe it's time for Doomguy87 to upload his stuff, to let people have a good hard look directly at what isn't working and why.  There could be a number of issues getting in the way of the texture that aren't even related to ASE files, so make sure everything needed is uploaded.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203754" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 2:43 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ya its textured but now i cant see the pattern of the texture, its just <span style="color: #BFBF00">this colour</span> (which is the colour of the texture but now theres no design)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203773" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 11:08 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div>
  <div class="quotecontent">Your computer is set to "retard-proof", or as the politically correct like to say, "French-Canadian Proof".</div>
  <br />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" />
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203779" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 3:16 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /><br /><br />I am French-Canadian.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121042030im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203106" date="Posted: Mon Aug 04, 2008 4:22 pm "><author>Gripper666</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hi, ive finally worked out how to import a model into doom3 that has a single texture but my problem is how can i import a single model with multiple textures? everytime i try it only shows up with a single texture in the editor &amp; game, is there anything special i should be doing or does it work on the same principle as the single texture method?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203129" date="Posted: Mon Aug 04, 2008 11:53 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's possible to use multiple material shaders on a single model. The models that come with the game prove as much.<br /><br />However, what changes you need to make in order to be successful is dependant on your workflow. What model format are you working with, LWO, ASE, MD5? What's your toolset? What import/export utilites are you using?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203131" date="Posted: Tue Aug 05, 2008 12:12 am "><author>Gripper666</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">well i downloaded some free models that are .3ds format from a free website &amp; i load them into 3ds max 9 &amp; after adding textures &amp; adding a multires &amp; uv map i export them to an .ase file, then i open the exported model in notepad &amp; make afew changes to the texture paths so the doom editor can find them.<br />this method works fine if i use just 1 texture but if i add more they never show up, im pretty new to using 3d modelling programs so im kinda lost at the moment.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203136" date="Posted: Tue Aug 05, 2008 1:25 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">For ASE objects you must keep 1 texture by object (no multimaterials) BUT you can export severals objects into only one model/ASE with the "export selected' command.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203142" date="Posted: Tue Aug 05, 2008 7:46 am "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Erm, no its not impossible... Its pretty damn easy?<br /><br />Just set up different surfaces is your model file that point to different textures...? I've been doing it for years. I think its something like 16 max surfaces in a model file.<br /><br />EDIT: Wow, bit early in the morning for me... I could of sworn everybody said it was impossible then lol.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203550" date="Posted: Tue Aug 12, 2008 12:44 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">when u adjust the path name in ur .ASE does the bitmap path have to be "Purgatory\Purgatory\Doom\base\textures\custom\your_file.tga ?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203554" date="Posted: Tue Aug 12, 2008 2:47 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="codetitle">
    <b>Code:</b>
  </div>
  <div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\yourMaterialName"</div>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203558" date="Posted: Tue Aug 12, 2008 3:57 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok just base\mymaterialname thanks brian</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203615" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 7:24 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">by material do u mean my texture or .mtr file and wouldnt the paths be *BITMAP "\\base\materials\mymaterialname?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203617" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 9:19 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">yourMaterialName<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage   textures/anyFolder/whatever_ed.tga<br />   diffusemap   textures/anyFolder/whatever_d.tga<br />}<br /></div><br /><br />will use<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />but if you NAME your material<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">materials\yourMaterialName<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage   textures/anyFolder/whatever_ed.tga<br />   diffusemap   textures/anyFolder/whatever_d.tga<br />}<br /></div><br /><br />then the ASE Bitmap would be<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\materials\yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />because<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">\\base\<br /></div><br /><br />is the only part that is an actual PATH and<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">materials\yourMaterialName<br /></div><br /><br />is just a NAME.<br /><br />HOWEVER, by calling your material <br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">materials\yourMaterialName<br /></div><br /><br />You will find yourMaterialName in a subfolder called MATERIALS in the editor, as the folder will be automatically created IN THE EDITOR</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203618" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 9:34 am "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thats not correct...?<br /><br />It should point to the surface used by your model, NOT the material. The material is just a file to store all other materials in.<br /><br />So, if your "material" looks like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">models/weapons/pie/pie_hat<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage   models/weapons/pie/pie_hat_d.tga<br />   diffusemap   models/weapons/pie/pie_hat_d.tga<br />}</div><br /><br />Then of course your actual ".md5mesh" file should read like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "\\base\models\weapons\pie\pie_hat"</div><br /><br />See why this is different? Its because its linking to the SURFACE, not the material file.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203640" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 10:23 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Dude, I have no idea what you're talking about, but we're talking about ASE models, not MD5MESH models, and I have over 1500 working examples within my released mods to prove my info is proper and functional.<br /><br />For an MD5MESh, all that is required is<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">shader "yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />So, please don't confuse the issue unless you have something accurate to post.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203641" date="Posted: Wed Aug 13, 2008 10:36 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">its true, his models work but IM having an issue with textures, in any case thanks <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203659" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 11:06 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I have over 1500 working examples within my released mods to prove my info is proper and functional.</div><br />***FREE PUB HERE***<br /><br />Really?!? And what are those released mods?<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203662" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:45 pm "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Dude, I have no idea what you're talking about, but we're talking about ASE models, not MD5MESH models, and I have over 1500 working examples within my released mods to prove my info is proper and functional.<br /><br />For an MD5MESh, all that is required is<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">shader "yourMaterialName"<br /></div><br /><br />So, please don't confuse the issue unless you have something accurate to post.</div><br /><br />As do I, and have been working with .ase models professionally for years now.<br /><br />What you posted, is wrong. There are no two ways about it. Whatever mod you have these thousands (lol) of models for, must really hate you, because you dont know the basics. You are linking the shader in the .ase file to the MATERIAL, which is wrong. You should be point to a specific TEXTURE, which the material itself will handle.<br /><br />Take another look at your post. You tell him this:<br /><br />*BITMAP "\\base\materials\yourMaterialName"<br /><br />Which is clearly WRONG for what should be in the .ase file. Thats telling him to point to his .mtr file and NOT to his surface.<br /><br />So please, dont try and school me on the basics kid, I've been working far too long with them. Re-read our post, and see where you made the mistake.<br /><br />EDIT: Remember, hes trying to get this working ingame, with no textures showing up. No textures show up because the .ase file is pointing to a material, not a surface. If we were to take this ingame, its the wrong way to go about things because it will never render correctly and will fill the console with errors.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203664" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:58 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Seriously, dude, show us your portfolio or shut up.<br /><br />As for mine, download them from my site and tell me I am wrong and my stuff doesn't work. I never said to point to the WHATEVER.MTR, I said to point to the name of his MATERIAL. What you said was <br /><br />"The material is just a file to store all other materials in."<br /><br />What is that supposed to mean? Then you went on the mention MD5MESH and that had nothing to do with what was being discussed. Kid.<br /><br />@ 6th Venom: By example, Bubba Lego-Tep has over 1470 ASE models, so add the contents of the other mods to it, and it's actually quite a bit more than 1500, and they all work as I described with no errors in consoles.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203665" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 12:59 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">gavavva wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">EDIT: Remember, hes trying to get this working ingame, with no textures showing up. No textures show up because the .ase file is pointing to a material, not a surface. If we were to take this ingame, its the wrong way to go about things because it will never render correctly and will fill the console with errors.</div><br />In terms of doom3 you are totally, and absolutely, 100% <span style="font-weight: bold">WRONG</span>. And don't diss BrainTrepaning because he's proven himself over and over to the community, giving us countless of tutorials and mods, what he posted is correct.<br /><br />There are no 'surfaces' in Doom3, only material decls, popularly named 'materials' that define which texture files to use. I suggest you head on over to <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650/http://www.iddevnet.com/">http://www.iddevnet.com</a><!-- m --> and educate yourself, before shaming yourself further with your arrogant tone. I don't mind if people make mistakes, we make them to learn from them, but your arrogance is staggering considering the fact that you are plain wrong.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203666" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 1:20 pm "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The point I'm trying to make is you are telling him that BITMAP in his .ase file needs to point to a .mtr file. Go back and re-read the post. That should point to an actual surface CONTAINED inside the .mtr file, otherwise it wont know what surface to look for.<br /><br />I've uploaded an example model, below. Notice that it points to the surface:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "//base/models/proj/nail.tga"</div><br /><br />This means that, regardless of the name of the material file (which can be called anything), it will search inside all available material .mtr files for this surface. Which would look like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">base/models/proj/nail<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage       base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br /><br />   bumpMap      base/models/proj/nail_local.tga<br />   diffuseMap      base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br />   specularMap      base/models/proj/nail_s.tga<br />}</div><br /><br />Download the model, and tell me I'm wrong? Because if I am wrong, then I honestly dont see how its worked in the few retail games I've shipped.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203667" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 1:26 pm "><author>gavavva</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm not the type of guy who cant admit when hes wrong, but to be quite honest it appears just because this guy posted a few tutorials you take his word as gods, but wont listen to the guy wit ha few posts. Fair enough. But lose the attitude gents, its not called for, not here. The end result from all of us is the same, and that is to help this chap, yeah?<br /><br />So whatever way we get there, and whoever is wrong, doesnt matter. If I am wrong, then thats perfectly fine, I'm wrong. I'm not a wimp, and I can take a beating on an online forum <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />But come on gents, dont turn this into a slanging match just because I'm not somebody else, eh? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203668" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 1:41 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">gavavva wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">The point I'm trying to make is you are telling him that BITMAP in his .ase file needs to point to a .mtr file. Go back and re-read the post. That should point to an actual surface CONTAINED inside the .mtr file, otherwise it wont know what surface to look for.<br /><br />I've uploaded an example model, below. Notice that it points to the surface:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "//base/models/proj/nail.tga"</div></div><br />This works, because it's a hack that works inside doom, but it's wrong. You need to specify the material declaration, like this:<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">*BITMAP "//base/materials/myybox"<br /></div><br /><br />No additions.<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">This means that, regardless of the name of the material file (which can be called anything), it will search inside all available material .mtr files for this surface. Which would look like this:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">base/models/proj/nail<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage       base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br /><br />   bumpMap      base/models/proj/nail_local.tga<br />   diffuseMap      base/models/proj/nail_d.tga<br />   specularMap      base/models/proj/nail_s.tga<br />}</div></div><br />This is also wrong. It does not search inside all available materials, in fact it ignores anything after the material decl, so you can point to mybox or mybox.tga but it still points to the mybox decl. Or in your case, if you simply point to nail it will also work. <br /><br />From <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650/http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/modelexport.php">http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/modelexport.php</a><!-- m --><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"><span style="font-weight: bold">Static Models</span><br />Getting a static model (like a trash can or a shrubery) in to the game is really easy. Doom 3 reads lwo (lightwave) and ase (3dsmax) files natively so you simply save out the model in one of those two formats and you can use it in the game.<br /><br />The material that is used in game is the diffuse texture specified in the model.<br /><br />The relative material name is determined by searching for "base" in the texture path. For example, if the texture specified in the .ase is "C:\Doom\base\textures\base_trim\red1.tga" Then it would use the material named "textures\base_trim\red1"<br /><br />If you are running a custom mod, then it will look for the mod name if it can't find "base" so "C:\Doom\jailbreak\textures\base_trim\red1.tga" would also work in the jailbreak mod.<br /><br />The path cannot have spaces in it. Doom 3 should be installed in "C:\Doom\" or some other place without spaces. If Doom 3 is in the default location of "C:\Program Files\Doom 3\" it will not work because of the space in "Program Files" and the space in "Doom 3"<br /><br />Generally speaking, as long as you keep all your assets in the final directory that it will be in, then you should just be able to use it in game without having to touch anything. Problems tend to arise if you edit your assets in one directory, then move them in to the base directory or your mod directory after you export.<br /><br />If you are working on a new chair, you should work on it in<br />C:\Doom3\mymod\models\mapobjects\chairs\mychair\<br />rather than working on it in<br />C:\My Stuff\Models\Cool Models\Stuff For My Mod\Chair<br />then moving to the proper directory after it's been exported.<br /><br />Spaces in file names are bad.<br /><br />For more information on exporting from 3dstudio max, click here <br /></div><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">gavavva wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I'm not the type of guy who cant admit when hes wrong, but to be quite honest it appears just because this guy posted a few tutorials you take his word as gods, but wont listen to the guy wit ha few posts...<br /><br />But come on gents, dont turn this into a slanging match just because I'm not somebody else, eh? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121041650im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div><br />I'm sorry but these two statements just don't match, you just blatently dismissed my initial reply because you assume that I'm taking Brain Trepaning's word on it. I have years of experience here on this board and with my own mods and base my knowledge on my experiences alone.<br />I don't know if you see it or not, but the only one making this a slanging match is you, and people (including myself) get riled up because that doesn't help the TS at all; plus the fact that your wild assumptions are belittling.<br /><br />For the record, BT never said anywhere in this forum to point to a material file, he's always been very specific in explaining to point towards the material decl itself. The rule of thumb is very simple: never, ever, use the 4 letter combination '.tga' in any .ase file.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203681" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 6:18 pm "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Things are simple really, don't need to flame over no more!<br /><br />Bitmap's line in ASE usually reference to images, cause it's defined in a Material's definition... but, it's a 3d program's Material's definition.<br />Doom3's way to "read" the ASE, and its Doom3 material reference are not the same as 3d programs.<br /><br />That's basicly why you can't define specular or bumpmap in an ASE for Doom3, and you got to reference to the right Doom3 material definition that define specularmap, bumpmap, etc.<br /><br />So yeah, you're right too. But we're not talking about a general way to handle/read/write a common ASE, we're talking about a Doom3 ASE.<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203684" date="Posted: Thu Aug 14, 2008 11:08 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok that is it!!! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><br /><br />idk wtf i did wrong but i followed brian's tut exactly so here are my file, wtf did i do wrong.<br /><br />texture names: armchair_d.tga<br />                     armchair_ed.tga<br /><br /><br />.mtr file: <br /><br />textures/chair/armchair<br />{<br />    qer_editorimage	textures/chair/armchair_ed.tga<br /><br />         diffusemap	textures/chair/armchair_d.tga<br />}<br /><br />and ASE BITMAP path: *BITMAP "\\Purgatory\Purgatory\Doom\base\textures\chair\armchair.tga"<br /><br />plz help me <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203698" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 7:51 am "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">textures/chair/armchair<br />{<br />qer_editorimage textures/chair/armchair_ed.tga<br />diffusemap textures/chair/armchair_d.tga<br />}</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">ASE BITMAP path: *BITMAP "\\base\textures\chair\armchair"</div><br /><br />Notice the SLASHES face different ways. <br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">textures/chair/armchair</div> MATERIAL NAME<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">BITMAP "\\base\textures\chair\armchair</div> ASE BITMAP REFERENCE TO MATERIAL NAME<br /><br />Not always a problem, but sometimes it is, like when the SLASH is actually used as a letter in a material name.<br /><br />Anyway, if you're following my tutorial exactly, then name the stuff exactly as I did and it will work.<br /><br />If it does not work, then you did not follow the tutorial exactly.<br /><br />By the way, I do not care if I am right or wrong, I only care that my information is correct.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203699" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 7:56 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Doomguy87 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">ok that is it!!! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><br /><br />idk wtf i did wrong but i followed brian's tut exactly so here are my file, wtf did i do wrong.<br /><br />texture names: armchair_d.tga<br />                     armchair_ed.tga<br /><br /><br />.mtr file: <br /><br />textures/chair/armchair<br />{<br />    qer_editorimage	textures/chair/armchair_ed.tga<br /><br />         diffusemap	textures/chair/armchair_d.tga<br />}<br /><br />and ASE BITMAP path: *BITMAP "\\Purgatory\Purgatory\Doom\base\textures\chair\armchair.tga"<br /><br />plz help me <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div><br />Your ASE bitmap path should read:<br /><br />*BITMAP "\\base\textures/chair/armchair"<br />or<br />*BITMAP "\\base\textures\chair\armchair"<br /><br />Both will work fine.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203737" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 8:58 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">also y is *BITMAP path suddenly "\\<span style="text-decoration: underline">base</span>\textures\chair\armchair<br /><br />btw nothing worked<br /><br />EDIT:ok i did everything exactly with the taurus knot and everything and the fucking thing absolutley refuses to apply a texture, W T F <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><br /><br />also i cant rename it to .pk4 with winzip becuz when i save it it shows up as pak666 and not pak666.zip <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203742" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 10:40 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You're way greener with computers than I originally thought.<br /><br />Your computer is set to "retard-proof", or as the politically correct like to say, "French-Canadian Proof".<br /><br />You have to set your computer's preferences to show file extensions. <br /><br />I suggest downloading my mini-mod "Bob Sapp UFC Battle" and extracting it to its own folder and see how it's laid out. I made it specifically to be a drag-and-drop template for single-player Doom 3 mods.<br /><br />Good luck and have fun. For me, getting pissed off and finally getting stuff to work was what kept me going, but I can understand how it would also drive others away.<br /><br />As a second suggestion, post a link to your tutorial file ZIP that does not work so someone can download it and take a look.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203744" date="Posted: Fri Aug 15, 2008 11:45 pm "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey i did not know that i hardly use things like winzip but in anycase i finally got it to work by taking a llok at some scripts. and brain seriously u dont have to be like that, i just started this kinda stuff last year so im not the best but i am taking computer engineering so i should learn faster. but in any case i don't wanna fight so thanks for ur help everyone <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />and lastly.....how do i get to the system preferences i cant find it on my comp.DONT SAY ANYTHING. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p203753" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 2:40 am "><author>LDAsh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Maybe it's time for Doomguy87 to upload his stuff, to let people have a good hard look directly at what isn't working and why.  There could be a number of issues getting in the way of the texture that aren't even related to ASE files, so make sure everything needed is uploaded.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203754" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 2:43 am "><author>Doomguy87</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ya its textured but now i cant see the pattern of the texture, its just <span style="color: #BFBF00">this colour</span> (which is the colour of the texture but now theres no design)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203773" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 11:08 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="quotetitle">Brain Trepaning wrote:</div>
  <div class="quotecontent">Your computer is set to "retard-proof", or as the politically correct like to say, "French-Canadian Proof".</div>
  <br />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" />
  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" />
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p203779" date="Posted: Sat Aug 16, 2008 3:16 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /><br /><br />I am French-Canadian.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081121040837im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
