<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="21943"><title>The Gamer's Bill of Rights Unveiled</title><posts><post id="p204470" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 10:27 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081118091353/http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/54480">http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/54480</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We the Gamers of the world, in order to ensure a more enjoyable experience, establish equality between players and publishers, and promote the general welfare of our industry hereby call for the following:<br /><br />   1. Gamers shall have the right to return games that don't work with their computers for a full refund.<br />   2. Gamers shall have the right to demand that games be released in a finished state.<br />   3. Gamers shall have the right to expect meaningful updates after a game's release.<br />   4. Gamers shall have the right to demand that download managers and updaters not force themselves to run or be forced to load in order to play a game.<br />   5. Gamers shall have the right to expect that the minimum requirements for a game will mean that the game will adequately play on that computer.<br />   6. Gamers shall have the right to expect that games won't install hidden drivers or other potentially harmful software without their express consent.<br />   7. Gamers shall have the right to re-download the latest versions of the games they own at any time.<br />   8. Gamers shall have the right to not be treated as potential criminals by developers or publishers.<br />   9. Gamers shall have the right to demand that a single-player game not force them to be connected to the Internet every time they wish to play.<br />  10. Gamers shall have the right that games which are installed to the hard drive shall not require a CD/DVD to remain in the drive to play.<br /></div><br /><br />Yay!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081118091353im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p204472" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 11:12 am "><author>rebb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Oh hey, i wish they would extend that to a full "User's Bill of Rights".<br /><br />There are so many standard programs that are prime offenders against this Bill already - if they were Games.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204483" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 2:25 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">besides #1 &amp; 3, I agree.<br /><br />why not #1?  people are stupid &amp; they will say it didn't work on their toaster.  With #5 #1 is negated: if you fit #5 anything wrong isn't the dev's/publisher's fault, it's your machine's fault.<br /><br />Why not #3?  no reason to expect updates.  If #5 &amp; #2 fits then the game is done.  If it doesn't work with a windows update or a new processor, that's YOU problem,  #2 &amp; 5 said the requirements on the box woud work, nothing else.  We're not stupid enough to buy a NES game &amp; expect it to run on a PS3, PC games no different.<br /><br />Basically, those two say "turn Pc in to console".  Hence buy a console.  :/</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204485" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 2:46 pm "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Developers Bill of rights<br /><br />1) We shall have the right to over charge to 'meet' the requirements of the "Gamers Bill of Rights"<br />2) Repeat #1<br />3) We reserve the right to change these rights at any time without notification and for any reason that may or may not be plausible, made up, or falsely true.<br />4) E&amp;OE</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204487" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 3:12 pm "><author>Mordenkainen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">These are well intentioned but ultimately vague and wide open to abuse. A couple are IMHO not practical in a capitalist-driven society such as ours. Finally, until they are adopted by at least a major publisher their impact on gamer lives will be diminute. After all this is all about improving how people play games and not a publicity stunt to help sell Space Siege, right? From the top:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">1. Gamers shall have the right to return games that don't work with their computers for a full refund.</div><br /><br />That's excellent and actually in place already over here. As long as the game is still shrinkwraped you can return it to the store for either another item or, if you push hard enough, a full refund. I'm left scratching my head why this is a gamer's right when this deals with a customer returning an unusable item to a store. For other countries where this isn't yet possible, how will publishers adhering to these rights allow for this one to happen without the cooperation of the stores?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">2. Gamers shall have the right to demand that games be released in a finished state.</div><br /><br />We have a right to demand this but we don't have a right to expect this. All software is imperfect, there is no bug-free software. And what exactly is a "finished state". If you take a literal interpretation then this right is somewhat contradictory to the third right.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">3. Gamers shall have the right to expect meaningful updates after a game's release.</div><br /><br />Again with the semantics, right to expect does not mean right to have delivered. Also, what is a "meaningful update"? For some it's extra maps, for others it might be extra game modes. Who gets to decide. Also, notice how there's no mention of price for these updates.<br /><br />I've wanted a formal comittment to deliver patches (at least) from developers/publishers for some time now but this right says nothing and suggests nothing. A more reasonable requirement would be to support all games for at least a year and multiplayer games for at least 3 years. But even so, what kind of support? A developer that releases a single patch exactly 12 months after the game's release that only changes the version number is technically fulfilling the requirement even if their soul will rot in hell.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">4. Gamers shall have the right to demand that download managers and updaters not force themselves to run or be forced to load in order to play a game.</div><br /><br />Finally a right that is a little more specific. Basically this right says the game has to be separate from whichever delivery medium the game comes in. I agree with this one and I think it's specific enough to be useful. This can actually subsume rights 9 and 10 but I guess GPG/Stardock wanted a round number.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">5. Gamers shall have the right to expect that the minimum requirements for a game will mean that the game will adequately play on that computer.</div><br /><br />Again a reasonable right and one many people have wished to be standardised. But again this right is too vague. What exactly is a game that "plays adequately"? Is it 30fps? At what resolution? Does it matter that you can run a 2008 game at 30fps if you have to turn the quality back to 1995?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">6. Gamers shall have the right to expect that games won't install hidden drivers or other potentially harmful software without their express consent.</div><br /><br />Agreed but again a bit vague and open to interpretation. What is a driver? Does that include OGL ICDs? What if a game will only run if you install the latest driver version? Are games going to have a gazillion Accept/Cancel screens? One for the game, another for the GameSpy Arcade stuff, another for Punkbuster and another for God knows what else? Anyway, this one is doable but seems overly picky to me.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">7. Gamers shall have the right to re-download the latest versions of the games they own at any time.</div><br /><br />Again agreed and again vague. Is this for all games or only for the ones you've bought a digital version? From where can we re-download it? Publisher's website? Usernet?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">8. Gamers shall have the right to not be treated as potential criminals by developers or publishers.</div><br /><br />War is hell, children must not be molested, while pets mustn't ever starve. Yes, yes. HOW? Ditch DRM? Be specific.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">9. Gamers shall have the right to demand that a single-player game not force them to be connected to the Internet every time they wish to play.</div><br /><br />This is the other more specific right even though it is a superset of right 4. Also notice the wording: a right to demand does not equal a right to expect or a right to have this capability. I know they were going for flavour when they wrote this but how about: Games can only require an internet connection for checking for updates or playing multiplayer. There, much clearer.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">10. Gamers shall have the right that games which are installed to the hard drive shall not require a CD/DVD to remain in the drive to play.</div><br /><br />AKA the No-CD crack. No snarky comments here.<br /><br />Anyway, this could have probably be reduced to three or four requirements that games to fulfil to gain the "Gamer Friendly" award.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204500" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 9:00 pm "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-size: 75%; line-height: normal">11: Gamers shall not read The Gamer's Bill of Rights in hope that it will bring a positive future to their gaming experience <span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic">Please</span></span> go kill yourselves developers who can't so much as hire a crew to keep their games updated regularly and providing at least a half-ways gah-FUH-FLUBBLE JERK JAH HAH HAH-HAH-HAH HAHAHAHA! <br /><br />Oh, and, and...<br /><br />12: Developers shall have the rights to exploit the fact that just because they created a game means they can control whether or not they want to please their customers or go spend their money on cars and prostitutes and make up stories about how their supposedly large team is busy working twenty-four-seven run-on sentence to create a brand new game that won't be released for another eight or ten years that will in turn be beaten in ten or twenty hours total gameplay time, even exploring every aspect of the world and going at snail pace, wait, what's that? It's snowing out? Or maybe it's a ________!<br /><br />Wait, I'm not done yet.<br /><br />13: Developers shall have the rights to tell their customers that, frankly, they have no idea what they're talking about. Afterall, the developers know what's right about their game, since, you know, they developed it. Customers? They're animals - They know nothing about what it's like to make a few changes in script or backspace and enter a few numbers. It is I, Hostel Part II-cles, God of Castration Scenes, who makes the changes around here. Plus, customers don't know any aspect of the game to tell the developers, who have had far less experience actually play-testing and experiencing the game fully, how to fix something to make the game more enjoyable and fun for everyone else.<br /><br /><br />Or maybe I'm just ranting and letting out steam about how some developers pay absolutely no attention to the players and fans and what <span style="font-style: italic">they</span> would like to see. A little balance, maybe? Give them this, and them that? Nope. "We built these casinos with our own money - You stole our land from us, and now you seek to demand us further?" Maybe I could cheese it up a little bit by making a reference to World of ________! For the Alliance! <br /><br />"Hello, Hostel Part II-cles, can you help me? Zombies have attacked our city and they made way with everything we had. Would you kindly go and kill ten thousand of them and bring me back six thousand zombie fingers that have a 0.01% chance to be "looted" off of their corpses? Vengeance will be sweet." Quest Reward: 1 Copper. <span style="font-style: italic">Accept!</span><br /><br />Whee!<br />Quest Log!<br />Evil Zombie Pyromancer Slain 15/10,000<br />Stinky Finger Collected 0/6,000<br /><br />Jesus God! This is fun. So is Google.</span><br /><br /><br />Though, all of that aside, it'd be <span style="font-style: italic">cool</span> if this was serious.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204505" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 9:39 pm "><author>DoV_Tomas</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here's a few more that could be added to the list:<br /><br />1. Gamers shall have the right to see previews taken from the actual game play, not from cut-scenes or cinematics made in stand-alone animation programs. This goes for still preview images as well. <br /><br />2. Gamers will have the right to be treated as if their IQ was more than 50 and that their age range extends beyond 12, so it's acknowledged that some gamers can actually do more than just mash buttons to win a game. <br /><br />3. Gamers will receive actual instructions for sim games, and not have to rely on digging through forums to find out how to play the game. <br /><br />4. Gamers will have the right to receive fixes from the publisher instead of relying on community members who don't get paid for their efforts and dedication. <br /><br />5. Modders who devote years of their lives creating free content for the community and extending a company's brand will be acknowledged when hiring time comes. <br /><br />6. Developers will admit that brutal killing is not the only form of entertainment that people like.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204470" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 10:27 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081118090728/http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/54480">http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/54480</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We the Gamers of the world, in order to ensure a more enjoyable experience, establish equality between players and publishers, and promote the general welfare of our industry hereby call for the following:<br /><br />   1. Gamers shall have the right to return games that don't work with their computers for a full refund.<br />   2. Gamers shall have the right to demand that games be released in a finished state.<br />   3. Gamers shall have the right to expect meaningful updates after a game's release.<br />   4. Gamers shall have the right to demand that download managers and updaters not force themselves to run or be forced to load in order to play a game.<br />   5. Gamers shall have the right to expect that the minimum requirements for a game will mean that the game will adequately play on that computer.<br />   6. Gamers shall have the right to expect that games won't install hidden drivers or other potentially harmful software without their express consent.<br />   7. Gamers shall have the right to re-download the latest versions of the games they own at any time.<br />   8. Gamers shall have the right to not be treated as potential criminals by developers or publishers.<br />   9. Gamers shall have the right to demand that a single-player game not force them to be connected to the Internet every time they wish to play.<br />  10. Gamers shall have the right that games which are installed to the hard drive shall not require a CD/DVD to remain in the drive to play.<br /></div><br /><br />Yay!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081118090728im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p204472" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 11:12 am "><author>rebb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Oh hey, i wish they would extend that to a full "User's Bill of Rights".<br /><br />There are so many standard programs that are prime offenders against this Bill already - if they were Games.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204483" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 2:25 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">besides #1 &amp; 3, I agree.<br /><br />why not #1?  people are stupid &amp; they will say it didn't work on their toaster.  With #5 #1 is negated: if you fit #5 anything wrong isn't the dev's/publisher's fault, it's your machine's fault.<br /><br />Why not #3?  no reason to expect updates.  If #5 &amp; #2 fits then the game is done.  If it doesn't work with a windows update or a new processor, that's YOU problem,  #2 &amp; 5 said the requirements on the box woud work, nothing else.  We're not stupid enough to buy a NES game &amp; expect it to run on a PS3, PC games no different.<br /><br />Basically, those two say "turn Pc in to console".  Hence buy a console.  :/</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204485" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 2:46 pm "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Developers Bill of rights<br /><br />1) We shall have the right to over charge to 'meet' the requirements of the "Gamers Bill of Rights"<br />2) Repeat #1<br />3) We reserve the right to change these rights at any time without notification and for any reason that may or may not be plausible, made up, or falsely true.<br />4) E&amp;OE</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204487" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 3:12 pm "><author>Mordenkainen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">These are well intentioned but ultimately vague and wide open to abuse. A couple are IMHO not practical in a capitalist-driven society such as ours. Finally, until they are adopted by at least a major publisher their impact on gamer lives will be diminute. After all this is all about improving how people play games and not a publicity stunt to help sell Space Siege, right? From the top:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">1. Gamers shall have the right to return games that don't work with their computers for a full refund.</div><br /><br />That's excellent and actually in place already over here. As long as the game is still shrinkwraped you can return it to the store for either another item or, if you push hard enough, a full refund. I'm left scratching my head why this is a gamer's right when this deals with a customer returning an unusable item to a store. For other countries where this isn't yet possible, how will publishers adhering to these rights allow for this one to happen without the cooperation of the stores?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">2. Gamers shall have the right to demand that games be released in a finished state.</div><br /><br />We have a right to demand this but we don't have a right to expect this. All software is imperfect, there is no bug-free software. And what exactly is a "finished state". If you take a literal interpretation then this right is somewhat contradictory to the third right.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">3. Gamers shall have the right to expect meaningful updates after a game's release.</div><br /><br />Again with the semantics, right to expect does not mean right to have delivered. Also, what is a "meaningful update"? For some it's extra maps, for others it might be extra game modes. Who gets to decide. Also, notice how there's no mention of price for these updates.<br /><br />I've wanted a formal comittment to deliver patches (at least) from developers/publishers for some time now but this right says nothing and suggests nothing. A more reasonable requirement would be to support all games for at least a year and multiplayer games for at least 3 years. But even so, what kind of support? A developer that releases a single patch exactly 12 months after the game's release that only changes the version number is technically fulfilling the requirement even if their soul will rot in hell.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">4. Gamers shall have the right to demand that download managers and updaters not force themselves to run or be forced to load in order to play a game.</div><br /><br />Finally a right that is a little more specific. Basically this right says the game has to be separate from whichever delivery medium the game comes in. I agree with this one and I think it's specific enough to be useful. This can actually subsume rights 9 and 10 but I guess GPG/Stardock wanted a round number.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">5. Gamers shall have the right to expect that the minimum requirements for a game will mean that the game will adequately play on that computer.</div><br /><br />Again a reasonable right and one many people have wished to be standardised. But again this right is too vague. What exactly is a game that "plays adequately"? Is it 30fps? At what resolution? Does it matter that you can run a 2008 game at 30fps if you have to turn the quality back to 1995?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">6. Gamers shall have the right to expect that games won't install hidden drivers or other potentially harmful software without their express consent.</div><br /><br />Agreed but again a bit vague and open to interpretation. What is a driver? Does that include OGL ICDs? What if a game will only run if you install the latest driver version? Are games going to have a gazillion Accept/Cancel screens? One for the game, another for the GameSpy Arcade stuff, another for Punkbuster and another for God knows what else? Anyway, this one is doable but seems overly picky to me.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">7. Gamers shall have the right to re-download the latest versions of the games they own at any time.</div><br /><br />Again agreed and again vague. Is this for all games or only for the ones you've bought a digital version? From where can we re-download it? Publisher's website? Usernet?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">8. Gamers shall have the right to not be treated as potential criminals by developers or publishers.</div><br /><br />War is hell, children must not be molested, while pets mustn't ever starve. Yes, yes. HOW? Ditch DRM? Be specific.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">9. Gamers shall have the right to demand that a single-player game not force them to be connected to the Internet every time they wish to play.</div><br /><br />This is the other more specific right even though it is a superset of right 4. Also notice the wording: a right to demand does not equal a right to expect or a right to have this capability. I know they were going for flavour when they wrote this but how about: Games can only require an internet connection for checking for updates or playing multiplayer. There, much clearer.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">10. Gamers shall have the right that games which are installed to the hard drive shall not require a CD/DVD to remain in the drive to play.</div><br /><br />AKA the No-CD crack. No snarky comments here.<br /><br />Anyway, this could have probably be reduced to three or four requirements that games to fulfil to gain the "Gamer Friendly" award.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204500" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 9:00 pm "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-size: 75%; line-height: normal">11: Gamers shall not read The Gamer's Bill of Rights in hope that it will bring a positive future to their gaming experience <span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic">Please</span></span> go kill yourselves developers who can't so much as hire a crew to keep their games updated regularly and providing at least a half-ways gah-FUH-FLUBBLE JERK JAH HAH HAH-HAH-HAH HAHAHAHA! <br /><br />Oh, and, and...<br /><br />12: Developers shall have the rights to exploit the fact that just because they created a game means they can control whether or not they want to please their customers or go spend their money on cars and prostitutes and make up stories about how their supposedly large team is busy working twenty-four-seven run-on sentence to create a brand new game that won't be released for another eight or ten years that will in turn be beaten in ten or twenty hours total gameplay time, even exploring every aspect of the world and going at snail pace, wait, what's that? It's snowing out? Or maybe it's a ________!<br /><br />Wait, I'm not done yet.<br /><br />13: Developers shall have the rights to tell their customers that, frankly, they have no idea what they're talking about. Afterall, the developers know what's right about their game, since, you know, they developed it. Customers? They're animals - They know nothing about what it's like to make a few changes in script or backspace and enter a few numbers. It is I, Hostel Part II-cles, God of Castration Scenes, who makes the changes around here. Plus, customers don't know any aspect of the game to tell the developers, who have had far less experience actually play-testing and experiencing the game fully, how to fix something to make the game more enjoyable and fun for everyone else.<br /><br /><br />Or maybe I'm just ranting and letting out steam about how some developers pay absolutely no attention to the players and fans and what <span style="font-style: italic">they</span> would like to see. A little balance, maybe? Give them this, and them that? Nope. "We built these casinos with our own money - You stole our land from us, and now you seek to demand us further?" Maybe I could cheese it up a little bit by making a reference to World of ________! For the Alliance! <br /><br />"Hello, Hostel Part II-cles, can you help me? Zombies have attacked our city and they made way with everything we had. Would you kindly go and kill ten thousand of them and bring me back six thousand zombie fingers that have a 0.01% chance to be "looted" off of their corpses? Vengeance will be sweet." Quest Reward: 1 Copper. <span style="font-style: italic">Accept!</span><br /><br />Whee!<br />Quest Log!<br />Evil Zombie Pyromancer Slain 15/10,000<br />Stinky Finger Collected 0/6,000<br /><br />Jesus God! This is fun. So is Google.</span><br /><br /><br />Though, all of that aside, it'd be <span style="font-style: italic">cool</span> if this was serious.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p204505" date="Posted: Wed Sep 03, 2008 9:39 pm "><author>DoV_Tomas</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here's a few more that could be added to the list:<br /><br />1. Gamers shall have the right to see previews taken from the actual game play, not from cut-scenes or cinematics made in stand-alone animation programs. This goes for still preview images as well. <br /><br />2. Gamers will have the right to be treated as if their IQ was more than 50 and that their age range extends beyond 12, so it's acknowledged that some gamers can actually do more than just mash buttons to win a game. <br /><br />3. Gamers will receive actual instructions for sim games, and not have to rely on digging through forums to find out how to play the game. <br /><br />4. Gamers will have the right to receive fixes from the publisher instead of relying on community members who don't get paid for their efforts and dedication. <br /><br />5. Modders who devote years of their lives creating free content for the community and extending a company's brand will be acknowledged when hiring time comes. <br /><br />6. Developers will admit that brutal killing is not the only form of entertainment that people like.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
