<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22012"><title>Dark Salvation Teaser Trailer</title><posts><post id="p205348" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 5:25 am "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">As a lot of you may know, I've been on a very long hiatus and it's mainly been because I'm trying to complete the Dark Salvation project I started years back. It's amazing how long creating a game takes when you start from scratch with no money and an on and off development team, but things have changed and progressed tremendously despite any setbacks we've had and all the obstacles we've run into. Much has been done to the point of near completion on this project and it is starting to feel good. It's never hard to start a project nor even work on a project for a certain amount of time but the hardest thing you can ever do in game development is complete and release a project. I do believe we have created something that is a solid FPS shooter that is fun to play. While it does use a bit of dated Quake 3 Arena engine technology, we've made the engine look as good as it can for what it is and we didn't aim at beefing up the graphics renderer itself. The fun factor was the main goal.<br /><br />With that said we've released a teaser trailer in two flavors showing off some of the oil painted style of in game cinematics as well as some gameplay footage for some of the levels. Nothing too fancy, just a dark video to show what we've been up to for so long and a hint to what the game is about. So you can view the site and video normally but for kicks if you have a pair of Anaglyph 3D glasses handy, you can view the site and video in 3D. Just click the glasses in the bottom right hand corner.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: #BF0000">WARNING:</span></span> <span style="color: #BF0000">The video does contain some brutal gore &amp; violence, so if you are easily offended or disgusted do not click. Viewer discretion is advised.</span><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520/http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/teaser.html">http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/teaser.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />All feedback is welcome.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205358" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 9:09 am "><author>Ivan_the_B</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hard to give a feedback on few seconds of gameplay. <br />Anyhow, weapons seems fun and Q3 always looks good to me ( <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/icons/misc/heart.gif" alt="Image" /> ). <br />Hope monsters will offer some variety, in the video they are just moving around...<br /><br />It somehow reminds me painkiller... will it offer that kind of gameplay?<br /><br />Ps: the video took an eternity to load  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205360" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 9:51 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Devil's back!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /><br /><br />I'd like to see more ingame footages... <br />Same thing about video loading.<br /><br />Keep the good work anyway!<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205362" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 9:59 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Looks very good, Kiltron.<br /><br />Happy to see you're still in action. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205364" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 10:24 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The video felt a lot like B-movie horror. Where the head of the guy with the skull mask (or was that is real head?) explodes. Was quite amusing in a silly way. The game play shots though, didn't really give me anything to get interested about. <br /><br />Screenshots of the game I've seen are more vivid than that live action bit at the end.<br /><br />The animations of the weapons at least are quite stiff and don't really accommodate the action, and it gives me a bit of "Morrowind action" feel about it. (can't say anything about the monsters, though they just seemed to fall over and die the second you hit them) Then there's that place where the player are stepping around a sec or two, then looks up at the sky. That's a classic, "I have nothing better to show than this cool sky we made, look how it moves."<br /><br />I hope you'll succeed with this game. But this teaser, I don't think it teased me all that much.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205461" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 2:31 pm "><author>Tetzlaff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yes, the intro is very B-Movie like...<br />Gameplay footage is very short but so far I like what I see, environment reminds me to Quake1 and Painkiller. Will it be free exploration gameplay like in Quake1, or Painkiller style restrictive arena combat? Weapons look interesting, but I find it a bit weird that you get skeletal hands with one weapon.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205463" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 3:02 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Tetzlaff wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">but I find it a bit weird that you get skeletal hands with one weapon.</div><br />This is the player character... <br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/images/concept1.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />though I wonder what's up with the "Lacrimosa" fan in that image.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205465" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 4:24 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">looks like the player didn't listen to mom when she said it's BAD to put your hands in the fire.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />this game looks interesting to me.  Hoping it's fun, would like to see more gameplay footage though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205469" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 5:55 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I love how the game looks, When seeing media from this awhile back I assumed the project may have been dead.  I love the atmosphere the gameplay videos gives off.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205471" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 2:28 am "><author>TRSGM</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">AAAAAAAAAGH THEY'RE INVADING MY HOMETOWN</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205472" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 3:24 am "><author>MBolus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The intro reminds me of the local club, but the look and play remind me of some of the fun games of the '90s! <br /><br />Can't wait!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205479" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 9:34 am "><author>Tetzlaff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kristus wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">This is the player character... <br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520/http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/images/concept1.jpg">http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation ... ncept1.jpg</a><!-- m --><br /></div><br /><br />I see... don´t know what to say, it oscillates between weird, funny and... something else. So you are a white haired goth girl with skeletal hands.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205494" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 11:29 pm "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for the feeback everyone. I'll try and answer what I can.<br /><br />I really don't want to say the game plays like Quake or Painkiller since I don't want to really relate the games like that to one another, but you are correct in both aspects of the type of gameplay there is. You have open free exploration in some parts of levels while other parts have arena combat style of gameplay. It is definitely fast paced, probably just a tiny bit slower than Quake 3 Arena.<br /><br />As far as the monsters just falling over and dying, they actually have both death animations and/or gibbed deaths.<br /><br />Yes that is the main character. When you see her skeletal hands from the purple crystal she's carrying, that is the object she became possessed with when it approached her. When she touched it, it burnt off the flesh of her forearms while transferring it's power to her.<br /><br />Definitely oldschool fps gaming is exactly what we've aimed for.<br /><br />We are for sure working on putting together a more detailed video of just the gameplay which will be in the official trailer. This will be a much higher res video.<br /><br />With the buffering issues on playing the video, yeah we've noticed it and I believe it had something to do with the hosting package we originally had. I've contacted the host to upgrade the package to something that will allow more bandwidth for uninterrupted video streaming.<br /><br />I'm really looking forward to getting the pictures back of the real life model (shown in the upper right corner of the concept art) showing her in that outfit and releasing them to the public. I get a ****** just thinking about it! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205496" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 11:39 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kiltron wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"> <br />I'm really looking forward to getting the pictures back of the real life model (shown in the upper right corner of the concept art) showing her in that outfit and releasing them to the public. I get a ****** just thinking about it! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div><br /><br />I think I'll pass on that imagery.<br /><br />Say hi to my mom:<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://img407.imageshack.us/img407/1372/momms0.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205502" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 12:06 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That model is the main character, she's F***ING HOT.  My kinda girl heh. (NOT BRIAN'S MOM)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205519" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 5:44 am "><author>CrimsonHead</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I applaud what you're doing Kiltron. Dev time is so lengthy on beefier engines and there's the possibility of the team falling apart because of it, I have given thought myself many times to trying to do something artistically stylized in the q3 engine (or even the doomsday engine) for that very reason. There is a niche for it, look at all the people who still play CS for it's low requirements, you'll be reaching a larger audience than you would with something tech 4 and up.<br /><br />I'm looking forward to playing it already, I get that itch for some old school type action and it's a really dry genre these days. I like the overall aspect of what I saw, the levels look like scary nightmarish places but with a little twist of dark insanity almost reminiscent of something along the lines of <span style="font-style: italic">Alice</span>. I was a little iffy about the main character when I saw the concept pic, but then I saw how cool and unique the in game hand models looked and I think she will work if done just right. Watching the video I was reminded of the game Painkiller somewhat, but that is'nt necessarily a bad thing, and the games art style looks unique enough that I don't think anyone would use the word "clone" unless they were the usual unreasonable fanboy haters of all id engine games(I'm sure you've been around the Doom boards and read enough reviews to know who I'm talking about). Now that I really think about it...That is probably what draws me to it is looks like my type of game(like the kind of games I like: Doom, Quake, Painkiller, etc.), except it's fresh and new with cool looking new weapons and an intriguing character, and what looks like might possibly be a good story. Already I found myself asking questions, I want to know more about what's going on, what went wrong, etc. and that's what a good story or basic game scenario should do is pull you in and keep you gripped like that.<br /><br />It looks like you're headed in the right direction. We don't know eachother personally in real life, but we've been what I'd call pleasant acquaintances at the least on these boards for quite a number of years now, I feel happy for you right now and I'm proud Kiltron. I'll be watching and I'm looking forward to completion and finally playing it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205538" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 5:20 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ah-hem: "where's teh demo"?  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />What's the price point you're thinking of?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205556" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 11:00 pm "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks CrimsonHead, much appreciated! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />Not sure about a demo just yet Friar, but definitely the game will be a digital download under $15. Any retail boxed copies if we get to that point will be more naturally.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205557" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 11:23 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Is there a planned release date?  What is the name of that model <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203022520im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205563" date="Posted: Wed Oct 01, 2008 1:46 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">you have anyone to do your game trailer?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205611" date="Posted: Thu Oct 02, 2008 12:09 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">After I'm done working on a map for another team, I wouldn't mind modding for a game like that.  I still enjoy the quake 3 engine in it's simplicity.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205348" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 5:25 am "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">As a lot of you may know, I've been on a very long hiatus and it's mainly been because I'm trying to complete the Dark Salvation project I started years back. It's amazing how long creating a game takes when you start from scratch with no money and an on and off development team, but things have changed and progressed tremendously despite any setbacks we've had and all the obstacles we've run into. Much has been done to the point of near completion on this project and it is starting to feel good. It's never hard to start a project nor even work on a project for a certain amount of time but the hardest thing you can ever do in game development is complete and release a project. I do believe we have created something that is a solid FPS shooter that is fun to play. While it does use a bit of dated Quake 3 Arena engine technology, we've made the engine look as good as it can for what it is and we didn't aim at beefing up the graphics renderer itself. The fun factor was the main goal.<br /><br />With that said we've released a teaser trailer in two flavors showing off some of the oil painted style of in game cinematics as well as some gameplay footage for some of the levels. Nothing too fancy, just a dark video to show what we've been up to for so long and a hint to what the game is about. So you can view the site and video normally but for kicks if you have a pair of Anaglyph 3D glasses handy, you can view the site and video in 3D. Just click the glasses in the bottom right hand corner.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: #BF0000">WARNING:</span></span> <span style="color: #BF0000">The video does contain some brutal gore &amp; violence, so if you are easily offended or disgusted do not click. Viewer discretion is advised.</span><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006/http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/teaser.html">http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/teaser.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />All feedback is welcome.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205358" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 9:09 am "><author>Ivan_the_B</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hard to give a feedback on few seconds of gameplay. <br />Anyhow, weapons seems fun and Q3 always looks good to me ( <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/icons/misc/heart.gif" alt="Image" /> ). <br />Hope monsters will offer some variety, in the video they are just moving around...<br /><br />It somehow reminds me painkiller... will it offer that kind of gameplay?<br /><br />Ps: the video took an eternity to load  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205360" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 9:51 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Devil's back!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /><br /><br />I'd like to see more ingame footages... <br />Same thing about video loading.<br /><br />Keep the good work anyway!<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205362" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 9:59 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Looks very good, Kiltron.<br /><br />Happy to see you're still in action. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205364" date="Posted: Fri Sep 26, 2008 10:24 am "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The video felt a lot like B-movie horror. Where the head of the guy with the skull mask (or was that is real head?) explodes. Was quite amusing in a silly way. The game play shots though, didn't really give me anything to get interested about. <br /><br />Screenshots of the game I've seen are more vivid than that live action bit at the end.<br /><br />The animations of the weapons at least are quite stiff and don't really accommodate the action, and it gives me a bit of "Morrowind action" feel about it. (can't say anything about the monsters, though they just seemed to fall over and die the second you hit them) Then there's that place where the player are stepping around a sec or two, then looks up at the sky. That's a classic, "I have nothing better to show than this cool sky we made, look how it moves."<br /><br />I hope you'll succeed with this game. But this teaser, I don't think it teased me all that much.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205461" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 2:31 pm "><author>Tetzlaff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yes, the intro is very B-Movie like...<br />Gameplay footage is very short but so far I like what I see, environment reminds me to Quake1 and Painkiller. Will it be free exploration gameplay like in Quake1, or Painkiller style restrictive arena combat? Weapons look interesting, but I find it a bit weird that you get skeletal hands with one weapon.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205463" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 3:02 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Tetzlaff wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">but I find it a bit weird that you get skeletal hands with one weapon.</div><br />This is the player character... <br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/images/concept1.jpg" alt="Image" /><br />though I wonder what's up with the "Lacrimosa" fan in that image.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205465" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 4:24 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">looks like the player didn't listen to mom when she said it's BAD to put your hands in the fire.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />this game looks interesting to me.  Hoping it's fun, would like to see more gameplay footage though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205469" date="Posted: Sun Sep 28, 2008 5:55 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I love how the game looks, When seeing media from this awhile back I assumed the project may have been dead.  I love the atmosphere the gameplay videos gives off.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205471" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 2:28 am "><author>TRSGM</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">AAAAAAAAAGH THEY'RE INVADING MY HOMETOWN</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205472" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 3:24 am "><author>MBolus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The intro reminds me of the local club, but the look and play remind me of some of the fun games of the '90s! <br /><br />Can't wait!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205479" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 9:34 am "><author>Tetzlaff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kristus wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">This is the player character... <br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006/http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation/images/concept1.jpg">http://www.mangledeye.com/darksalvation ... ncept1.jpg</a><!-- m --><br /></div><br /><br />I see... don´t know what to say, it oscillates between weird, funny and... something else. So you are a white haired goth girl with skeletal hands.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205494" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 11:29 pm "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for the feeback everyone. I'll try and answer what I can.<br /><br />I really don't want to say the game plays like Quake or Painkiller since I don't want to really relate the games like that to one another, but you are correct in both aspects of the type of gameplay there is. You have open free exploration in some parts of levels while other parts have arena combat style of gameplay. It is definitely fast paced, probably just a tiny bit slower than Quake 3 Arena.<br /><br />As far as the monsters just falling over and dying, they actually have both death animations and/or gibbed deaths.<br /><br />Yes that is the main character. When you see her skeletal hands from the purple crystal she's carrying, that is the object she became possessed with when it approached her. When she touched it, it burnt off the flesh of her forearms while transferring it's power to her.<br /><br />Definitely oldschool fps gaming is exactly what we've aimed for.<br /><br />We are for sure working on putting together a more detailed video of just the gameplay which will be in the official trailer. This will be a much higher res video.<br /><br />With the buffering issues on playing the video, yeah we've noticed it and I believe it had something to do with the hosting package we originally had. I've contacted the host to upgrade the package to something that will allow more bandwidth for uninterrupted video streaming.<br /><br />I'm really looking forward to getting the pictures back of the real life model (shown in the upper right corner of the concept art) showing her in that outfit and releasing them to the public. I get a ****** just thinking about it! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205496" date="Posted: Mon Sep 29, 2008 11:39 pm "><author>Brain Trepaning</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kiltron wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"> <br />I'm really looking forward to getting the pictures back of the real life model (shown in the upper right corner of the concept art) showing her in that outfit and releasing them to the public. I get a ****** just thinking about it! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div><br /><br />I think I'll pass on that imagery.<br /><br />Say hi to my mom:<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://img407.imageshack.us/img407/1372/momms0.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205502" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 12:06 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That model is the main character, she's F***ING HOT.  My kinda girl heh. (NOT BRIAN'S MOM)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205519" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 5:44 am "><author>CrimsonHead</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I applaud what you're doing Kiltron. Dev time is so lengthy on beefier engines and there's the possibility of the team falling apart because of it, I have given thought myself many times to trying to do something artistically stylized in the q3 engine (or even the doomsday engine) for that very reason. There is a niche for it, look at all the people who still play CS for it's low requirements, you'll be reaching a larger audience than you would with something tech 4 and up.<br /><br />I'm looking forward to playing it already, I get that itch for some old school type action and it's a really dry genre these days. I like the overall aspect of what I saw, the levels look like scary nightmarish places but with a little twist of dark insanity almost reminiscent of something along the lines of <span style="font-style: italic">Alice</span>. I was a little iffy about the main character when I saw the concept pic, but then I saw how cool and unique the in game hand models looked and I think she will work if done just right. Watching the video I was reminded of the game Painkiller somewhat, but that is'nt necessarily a bad thing, and the games art style looks unique enough that I don't think anyone would use the word "clone" unless they were the usual unreasonable fanboy haters of all id engine games(I'm sure you've been around the Doom boards and read enough reviews to know who I'm talking about). Now that I really think about it...That is probably what draws me to it is looks like my type of game(like the kind of games I like: Doom, Quake, Painkiller, etc.), except it's fresh and new with cool looking new weapons and an intriguing character, and what looks like might possibly be a good story. Already I found myself asking questions, I want to know more about what's going on, what went wrong, etc. and that's what a good story or basic game scenario should do is pull you in and keep you gripped like that.<br /><br />It looks like you're headed in the right direction. We don't know eachother personally in real life, but we've been what I'd call pleasant acquaintances at the least on these boards for quite a number of years now, I feel happy for you right now and I'm proud Kiltron. I'll be watching and I'm looking forward to completion and finally playing it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205538" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 5:20 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ah-hem: "where's teh demo"?  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />What's the price point you're thinking of?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205556" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 11:00 pm "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks CrimsonHead, much appreciated! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />Not sure about a demo just yet Friar, but definitely the game will be a digital download under $15. Any retail boxed copies if we get to that point will be more naturally.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205557" date="Posted: Tue Sep 30, 2008 11:23 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Is there a planned release date?  What is the name of that model <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081203055006im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205563" date="Posted: Wed Oct 01, 2008 1:46 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">you have anyone to do your game trailer?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205611" date="Posted: Thu Oct 02, 2008 12:09 am "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">After I'm done working on a map for another team, I wouldn't mind modding for a game like that.  I still enjoy the quake 3 engine in it's simplicity.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
