<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22121"><title>Fallout 3</title><posts><post id="p206793" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 4:02 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">anyone want to share opinions on this one?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206795" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 4:14 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I will after it's released tomorrow <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113073407im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206807" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 5:46 pm "><author>Speedy</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">oblivion with guns!   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113073407im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p206808" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 5:58 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm going to be picking this one up in a few days once I beat Far Cry 2... it looks massive and impressive... the graphics aren't quite as top-notch as, say Crysis, Far Cry 2 or Mass Effect... it seems like some of the models have lower poly-counts than I would have hoped, but the game is dripping in atmosphere and I don't need visuals to be perfect if the story and gameplay are decent.<br /><br />The Gametrailers narrator mentions in his video review that the game packs in so much stuff that it can be overwhelming.  I actually love this notion... he basically says it's daunting to try to get to everything in one character's play-through, which to me translates to replay-ability freshness.  For example, I'm the kind of person who's replayed Mass Effect and tried to choose missions, squad-mates and dialog options that were sort of the opposite from my first play-through style and I've enjoyed it quite a bit.<br /><br />From what I've read and seen about Fallout 3, the dialog seems a little cheesy at times.  I don't mind it for a straight up FPS like Far Cry 2 or Crysis, but an RPG... not sure about that.<br /><br />I also like the "target body part" 3rd-person cam action/battle system idea... I still need to read a bit more on how it works but it "looks cool" so far from what I can tell.<br /><br />Again, this is all based on the reading and video reviews and footage that I've seen... I won't have a chance to play the game 'til November.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206812" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 7:23 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">oops. i thought it was out since there are a bunch of very positive reviews out...<br /><br />kotaku has a nice succinct review:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113073407/http://kotaku.com/5070394/fallout-3-review-wasting-away-again-in-radiationville">http://kotaku.com/5070394/fallout-3-rev ... ationville</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p206816" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 8:41 pm "><author>mavrik65</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's looking pretty good pc gamer said it's not as good as oblivion but it's worth buying. The thing with rpg's is that I get bored of the freedom before I "complete" the game and grinding to me sounds so pointless, imho games are about relaxing and having fun not working by doing the same repetitive task over and over. The graphics seem to be what I expect of a modern game not too amazing but not out dated. I've seen graphics like that on most 360 games, it definitely ain't crysis. But on the plus side they've made the game gorey which is brilliant because there hasn't been that many gorey games since aliens vs predator 2. And gore just gives a game that finer degree of destruction. And destruction is what it's all about <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113073407im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206830" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 10:21 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">On the topic of recent releases: For the love of god, if you have a 360, pick up Fable 2! It's probably one of the most emotionally engaging games I've played in a long time, and they really know how to press your buttons as a player (commit an evil act or LOSE EXPERIENCE, or BECOME UGLY? Playing a good character never was so hard in a game before <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113073407im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" />). I'd say it's probably as close to a good story as you can get without the protagonist actually having a personality.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206833" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 11:18 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yah, Fable 2's on my list too... heh damn, a lotta decent games out there in the last few weeks.  Christmas is early!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206834" date="Posted: Wed Oct 29, 2008 11:40 pm "><author>Mordenkainen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">In the future, nukes will even obliterate the laws of physics as demonstrated by F3's apparent lack of any shadows.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207012" date="Posted: Sat Nov 01, 2008 4:06 pm "><author>DoomUK</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Speedy wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">oblivion with guns!</div><br /><br />This is pretty much what it amounts to.  If it wasn't for the sheer scale of the game, you'd be forgiven for thinking is was some sort of elaborate TC.<br /><br />Discount the slightly quirky voice acting and it's a great game, though.  Just like Oblivion was.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207016" date="Posted: Sat Nov 01, 2008 9:09 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">is this more RPG like Oblivion or FPS like Stalker?  I'm not interested in a RPG-shooter, I'd rather play an FPs with RPG elements.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207017" date="Posted: Sat Nov 01, 2008 9:44 pm "><author>DoomUK</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">is this more RPG like Oblivion or FPS like Stalker?</div><br /><br />The former.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207062" date="Posted: Sun Nov 02, 2008 10:32 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I picked it up tonight.  $40 @ target.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207123" date="Posted: Tue Nov 04, 2008 3:14 pm "><author>qwertz123</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Speedy wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">oblivion with guns!   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113073407im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div><br /><br /><br />oblivion without shadows.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207125" date="Posted: Tue Nov 04, 2008 3:28 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I am playing Fallout 3 with no preconceptions whatsoever, my only experience with RPG's is Mass Effect, and I never played Oblivion.<br />I keep hearing there are 'no shadows' in FO3, I guess this must be an issue with their particular systems, as I have shadows and everything looks pretty good to me. <br /><br />Not having played Oblivion 3 I didn't know what to expect and so far I like what I've seen. I think Mass Effect is a little more balanced over all but that's hardly noticeable. All in all I like the experience of Fallout 3. The graphics are pretty sweet and the overall mood of it all is as grim as I'd like it to be.<br /><br />All in all 8/10, so far.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207129" date="Posted: Tue Nov 04, 2008 4:41 pm "><author>Mordenkainen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BloodRayne wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I keep hearing there are 'no shadows' in FO3, I guess this must be an issue with their particular systems, as I have shadows and everything looks pretty good to me.</div><br /><br />Can you take a screenie please? To be clear, this refers to shadows cast static geometry.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207133" date="Posted: Tue Nov 04, 2008 5:09 pm "><author>rebb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I don't really mind the Fallout 3 Graphics, the game makes up for it with it's "inner values".<br />Exploration in this game is actually more fun for me than it was in Oblivion - as there's more to find than just potions and swords, and many areas tell their own little stories.<br /><br />So far i haven't progressed far into the main storyline - just enjoying the countryside and fresh air <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113073407im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207141" date="Posted: Tue Nov 04, 2008 6:58 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i've tried all different setting &amp; can't get structure shadows, can't get entity shadows for the most part either.  Only thing making the game "look" bad is the lack of some depth because of the lack of shadows.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207198" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 8:43 pm "><author>Speedy</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">only chars cast shadows<br />and yes, the lighting is shitty, especially when you dont get a direct sun/moon light, just a dull ambient.  <br /><br />game is cool. huge world to explore  - been playing for 30+ hrs</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
