<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22147"><title>Seeing camera flashes, but no camera around?</title><posts><post id="p207162" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 7:24 am "><author>ajm113</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm really starting to get very curious on what is going on here since I am noticing it more. But for some odd reason, even during the day or night which is kinda rare sometimes. I see a flash of light and a flare if I have a view of it. The wired thing too is that it's projecting shadows sometimes and actually casting light, it kinda looks like a camera flash.<br /><br />Tonight as I just was walking back up stairs I noticed the flare flash outside of the front door, and the glass isn't very clear from a distance and the 'flash' was kinda blurred out and small through the window. I looked of course no one and it's 11 PM.<br /><br />One other night I believe I was going to my window and closing the curtains and I notice a flash in the dark in the backyard of my neighbors and I swore I seen the ray of light hitting on the sides of my window.<br /><br />I get the feeling now since I am noticing it that someone is fallowing me, but wired thing too is that I notice it in the most random places sometimes, I don't really know what is wrong... <br /><br />I know D3W isn't a 'medical' forum, but perhaps with intelligent users I can get some info what to do or someone else experiences with this?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207164" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 10:55 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Try to catch it on film, use your cellular. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113044730im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p207165" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 12:01 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Maybe you got a tumor?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207166" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 12:21 pm "><author>rebb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Cars driving by that reflect the light from another source to where you are maybe ?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207167" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 12:37 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I wouldn't say its a tumor if you can see shadows resulting from the light. I'd say you are halucinating. Did you recently change your drug consumption or are you on serious medication?<br /><br />Let someone else see it too before declaring yourself sane again!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207169" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 1:47 pm "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Perhaps you're at that crossover point from reality vs. virtual reality.<br /><br />What I'm saying is, compare how much time you spend in reality as apposed to how much you spend in VR. (playing FPS games or games in general but more so FPS games)<br /><br />If you spend more time in VR than in reality, your brain starts thinking you're in VR at times when you are in reality and some of the effects (realtime lighting, shadow casting, etc.) found in today's FPS games feel like they're happening in regular reality (though they really are, the brain is thinking it is happening from and in VR)<br /><br />And no, I'm not kidding.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207172" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 3:04 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This used to happen to me a lot when i was younger, but there has been times that people I am with notice it to.  My theory, a very high-tech pedo is on your tail, snatching photos.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207173" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 3:43 pm "><author>lowdragon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You would notice pervs just like that couse they (imho) wouldnt care about your awareness`ness (not a word but still :) - <br />there is another possibility which you will not like to hear/read. Sorry, but did you hear about the "one pixel error" on flatscreen monitors - i suggest you visit an eye doctor if it keeps happening. <br />It may be just the "eyes too tired but didnt recognise thing" - heh, iam not too good with the medical english.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207177" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 3:58 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Jack Rammsdell wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">This used to happen to me a lot when i was younger, but there has been times that people I am with notice it to.  My theory, a very high-tech pedo is on your tail, snatching photos.</div> <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113044730im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113044730im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113044730im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /> n1.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207178" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 4:06 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113044730/http://www.allaboutvision.com/conditions/retinadetach.htm">http://www.allaboutvision.com/condition ... detach.htm</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081113044730/http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photopsia">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Photopsia</a><!-- m --><br /><br />retina detachment can cause flashes of light.<br /><br />so can migraine headaches.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207191" date="Posted: Wed Nov 05, 2008 7:00 pm "><author>ajm113</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah, don't think it can be a car if it happens in none areas of where cars move or any reflections of light.<br /><br />I don't know if its the games or the systems of games, but it seems my dad see's them once. My parents smoke a lot, like 24 hrs a day, idk if its part of the problem.<br /><br />Sorry that I can't respond to everyone, but I am in a rush. I'll look at the link later today, since I am still at school..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207311" date="Posted: Fri Nov 07, 2008 9:51 pm "><author>CrimsonHead</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I actually have experienced visual hallucinations from a migraine headache, it's nothing like what you are describing though, I saw bright silvery shining fireflies swimming around, they almost looked like silver sperm cells for lack of a better description, aside from that the pain is so overwhelming it made me physically sick and nauseus. <br /><br />Do you get enough sleep at night? Are you eating like you should? You don't have to answer of course, but have you done anything to invite law enforcement surveillance?  I'm leaning towards the phenomenon being one of those three since you are'nt alluding to any other symptoms such as dizzyness or pain. You could always hire a private detective and discover for certain if someone is spying on or stalking you.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207313" date="Posted: Fri Nov 07, 2008 10:00 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">This happened to my friend before, but he died soon after he told people online about it...</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
