<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22157"><title>Help: Error: multiple entitity's named 123_head</title><posts><post id="p207327" date="Posted: Sat Nov 08, 2008 5:22 pm "><author>jankee7777</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">heej everybody,<br /><br />I have been working on a map just like the maps in lms. i've tested the map and it worked fine, but when I'am playing with my mates they get disconnected.(when zsec are spawned in the game) They get the error: multiple entitity's named 123_head. (or something like that.)<br /><br />I search on this forum but i haven't founded a solution. <br /><br />Maybe this helps: I have 4 zsec guys that spawn in the game, but they haven't got heads. If have tried to copy the zsec from the orignally lms maps, but that has no effect. Everything the error comes up.<br /><br />I have used my own def files, but the only changes i have made are the names and the heads. (I can see them but my mates can't)<br />I think that's the reason why LMS havent use much zsec in their LMS maps.<br /><br />All of the entitity's have networkSync 1 on them. <br /><br />If I remove the zsec my map runs perfectly. <br /><br />Can somebody help me plz?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207329" date="Posted: Sat Nov 08, 2008 7:15 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The standard D3 netcode doesn't sync heads, which is probably why LMS don't use that entity. I know the OpenCoop team did a lot of work in getting heads to sync correctly for their player selector, so I don't think there is anything you can do just in the map. Would need SDK work so that would be for the LMS team.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207332" date="Posted: Sat Nov 08, 2008 8:20 pm "><author>jankee7777</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thank you, simulation for your reply.<br /><br />Now I know that it isn't possible and that saves me a lot of time. I think I will replace the zsec with a couple of commando's holding a chaingun with the same health als a zsec.<br /><br />I have 1 more question: Is it possible to change the model of your character in MP (standard a marine) into a model of a securityguy ?<br />(the one that isn't yet infected/zombie.)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207334" date="Posted: Sat Nov 08, 2008 8:54 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">jankee7777 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I have 1 more question: Is it possible to change the model of your character in MP (standard a marine) into a model of a securityguy ?<br />(the one that isn't yet infected/zombie.)</div><br />Yes, it is possible. EMZ allows you to select from several models in MP...<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103744/http://www.the-emz.com/d3emz131/">http://www.the-emz.com/d3emz131/</a><!-- m --> (scroll down to Player Models, Skin Colours and Skin Types)<br /><br />To make the model selectable you would need SDK work. If you were happy to have the same model for all players you could do it without SDK work. You would need to edit the defintion of model_mp_marine to use an alterative mesh and skin. The mesh has to be based on the same skeleton as the standard MP marine.<br /><br />In the standard SDK install for D3 there is a folder called "base\animation" which contains 7 additional md5mesh files (mp_security.md5mesh, etc). These are rigged to the standard MP skeleton but don't have heads so you'd have the same problem that you had with the zsec. However, I have made versions of most these with heads which you can download from <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20081120103744/http://www.the-emz.com/download/mpmodels.zip" class="postlink">http://www.the-emz.com/download/mpmodels.zip</a>.<br /><br />That said, if you're simply making a new MP map (rather than an entire mod) then I don't think you should be altering the player def files; could mess with other things unintentionaly.<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207335" date="Posted: Sat Nov 08, 2008 9:12 pm "><author>jankee7777</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">simulation,<br /><br />I have noticed that you said that I most change a def file. (mp.def)<br />I think that a little bit dangerous to alter the files, because it will screw up LMS.<br />Can I created a new character and place them next to the orignally doom3. (like LMS did)<br />It haven't to be in the main gui or the hud gui. <br />Maybe that I am calling it from the console (maybe with: playermodel security_guy_mp)<br />Can you help me with this or can you give me a tutorial of some other thing ?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207336" date="Posted: Sat Nov 08, 2008 9:23 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">jankee7777 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">simulation,<br /><br />I have noticed that you said that I most change a def file. (mp.def)<br />I think that a little bit dangerous to alter the files, because it will screw up LMS.<br />Can I created a new character and place them next to the orignally doom3. (like LMS did)<br />It haven't to be in the main gui or the hud gui. <br />Maybe that I am calling it from the console (maybe with: playermodel security_guy_mp)<br />Can you help me with this or can you give me a tutorial of some other thing ?</div><br /><br />Yes, thats why I said "That said, if you're simply making a new MP map (rather than an entire mod) then I don't think you should be altering the player def files; could mess with other things unintentionaly."<br /><br />You won't be able to add stuff to play with LMS in that way. You'd need to create your own mod for that.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
