<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22207"><title>Source: Quake 3 ported to c++ with radiant built in.</title><posts><post id="p207919" date="Posted: Fri Nov 28, 2008 6:44 pm "><author>eviltwigflipper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Me and my friends were working on a project, and one of them went on active duty im not going to let our code go to waste, im going to finish it up as a "idtech3 to idtech4" type project.<br /><br />Basically I ported Quake 3 to C++ with Radiant build in as a command(type editor in the console).  The windows do come up black i havent fixed that yet, but I wanted to post this out to the community to see what type of feedback I get.  Im going to be uploading a wiki and a bored for the code but I wanted to post it here to see what every one thought.<br /><br /><!-- w --><a class="postlink" href="/web/20081204032802/http://www.jminteractive.net/source.zip">http://www.jminteractive.net/source.zip</a><!-- w --><br /><br />You need to download the fmod dll's.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207921" date="Posted: Fri Nov 28, 2008 6:53 pm "><author>aardwolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">nice job, but why does it need the propietary fmod?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207922" date="Posted: Fri Nov 28, 2008 6:57 pm "><author>eviltwigflipper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I was ditching the sound system at the time and fmod was the quickest way to get ogg support into our game.  Ill upload a quick fix for the game using UserInterface_Shared.cpp, it should just be using jmUIManager, ill fix that and upload it.<br /><br />And jmNetManager needs to be redone as well, ill upload a nicer code base in a bit, i had to move the gentity_t structure over there and I don't like the way I did it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207927" date="Posted: Sat Nov 29, 2008 2:14 am "><author>eviltwigflipper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I uploaded a new version of the source code it messes up the menu UI system a little bit, but the UserInterface_Shared.cpp is not no longer in game, and all the UI functions are called from jmUIManager.  And now menus.txt, hud.txt and the other ones are now deprecated.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207932" date="Posted: Sat Nov 29, 2008 4:04 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Uhm, isn't it illegal to use FMod with Quake3? It's got conflicting licenses. Quake3 is GPL and FMod proprietary.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207933" date="Posted: Sat Nov 29, 2008 5:12 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <div class="quotetitle">fmod wrote:</div>
  <div class="quotecontent">FMOD Non-Commercial License<br /><br />If your product is not intended for commercial gain and does not include the FMOD library for resale, license or other commercial distribution, then use of FMOD is free. Yes that's right, free from license fees!.</div>
  <br />
  <br />
  <a href="/web/20081204032802/http://www.fmod.org/index.php/sales" class="postlink">http://www.fmod.org/index.php/sales</a>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207934" date="Posted: Sat Nov 29, 2008 5:20 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">GPL allows commercial exploitation.  Unless they give it away with no license restrictions (including the ability to use it commercially) it's not compatible with the GPL.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207938" date="Posted: Sat Nov 29, 2008 6:46 pm "><author>eviltwigflipper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I plan on removing FMod from the engine, it was just a quick way to get ogg support for the game.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207939" date="Posted: Sat Nov 29, 2008 8:20 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it's technically not illegal if you never release the engine in any form.  <img src="/web/20081204032802im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />I think there's even work around you could do if you wanted to use it.  IE compiling a separate sound dll &amp; using that.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207941" date="Posted: Sat Nov 29, 2008 8:25 pm "><author>eviltwigflipper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There is alot of work that needs to be done with it but basically here is a break down of the engine:<br /><br />Cgame and Game are now merged into one module,<br />UI is in the engine.<br />botlib was renamed to aaslib.<br /><br />jmCommon									*common;<br />jmCollisionModelManager					*collisionModelManager;<br />jmSoundManager							*sound;<br />jmRenderer								*renderer;<br />botlib_export_t							*botlib;<br />jmFileManager							*fileManager;<br />jmNetManager								*network;<br />jmUIManager								*ui;<br /><br />radiant can be called by typing editor in the console.<br /><br />Im going to put up a wiki soon and a phpbb board, but what do you guys think do you think its useful?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207966" date="Posted: Sun Nov 30, 2008 9:55 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I downloaded the source code, setup my compiler and I get errors trying to compile it. <br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">fatal error RC1015: cannot open include file 'afxres.h'.</div><br /><br />Just missing an include file.  I have done some research and I cannot figure out what sdk the afxres.h comes in.  What else does the solution require to compile.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207970" date="Posted: Mon Dec 01, 2008 2:14 am "><author>eviltwigflipper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Its compiles under Visual Studio 2005, your probley compiling against 2003 or lower.  You need to rename afxres to something else I dont know off hand what it is.  Or your compiling with Visual Studio express and that doesn't really work either but MFC does come in the Windows SDK, but the IDE doesn't support resource editing AND it wont work "out of the box", read this.<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="/web/20081204032802/http://forums.microsoft.com/MSDN/ShowPost.aspx?siteid=1&amp;PostID=362656">http://forums.microsoft.com/MSDN/ShowPo ... tID=362656</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Google is your friend : ).<br /><br />You can take out radiant if you want, replace the old resource from GPL quake 3, comment out the editor command, delete the radiant project.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207972" date="Posted: Mon Dec 01, 2008 12:22 pm "><author>lowdragon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thx for your work on this - you turned the renderer to directX and not just the input, right ?<br /><br />[somewhat offtopic]<br />Iam not going to disrespect or downgrading you with offering my help <img src="/web/20081204032802im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /> (how could i) but you are aware of <a href="/web/20081204032802/http://www.rfactory.org/aiscript.html" class="postlink">the SP addons</a> [...]<br /><br />Addíng the editor is nice (i remember using inGame flare and entity editors added to the gamecode) but i think further - if/how it would be extended.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207975" date="Posted: Mon Dec 01, 2008 6:33 pm "><author>aardwolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">So, i take it it will be necessary to use object oriented programming to modidy this new quake3++, right?  Seems useful.  And, are there any improvements, like speed wise, stability, visual eye candy, etc?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207976" date="Posted: Mon Dec 01, 2008 7:52 pm "><author>Jack Rammsdell</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">eviltwigflipper wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Its compiles under Visual Studio 2005, your probley compiling against 2003 or lower.  You need to rename afxres to something else I dont know off hand what it is.  Or your compiling with Visual Studio express and that doesn't really work either but MFC does come in the Windows SDK, but the IDE doesn't support resource editing AND it wont work "out of the box", read this.<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="/web/20081204032802/http://forums.microsoft.com/MSDN/ShowPost.aspx?siteid=1&amp;PostID=362656">http://forums.microsoft.com/MSDN/ShowPo ... tID=362656</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Google is your friend : ).<br /><br />You can take out radiant if you want, replace the old resource from GPL quake 3, comment out the editor command, delete the radiant project.</div><br /><br />I am only interested in the built in radiant editor,  I made a very elemental mistake of not installed the windows platform sdk.  I googled it previously and I read that the file was no longer included in the mfc pack.  I will try to recompile it once I get the sdk.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p207994" date="Posted: Tue Dec 02, 2008 8:55 pm "><author>eviltwigflipper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I finally got radiant to run in a seperate thread.  Ill upload the code in a little bit.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
