<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22372"><title>Sandbox Top 100 Finalist at MODDB, VOTE PLEASE! + 2.3 Patch</title><posts><post id="p210142" date="Posted: Tue Jan 20, 2009 6:21 pm "><author>calimer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">PLEASE VOTE FOR US AGAIN!!!!! I'm so excited to announce that out of over 5,000 game projects and 58,736 votes Sandbox has made it as a finalist, ranked as one of the top 100!!  Now begins a second round of voting so please consider voting for us again!  The more reputation we are able to get the more kids, and adults, we can get this project to!  Please see the top of our moddb profile for instructions:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="/web/20090125083531/http://www.moddb.com/games/platinum-arts-sandbox">http://www.moddb.com/games/platinum-arts-sandbox</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Platinum Arts Sandbox is an open source easy to use standalone Free 3D Game Maker and 3D Game Design program currently being used in many schools throughout the world that allows kids and adults to create their own video games, worlds, levels, save the princess adventures and quests, even cooperatively! The goal is to make it accessible to kids but also powerful enough for full game projects.  In the words of Margaret, a nine year old Sandbox whiz I babysit for, “Press Edit and go fulfill your dreams!”. Now features new game modes such as Save The Princess, sidescroller, machinima, kartmode, RPG, and more!  Our homepage is Kids.PlatinumArts.Net<br /><br />We have a new patch for our popular Save The Princess maps!  Please go to our download page:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="/web/20090125083531/http://kids.platinumarts.net/download-sandbox.html">http://kids.platinumarts.net/download-sandbox.html</a><!-- m --><br />Extract these files into your /packages/base folder and replace the existing files!  This should fix some bugs that were making the maps not act how they should <img src="/web/20090125083531im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />  As a note the maps have been considered quite challenging!!  Do you have what it takes to save the most beautiful princess in the world?<br /><br />In addition we have recently been featured at a Linux Conference in Australia! Miniconf was an awesome experience because I was able to give the talk over Skype to our folk from down under!  For more information about the the conference here is a listing of the presentations:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="/web/20090125083531/http://games.sericyb.com.au/">http://games.sericyb.com.au/</a><!-- m -->  Check our homepage for a picture of the happy audience <img src="/web/20090125083531im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />If you are unfamiliar with Sandbox be sure to check out our tutorial video!!  I'm quite amazed actually at how many messages I get a day regarding Sandbox because of the video <img src="/web/20090125083531im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="/web/20090125083531/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g44Ww2bg2_E">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g44Ww2bg2_E</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Thank you everyone for your interest and support of Sandbox!  I am still going crazy in excitement that we made it into the top 100!!  Thank you so much everyone who voted!!!!  Take care.<br />-mike<br />Kids.PlatinumArts.net</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
