<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22382"><title>Der_ton md5 exporter says: Unable to convert: ... Modifier</title><posts><post id="p210245" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 10:16 am "><author>nanar77</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hello everybody,<br /><br />I'm a coder and not a graphist. It is the first time I use 3DS Max and after having tried a tutorial, I tried to export my work to MD5. I got the error: -- Unable to convert: undefined to type: Modifier<br /><br />Can somebody help me?<br /><br />Regards,<br />Bernard.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210248" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 11:29 am "><author>6th Venom</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi Bernard!<br />You must export an editable mesh (and no poly, patch or spline, etc) that have a skin modifier for animation.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210253" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 2:12 pm "><author>nanar77</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thank you for your advice, I found a solution but I need to be sure that it is the "correct" way:<br /><br />I tried to add a Skin modifier and to add all the joints of my skeleton in the envelope. My modifier list was:<br />+Skin<br />+Physique<br />+Editable Mesh<br /><br />It worked!<br /><br />Is it the correct way?<br />If it is, please der_ton, could you add a sample of a modifier list in the readme? It could be good for ultra newbies like me.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210258" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 2:47 pm "><author>Neurological</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You have to collapse the Physique modifier to the mesh or won't take effect. You need just Editable Mesh and Skin. Then when exporting select Skin.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210263" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 4:55 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">is there a reason you require a skin from 3ds max?  Blender just had the bones+mesh.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210265" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 5:40 pm "><author>Neurological</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yeah the Skin modifier is where all the bones weights are stored. Without it will give an error on exporting.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210266" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 6:19 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">ok, so it's like weight painting in blender.  got ya.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210267" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 6:21 pm "><author>nanar77</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good explanations, thanks. As strange as it could be, having a stack like the one below works. Surely that I did something that makes the Physique modifier useless... I'll try to remove it.<br />+Skin<br />+Physique<br />+Editable Mesh<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">is there a reason you require a skin from 3ds max? Blender just had the bones+mesh.</div><br />As a newbie in the field, I prefer to use Max because to me, Blender is a little repulsive, I don't understand anything. I know that there are a lot of good books for Max so I'll start 3D with it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p210268" date="Posted: Fri Jan 23, 2009 6:37 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">nanar77 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">As a newbie in the field, I prefer to use Max because to me, Blender is a little repulsive, I don't understand anything. I know that there are a lot of good books for Max so I'll start 3D with it.</div><br /><br />Sorry, wasn't intended towards you, was intended towards those who answered your question.  I was wondering why blender didn't need that step.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
