<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22778"><title>Problem in the second recycling level</title><posts><post id="p214225" date="Posted: Mon May 04, 2009 11:27 am "><author>Shinra</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I won't bother posting my machine specs here, since I feel it has little to do with the issue at hand.<br /><br />So anyway, hi, I have this teeny problem at hand:<br /><br />During the second level of the recycling plant, or whatever it was named, at the very beginning you go into a small room where Betruger has a chat with you once you activate the pump.<br /><br />So, my problem is as follows: when the video with Betruger plays, I can see the video, but there is no sound coming from it. Betruger talks and talks, or at least appears to, but I don't hear a thing from him. All other voices work perfectly well at all times.<br /><br />Being not the least of my problems, after he is done talking, the door I came in refuses to open. Like, completely. I'm totally stuck in the small room, with no apparent means to get out. And this of course, sucks, since I can't advance in the game.<br /><br />It should also be noted that I am playing the exact same copy on the exact same machine I have used to play it through previously, with no such problems. Only thing differing here is that I now have a different hard disk.<br /><br />I tried uninstalling and reinstalling the game from my own copy and loading from the beginning of the level, and I even tried installing from a different copy of the game, but it still refuses to work.<br /><br />So. Any ideas?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214227" date="Posted: Mon May 04, 2009 12:05 pm "><author>Neurological</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">After the betruger video try opening the console, there you will see the error. Then report it here so we can look at it. But it sound like a missing sound. Does the imp break the glass after the video?<br /><br />Also in what language are you playing?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214229" date="Posted: Mon May 04, 2009 1:15 pm "><author>Shinra</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Right then, took me a while to find out how to bring out the console n_n<br /><br />Anyway, at the start of the level, the console gives out 3 warnings:<br /><br />"WARNING: Couldn't load image: guisurfs/hazard1:1<br />WARNING: Couldn't load model: 'models/mapobjects/recycle/recycwallight_broken.ase'<br />WARNING: Couldn't load sound: 'guisounds.wav' using default<br /><br />3 warnings"<br /><br />That would be what the console states out.<br /><br />As to your other queries:<br /><br />The imp doesn't break anything. It crawls across the window during the video (and goddamn did it get me &gt;.&lt;), but after disappearing, it is not heard from again. I am completely stuck in the room. T_T<br /><br />Also, I am playing it on English.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
