<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22771"><title>Nvidia forever!</title><posts><post id="p214175" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 12:24 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">After just 4 months of instabilities, poor driver updates and incompatibility my ATI HD4850 died last night. And it didn't even die gracefully! (I had hoped for smoke or the occasional fan flying through the room).<br /><br />Whenever I started any 3d app my pc would just shut down, first I hoped it were just driver issues bent then of course.. I knew it was the card. So this morning I went to the store and bought myself an Nvidia GTX 285. I will be sending the HD4850 back to ATI for repairs (it's still under warranty), then when it's repaired I'm going to sell it.<br /><br />I slipped it in painlessly, the drivers were installed in a matter of minutes, if not seconds. I started up some games and immediately got that familiar feeling I get when things feel right. Ever since I had my ATI I knew it tore through any game no problems. But something always felt 'off'. I wasn't sure what it was until I saw the crisp image of an Nvidia card.<br /><br />Then I knew and could finally make a judgement of my own, having had first hand experience: NVidia is just infinitely better than ATI. <br />I'm just so glad to be back with Nvidia. If you're doubting... choose safe... choose NVidia.<br /><br />No this is not a spambot.. just a really happy customer! <img src="/web/20090505203620im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214177" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 12:41 pm "><author>=FF=Sturm</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I dont want ATI, I DONT WANT NVIDIA TOO, INTEL GRAPHICS SUCK.<br />Conclusion: I make my own VIdcards, wanna one? its 1 TB !!!<br />(opinions are endrosed by chinesse <img src="/web/20090505203620im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /> and It has no warranty )</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214178" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 2:08 pm "><author>aaa111</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well,i do always own nvidia's card,as i am a big fan of nvidia.Post nv30 era nvidia is doing very well in term of both image quality/performence.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214179" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 2:36 pm "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Funny thing about cards. I recently was having an overheating problem with my Nvidia card. No there was nothing wrong with the card itself but the airflow between the fan and heatsink had a wall of dust I had to clean out.<br /><br />So I decided to investigate even further and took the heatsink off. The thermal paste was pretty much done. So I grabbed me some Arctic Silver 5 and repasted it. Dropped the temp by far and is back to normal.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214180" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 2:56 pm "><author>FragWeapon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I decided to be a dumb ass and buy two 4850's back when I bought my PC early this year. Trying to put the things crossfire was pretty retarded... First off, there was NO instructions on how to put the things in crossfire. Yea you'd think putting the ribbons on and it works.... So I went to ati's website, and it shows putting two of the ribbons on, but then if you look at their images it shows one ribbon on. I was just so confused, so I started off putting one on, it seemed to have worked. But I decided to put the other one on just to be safe. I fire up 3DMark and get double the speed literally with crossfire on. But on XP Catalyst shows only one card connected... I read up on it, it's only a bug. <br /><br />I just cannot believe that a thing ATI keeps pushing (crossfire) and advertizing doesn't even have proper instructions included with the hardware, there wasn't even any mention of crossfire installation. <br /><br />Now that I have Vista, the ATI drivers suddendly do not want to install, this is a common issue for a lot of people, and I think the issue is on XP as well, but not nearly the same percentage as Vista.<br /><br /><br /><br />I'm sure ATI cards are rippin' the equivallent Nvidia card in performance a new one, but even then only about a 3fps difference, but the support is just horrible. And these issues have been around for years it seems, and it's only getting worse. I've never owned an nvidia card, it just seems that every time I go to buy a vid card ATI seems like the proper choice...well fuck that i'm never going ATI until I hear only good things about them.<br /><br />That being said I love my intel core i7!!! (best buy ever!)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214183" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 3:50 pm "><author>Argoon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Maybe i'm one of the lucky ones but i never add any big problems with my ATI cards drivers and this is my third one and even when i add Nvidia they worked fine, the only game that seams to run bad on my HD 3870 is Cryostasis, but that is because this game was made to run best on Nvidia.<br /><br />And Afaik the majority of ATI driver problems seam to be about crossfire (that i don't use). <br /><br />What no one can deny is that ATI does powerful cards at low price as the HD 4000 series have shown, and that as made Nvidia lower their prices also.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214185" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 6:33 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">nvidia cards stink.   <img src="/web/20090505203620im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" />  i'd rather have an intel integrated or an old voodoo!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214192" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 9:06 pm "><author>stabinbac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I stopped buying ATI cards when they dropped linux support for my 8500. The Nvidia drivers were also far better.<br /><br />There was always a weird feeling with ATI cards. They felt like they were performing fine, but they were probably a mess behind the scenes. I might just be the hugely different marketing, but Nvidia has always seemed more clean and stable.<br /><br />Desktop cubes are badass!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214194" date="Posted: Sat May 02, 2009 11:52 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've always found the aurora around nvidia interesting.... gamers seem to love them but I've read much from non-games on the technical end that say avoid nvidia for anything BUT gaming.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214205" date="Posted: Sun May 03, 2009 1:04 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">my nividia 6800gt that i bought just for d3 5 years ago died last week. <img src="/web/20090505203620im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /><br /><br />my pc gaming days are over for time being. i have an xbox360 if need to play video games. i just don't have time play anymore...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214211" date="Posted: Sun May 03, 2009 9:05 pm "><author>blah123</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thanks for supporting the pc gaming community!<br /><br />btw: is it possible to shove the xbox across the ass?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214212" date="Posted: Sun May 03, 2009 9:43 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">blah123 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">thanks for supporting the pc gaming community!<br /><br />btw: is it possible to shove the xbox across the ass?</div><br />You can completely forget about this attitude over here. Please adjust accordingly or proceed to leave. Thanks!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214213" date="Posted: Mon May 04, 2009 12:18 am "><author>FragWeapon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">blah123 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">thanks for supporting the pc gaming community!<br /><br />btw: is it possible to shove the xbox across the ass?</div><br /><br />thanks for supporting the gaming community as a whole! <br /><br />btw: what the fuck does "shove the xbox across the ass" mean?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214230" date="Posted: Mon May 04, 2009 1:26 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">blah123 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">btw: is it possible to shove the xbox across the ass?</div><br /><br />did he register on doom3world just to post that?  <img src="/web/20090505203620im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br />yes, xbox's can be shoved across the ass. up the ass, however, would be a bit difficult. for me anyway...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214232" date="Posted: Mon May 04, 2009 2:22 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">the 360 came out JUST so people would have a smaller XBOX to attempt to merge with asses!<br /><br />But it has an ATI vs Nvidia of the first one.   <img src="/web/20090505203620im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214250" date="Posted: Tue May 05, 2009 2:26 pm "><author>obsidian</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ehhh.... I've been having constant driver issues with an nVidia card and Vista. Random bluescreens and game crashes to Windows. Most of these crashes can be attributed some of the nVidia drivers, in particular nvlddmkm.dll (crash to windows) and nvlddmkm.sys (bluescreen). It also heats up heavily so I had to manually set the fan speed throttling because it doesn't work by itself.<br /><br />BFG GTX280<br />Windows Vista Ultimate x64</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
