<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="22786"><title>Duke Nukem Developer 3D Realms Shuts Down</title><posts><post id="p214314" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:07 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">*gasp* Who would have thought after developing a title for 13 years?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"> Update: Apogee Software and Deep Silver have issued a statement to Shacknews, confirming that there is a "situation at 3D Realms" but stressing they are not affected.<br /><br />"Deep Silver and Apogee Software are not affected by the situation at 3D Realms," a representative for the companies has told us. "Development on the Duke Nukem Trilogy is continuing as planned."<br /><br />In development at Frontline Studios, the Duke Nukem Trilogy represents three new Nintendo DS and PSP titles, with the first, Critical Mass, hitting in September. The trilogy is separate from Duke Nukem Forever, which was in the works at 3D Realms proper.<br /><br />Original story: A very reliable source close to Duke Nukem Forever developer 3D Realms today confirmed to Shacknews that the development studio has been shut down.<br /><br />The closure came about as a result of funding issues, our source explained, with the shut down said to affect both 3D Realms and the recently resurrected Apogee. Employees of both entities have already been let go.<br /><br />Phone calls and e-mails to various 3D Realms veterans have thus far gone unanswered, with 3D Realms publishing partner Take-Two and Apogee partner Deep Silver likewise unavailable for comment.<br />3D Realms was founded in 1987 by Scott Miller and George Broussard, and was best known for its Duke Nukem series of shooters starring the titular, bubblegum-lacking hero. The studio had infamously been working on Duke Nukem Forever, the next flagship franchise entry, for the past 13 years.<br /><br />A final push to release Duke Nukem Forever began in 2007, marked by a short teaser starring the in-game hero that was released late that year.<br /><br />As recent as January 2009, company steward George Broussard wrote on his Twitter feed that he was visiting Take-Two to show off the title. </div><br /><br /><br />Source: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513/http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/58519">http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/58519</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214315" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:16 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">A Decade of Duke: The Brief Long History of DNF<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513/http://www.shacknews.com/featuredarticle.x?id=720">http://www.shacknews.com/featuredarticle.x?id=720</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214316" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:37 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">:'-(</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214318" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:08 am "><author>Neurological</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Not suprised at all. I would have been more surprised if they were releasing DNF :p.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214319" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:17 am "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Horrible news...........I was really looking forward to this when it actually did come out.<br /><br />Maybe they'll try and have another developer pick up the pieces?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214322" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 4:55 am "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kiltron wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Horrible news...........I was really looking forward to this when it actually did come out.<br /><br />Maybe they'll try and have another developer pick up the pieces?</div><br /><br />agreed. The footage shown on the Jace Hall Show actually looked pretty cool.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214324" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 10:33 am "><author>Ww3</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's too bad for them. It does go to show that perfectionism gets you nowhere <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214325" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 10:41 am "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">wow what a surprise...  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214328" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 12:52 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">no heads up? no bye to the fans? no warning?  Honestly for a company that is so engrossed with fans, keeping their own forums, always interacting, George Broussard always twittering about something everyday...........it doesn't make sense why everything would shut down in 24 hours and no one is speaking.<br /><br />They may have been working on duke forever for a long time, but between Prey, duke 3d on Xbox 360(which george still gives out keys to on his twitter page), it's not like they weren't making money.<br /><br />Maybe its a hoax to rev up publicity for something big?  I hope I'm right.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214330" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:17 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just stumbled upon this<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513/http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/the-chair-story-revival/">http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/th ... y-revival/</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><br />Uhm... Dunno... Big important stuff written in that post... I think we just need some proof...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214335" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:16 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Rayne wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Just stumbled upon this<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513/http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/the-chair-story-revival/">http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/th ... y-revival/</a><!-- m --><br />Uhm... Dunno... Big important stuff written in that post... I think we just need some proof...</div><br />That sounds like a BS story to me.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214337" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:27 pm "><author>=FF=Sturm</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Fuck them all<br />It is not going to be release... NEVER! Keep waiting another 13 years</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214340" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:49 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">[edited] not really relevant any more.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214346" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 4:51 pm "><author>Bittoman</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What is with all the hostilities, verbal attacks and now bigotry/name calling lately?<br /><br />Can't we all just get along???  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_neutral.gif" alt=":|" title="Neutral" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214347" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 5:16 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">no, but there's still no reason to be attacking people!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214349" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 5:32 pm "><author>aaa111</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What does this mean for prey 2??will it be affected by the closure of 3drealms.<br /><br />BTW,this is really sad news,but it should have to happen anyway.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214351" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 6:30 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Seems like nobody took a read on the link I posted earlier...  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_question.gif" alt=":?:" title="Question" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214353" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 6:46 pm "><author>Sebultura</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What's sad is to see how quick the site's been shut down, without any words for real fans.<br />If 3dR was in a bad situation, this certainly didn't happened in 2 secs, so why shutting down the site this way ?<br /><br />I don't feel that much disgusted from the thing as I'm no real die hard 3dR fanboy, but I think this is a real pain to true fans, not to say a big offense to their loyalty  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225040513im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214355" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 7:51 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">GTA's since DNF started...<br /><br />Grand Theft Auto <br />Grand Theft Auto, Gameboy Color Port <br />Grand Theft Auto: London 1969 <br />Grand Theft Auto: London 1961 <br />Grand Theft Auto 2 <br />Grand Theft Auto III <br />Grand Theft Auto: Vice City <br />Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas <br />Grand Theft Auto Advance <br />Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories <br />Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories, PS2 Port <br />Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories <br />Grand Theft Auto IV</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214357" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 8:58 pm "><author>Sebultura</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">And you can even add China Town.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214746" date="Posted: Sun May 24, 2009 8:35 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There goes a game which I've been waiting for ever...<br /><br />Honestly, it should forever serve as the most advanced portray of feature creep and should get taught at game dev courses on university.<br /><br />A perfect game does not exist, neither will it, so nail down what you want to achieve and stick to the plan. Save the endless stream of ultimate features for the next game.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214761" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 7:29 am "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">There goes a game which I've been waiting for ever...<br /><br />Honestly, it should forever serve as the most advanced portray of feature creep and should get taught at game dev courses on university.<br /><br />A perfect game does not exist, neither will it, so nail down what you want to achieve and stick to the plan. Save the endless stream of ultimate features for the next game.</div><br />True dat. With all the ideas to perfect the franchise, you'd think George Broussard would've just saved that new material for sequels to Forever. Hell, he could've made a whole Duke Nukem Forever trilogy with the time its taken.<br /><br />At least Apogee itself didn't go out of business. I mean, they're the company that helped id get off the ground. It's just an awful shame this had to happen. Everything that keeps me sane has been going down the drain lately. First, my favorite (and only) L.A. radio talk station gets replaced by a Top 40 format to save cash. Next, I can no longer afford to buy all the great games that have come out lately (Left4Dead? How about Left4Broke <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" />). Now, 3d Realms goes bye! I was really looking forward to DNF, and I would've gladly continued waiting.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214767" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 10:47 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">evilartist wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">True dat. With all the ideas to perfect the franchise, you'd think George Broussard would've just saved that new material for sequels to Forever. Hell, he could've made a whole Duke Nukem Forever trilogy with the time its taken.</div><br /><br />That is almost exactly the same answer John Carmack gave on the DNF engine switching loolapalooza (Q2 back then).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214771" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 3:18 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">3d realms is the apogee that helped id, the new apogee is a different company.  But either way, neither are out of business.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214776" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 5:33 pm "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">3d realms is the apogee that helped id, the new apogee is a different company.  But either way, neither are out of business.</div><br />::looks up wikipedia:: Ah, okay. I thought the current Apogee was the same old Apogee. Apparently not.<br /><br />I had just now discovered <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232/http://kotaku.com/5255220/take+two-sues-duke-nukem-forever-devs-over-failure-to-deliver" class="postlink">this article</a>. It's weeks old, so you may already know about it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214778" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 5:38 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yeah, read that.  My assumption is that even though take 2 knows 3drealms has little to no $$, they DO have IP's that take 2 could profit from, so sue &amp; get the ip's transferred in instead of $$.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214783" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 8:53 pm "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">yeah, read that.  My assumption is that even though take 2 knows 3drealms has little to no $$, they DO have IP's that take 2 could profit from, so sue &amp; get the ip's transferred in instead of $$.</div><br />Now <span style="font-style: italic">there's</span> something to get mixed feelings about. On one hand, Take 2 can obtain the rights to Duke and actually find someone to finish the game. On the other hand, it means wishing for Scott and George to burn some more, which I don't want to see happen. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /> Plus, what if Take 2 redoes the game, but butchers the coolness of a Duke FPS and we're left with some half-assed version of what George was trying to make.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214787" date="Posted: Tue May 26, 2009 5:29 am "><author>CrimsonHead</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I really don't like the idea of 2k acquiring and outsourcing it at all, if that happens you will probably see me in forums encouraging people to boycott it (even though I know everyone dismisses me as a nutty corn flake most of the time, I gotta try), it just won't be the same thing. <br /><br />What if hypothetically something happened to a band like Metallica where they could'nt play live anymore and the record company decided to hire another band like say... Megadeth, or someone else like that to cover their music live but still bill the act as "Metallica"? I'm know Dave Mustaine is a very capable musician and would do a wonderful job, but it's just not the same thing, and not what I or a lot of others would want to see.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214796" date="Posted: Tue May 26, 2009 9:06 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">CrimsonHead wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I really don't like the idea of 2k acquiring and outsourcing it at all, if that happens you will probably see me in forums encouraging people to boycott it (even though I know everyone dismisses me as a nutty corn flake most of the time, I gotta try), it just won't be the same thing. </div><br /><br />Running around and encouraning people to boycott something as unmeaningful as a game is a waste of time, talent and resources. In such a case I just ignore it completely and focus on what is important.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">CrimsonHead wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">What if hypothetically something happened to a band like Metallica where they could'nt play live anymore and the record company decided to hire another band like say... Megadeth, or someone else like that to cover their music live but still bill the act as "Metallica"? I'm know Dave Mustaine is a very capable musician and would do a wonderful job, but it's just not the same thing, and not what I or a lot of others would want to see.</div><br /><br />Dave Mustaine wouldn't be Dave Mustaine if he'd submit into becoming a Metallica cover band player.<br />There are hordes of studio musicians unseen to the world who play circles around any of Metallicas band members, but it's not the technical ability to reproduce a sound what makes a band, it's the personalities of the band members. However, transferring an IP over to someone else is like exchanging the lead singer of the band - that could work. You'd end up with something different, but it's still going to be original enough to be excellent.  (AC/DC - just to name one).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214802" date="Posted: Tue May 26, 2009 12:26 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">What if hypothetically something happened to a band like Metallica where they could'nt play live anymore and the record company decided to hire another band like say... Megadeth, or someone else like that to cover their music live but still bill the act as "Metallica"? I'm know Dave Mustaine is a very capable musician and would do a wonderful job, but it's just not the same thing, and not what I or a lot of others would want to see.</div><br /><br />When giving a hypothetical bad situation of a band covering another bands music, you shouldn't use the example cover band whose lead singer/guitarist was the founding lead guitarist of the band they are covering.  Especially when he had influence over much of the first album and writing credits on about 4 songs  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" />...just saying.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214841" date="Posted: Thu May 28, 2009 12:30 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's the best way possible to put the final nail in the coffin of Duke Nukem Forever (last time i wrote these words in sentence i hope):<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232/http://www.escapistmagazine.com/videos/view/zero-punctuation/748-Duke-Nukem-Forever">http://www.escapistmagazine.com/videos/ ... em-Forever</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214844" date="Posted: Thu May 28, 2009 2:40 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">when I saw that video earlier the only thing that made me think of duke was they said the character was duke.  Besides that, I thought he was talking about HL2.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227120" date="Posted: Mon Sep 06, 2010 9:32 pm "><author>smurkenstein</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hell apprarently chilleth around this time of year:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232/http://www.dailytech.com/article.aspx?newsid=19544">http://www.dailytech.com/article.aspx?newsid=19544</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232/http://www.reghardware.com/2010/09/03/duke_nukem_forever/">http://www.reghardware.com/2010/09/03/d ... m_forever/</a><!-- m --><br /><br />I had the pleasure to look at this slightly embarassing jpg at work earlier (cursed open offices)<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232im_/http://regmedia.co.uk/2009/05/19/duke_nukem_big.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p227123" date="Posted: Mon Sep 06, 2010 10:04 pm "><author>reko</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Embarrasing jpg? <br />As long as you're a die-hard (not exactly) fan of classic FPS, graphics aren't a matter, the gameplay it's awesome <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p227124" date="Posted: Mon Sep 06, 2010 10:24 pm "><author>smurkenstein</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, graphics have certainly improved - those buns are perfectly rounded &amp; don't look a bit like Betruger's head   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041232im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214314" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:07 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">*gasp* Who would have thought after developing a title for 13 years?<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent"> Update: Apogee Software and Deep Silver have issued a statement to Shacknews, confirming that there is a "situation at 3D Realms" but stressing they are not affected.<br /><br />"Deep Silver and Apogee Software are not affected by the situation at 3D Realms," a representative for the companies has told us. "Development on the Duke Nukem Trilogy is continuing as planned."<br /><br />In development at Frontline Studios, the Duke Nukem Trilogy represents three new Nintendo DS and PSP titles, with the first, Critical Mass, hitting in September. The trilogy is separate from Duke Nukem Forever, which was in the works at 3D Realms proper.<br /><br />Original story: A very reliable source close to Duke Nukem Forever developer 3D Realms today confirmed to Shacknews that the development studio has been shut down.<br /><br />The closure came about as a result of funding issues, our source explained, with the shut down said to affect both 3D Realms and the recently resurrected Apogee. Employees of both entities have already been let go.<br /><br />Phone calls and e-mails to various 3D Realms veterans have thus far gone unanswered, with 3D Realms publishing partner Take-Two and Apogee partner Deep Silver likewise unavailable for comment.<br />3D Realms was founded in 1987 by Scott Miller and George Broussard, and was best known for its Duke Nukem series of shooters starring the titular, bubblegum-lacking hero. The studio had infamously been working on Duke Nukem Forever, the next flagship franchise entry, for the past 13 years.<br /><br />A final push to release Duke Nukem Forever began in 2007, marked by a short teaser starring the in-game hero that was released late that year.<br /><br />As recent as January 2009, company steward George Broussard wrote on his Twitter feed that he was visiting Take-Two to show off the title. </div><br /><br /><br />Source: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422/http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/58519">http://www.shacknews.com/onearticle.x/58519</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214315" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:16 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">A Decade of Duke: The Brief Long History of DNF<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422/http://www.shacknews.com/featuredarticle.x?id=720">http://www.shacknews.com/featuredarticle.x?id=720</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214316" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:37 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">:'-(</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214318" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:08 am "><author>Neurological</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Not suprised at all. I would have been more surprised if they were releasing DNF :p.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214319" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:17 am "><author>Kiltron</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Horrible news...........I was really looking forward to this when it actually did come out.<br /><br />Maybe they'll try and have another developer pick up the pieces?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214322" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 4:55 am "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kiltron wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Horrible news...........I was really looking forward to this when it actually did come out.<br /><br />Maybe they'll try and have another developer pick up the pieces?</div><br /><br />agreed. The footage shown on the Jace Hall Show actually looked pretty cool.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214324" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 10:33 am "><author>Ww3</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's too bad for them. It does go to show that perfectionism gets you nowhere <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214325" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 10:41 am "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">wow what a surprise...  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214328" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 12:52 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">no heads up? no bye to the fans? no warning?  Honestly for a company that is so engrossed with fans, keeping their own forums, always interacting, George Broussard always twittering about something everyday...........it doesn't make sense why everything would shut down in 24 hours and no one is speaking.<br /><br />They may have been working on duke forever for a long time, but between Prey, duke 3d on Xbox 360(which george still gives out keys to on his twitter page), it's not like they weren't making money.<br /><br />Maybe its a hoax to rev up publicity for something big?  I hope I'm right.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214330" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 2:17 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just stumbled upon this<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422/http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/the-chair-story-revival/">http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/th ... y-revival/</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><br />Uhm... Dunno... Big important stuff written in that post... I think we just need some proof...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214335" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:16 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Rayne wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Just stumbled upon this<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422/http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/the-chair-story-revival/">http://gamingisstupid.com/2009/05/06/th ... y-revival/</a><!-- m --><br />Uhm... Dunno... Big important stuff written in that post... I think we just need some proof...</div><br />That sounds like a BS story to me.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214337" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:27 pm "><author>=FF=Sturm</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Fuck them all<br />It is not going to be release... NEVER! Keep waiting another 13 years</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214340" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 3:49 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">[edited] not really relevant any more.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214346" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 4:51 pm "><author>Bittoman</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What is with all the hostilities, verbal attacks and now bigotry/name calling lately?<br /><br />Can't we all just get along???  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_neutral.gif" alt=":|" title="Neutral" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214347" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 5:16 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">no, but there's still no reason to be attacking people!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214349" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 5:32 pm "><author>aaa111</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What does this mean for prey 2??will it be affected by the closure of 3drealms.<br /><br />BTW,this is really sad news,but it should have to happen anyway.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214351" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 6:30 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Seems like nobody took a read on the link I posted earlier...  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_question.gif" alt=":?:" title="Question" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214353" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 6:46 pm "><author>Sebultura</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What's sad is to see how quick the site's been shut down, without any words for real fans.<br />If 3dR was in a bad situation, this certainly didn't happened in 2 secs, so why shutting down the site this way ?<br /><br />I don't feel that much disgusted from the thing as I'm no real die hard 3dR fanboy, but I think this is a real pain to true fans, not to say a big offense to their loyalty  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225043422im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214355" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 7:51 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">GTA's since DNF started...<br /><br />Grand Theft Auto <br />Grand Theft Auto, Gameboy Color Port <br />Grand Theft Auto: London 1969 <br />Grand Theft Auto: London 1961 <br />Grand Theft Auto 2 <br />Grand Theft Auto III <br />Grand Theft Auto: Vice City <br />Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas <br />Grand Theft Auto Advance <br />Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories <br />Grand Theft Auto: Liberty City Stories, PS2 Port <br />Grand Theft Auto: Vice City Stories <br />Grand Theft Auto IV</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214357" date="Posted: Thu May 07, 2009 8:58 pm "><author>Sebultura</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">And you can even add China Town.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214365" date="Posted: Fri May 08, 2009 6:23 pm "><author>BJA</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very sad news, I was so looking forward to a release <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /> I hope that doesn't mean we'll never see the duke again.<br /><br />Somes unreleased ingame screenshots...<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://talkinrealatyou.blogspot.com/2009/05/end-is-beginning.html">http://talkinrealatyou.blogspot.com/200 ... nning.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />and some conceptart<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.squidcakes.blogspot.com/">http://www.squidcakes.blogspot.com/</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214366" date="Posted: Fri May 08, 2009 7:09 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Aren't they tied to Non-Disclosure Agreements? The rumors state they don't actually close their doors until next Friday.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214375" date="Posted: Sat May 09, 2009 12:46 pm "><author>Kamikazee</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Oh well, other and better...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214377" date="Posted: Sat May 09, 2009 2:19 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Secret site, now made official:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.3drealms.com/bio/staff/index.html">http://www.3drealms.com/bio/staff/index.html</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Updated:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.3drealms.com/">http://www.3drealms.com/</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214378" date="Posted: Sat May 09, 2009 2:40 pm "><author>Kristus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">They seem to be really happy on the picture. (Maybe they're relieved that it's finally over :p)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214379" date="Posted: Sat May 09, 2009 3:37 pm "><author>Kamikazee</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Kristus wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">They seem to be really happy on the picture. (Maybe they're relieved that it's finally over :p)</div>While I can understand that a "I survived 3D Realms" photo can be interesting, but I would say they smile just a tad too much when their work place is closing up...<br /><br />All of this seems more of a marketing trick - god knows if they'll simply rename the company and register a new Internet domain.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214381" date="Posted: Sat May 09, 2009 5:14 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://sikander.shackspace.com/DNF">http://sikander.shackspace.com/DNF</a><!-- m --><br /><br />no marketing trick.  People are out of a job.  They're allowed to use stuff for portfolio so they can get new jobs.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214394" date="Posted: Sun May 10, 2009 5:20 am "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">http://sikander.shackspace.com/DNF<br /><br />no marketing trick.  People are out of a job.  They're allowed to use stuff for portfolio so they can get new jobs.</div><br /><br />It's not marketing trick that the development part of the company closed and that people are out of a job.  But it has yet to be mentioned officially and why people are out of a job.  3dRealms is not closing down, it is still continuing on as a company with Scott Miller and George Broussard.....that has been stated.  They are only getting rid of the rest of the staff.  Also they still own and are keeping IP rights to Duke Nukem, while Take2 has said it still is retaining rights to publishing DNF.  <br /><br />So the question remains......is DNF finished or almost finished simply to be completed by an outside dev?  After all you don't need a development staff if you don't have a game in development anymore and don't plan on having a game in development anymore.  <br /><br />There has more or less been complete silence in terms of Duke Nukem.  All that is really known is 3DR is staying open and keeping Duke IP, but all developers have been let go.  Still lots of potentially interesting questions.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214395" date="Posted: Sun May 10, 2009 6:37 am "><author>TelMarine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Footage of Duke Forever (not a joke):<br /><br />edit: previous link was removed, get this one while it lasts: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W01hKUgdwKg">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W01hKUgdwKg</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.liquidmesh3d.com/media/demo_reel_web.mov">http://www.liquidmesh3d.com/media/demo_reel_web.mov</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214397" date="Posted: Sun May 10, 2009 10:19 am "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Leaked video of this shitty game in action: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.dailymotion.com/video/x98ntd_duke-nukem-forever-gameplay-2009_videogames">http://www.dailymotion.com/video/x98ntd ... videogames</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214398" date="Posted: Sun May 10, 2009 11:51 am "><author>Ww3</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Looks like fun though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214413" date="Posted: Mon May 11, 2009 3:27 am "><author>FragWeapon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It almost looks like the rest of the game is fixing bugs and decorating levels... I laughed when Duke is falling while sticking the finger...lmfao</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214415" date="Posted: Mon May 11, 2009 4:45 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">here's pretty much all the non-fictional info put in to one convenient place: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://shoutcast.tastyspleen.net/admin/doku.php?id=3drealms">http://shoutcast.tastyspleen.net/admin/ ... d=3drealms</a><!-- m --><br /><br />In one thread @ 3drealms someone posted a quote that a former employee made about why the game failed.  I especially love this line:<br />"Read up on Valve's 'orange box' method of design -- that's how you make games"<br /><br />Why do I love it?  One simple reason: TF2.  TF2 was started soon after TF for Q1.  Deved in AT LEAST 9 years.  For a MOD that turned out to be a port of a port with enhanced graphics!  Why would ANYONE say THAT is a GOOD example of how to make a GAME?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214419" date="Posted: Mon May 11, 2009 6:37 am "><author>FragWeapon</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I think the Orange Box should be a great example on how to DISTRIBUTE games. Not make them, one of the reasons mentioned just above me. I mean the games are great and all but they're also pretty small other than the half life series. Portal, TF2, and Left 4 Dead (which isn't orangebox...I know) are all pretty short games...fun, but short (TF2 has barely any maps for a MP game...). But that's why they pack them with the bigger games for an affordable price. <br /><br />I mean I like valve's games but at the same time I don't. They always feel the same to me in terms of sound and art, and general atmosphere. It's like as if Portal, Half Life and even left 4 dead belong in the same world. But the thing that sets valve above most companies now-a-days is the thought that seems to be put into their games. They find something simple, and they stick to it, they don't try and over complicate things either. <br /><br />The way most gamers are though is they see one company makes an awesome game, the next game they make is decent, but since the last game was so awesome it's got a huge community right off the bat. And that's really where blizzard and valve are right now (in my opinion, please don't try and convince me to change my mind). <br /><br />3DRealms pretty much had every FPS player screaming like britney spears' fans for a while. But 3DR screwed up and look where they are now. So all it takes is valve to release one shitty game and they will lose lots of respect. "YOU CHEATED THE FANS!!!!" (heard that before? Doom 3 for example). The only people who would stick around for the next valve game are the fanboys. <br /><br />That being said, in my opinion, id software is pretty low on the popularity list at the moment, because of Doom 3...and Quake 4/ETQW (yes I know they didn't make these two, but only the fanboys know that). So we'll see how rage and Doom 4 turn out, or even Wolfenstein..which isn't id's. <br /><br />My opinions of course, and way off topic as usual. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214506" date="Posted: Thu May 14, 2009 8:16 am "><author>aardwolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">FragWeapon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I think the Orange Box should be a great example on how to DISTRIBUTE games. Not make them, one of the reasons mentioned just above me. I mean the games are great and all but they're also pretty small other than the half life series. Portal, TF2, and Left 4 Dead (which isn't orangebox...I know) are all pretty short games...fun, but short (TF2 has barely any maps for a MP game...). But that's why they pack them with the bigger games for an affordable price. <br /><br />I mean I like valve's games but at the same time I don't. They always feel the same to me in terms of sound and art, and general atmosphere. It's like as if Portal, Half Life and even left 4 dead belong in the same world. But the thing that sets valve above most companies now-a-days is the thought that seems to be put into their games. They find something simple, and they stick to it, they don't try and over complicate things either. <br /><br />The way most gamers are though is they see one company makes an awesome game, the next game they make is decent, but since the last game was so awesome it's got a huge community right off the bat. And that's really where blizzard and valve are right now (in my opinion, please don't try and convince me to change my mind). <br /><br />3DRealms pretty much had every FPS player screaming like britney spears' fans for a while. But 3DR screwed up and look where they are now. So all it takes is valve to release one shitty game and they will lose lots of respect. "YOU CHEATED THE FANS!!!!" (heard that before? Doom 3 for example). The only people who would stick around for the next valve game are the fanboys. <br /><br />That being said, in my opinion, id software is pretty low on the popularity list at the moment, because of Doom 3...and Quake 4/ETQW (yes I know they didn't make these two, but only the fanboys know that). So we'll see how rage and Doom 4 turn out, or even Wolfenstein..which isn't id's. <br /><br />My opinions of course, and way off topic as usual. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div><br /><br />But both Steam and TF2 suck.  Steam is a shitty system and TF2 is just a glorified quake mod, much like every Valve "game".</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214510" date="Posted: Thu May 14, 2009 12:41 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">But both Steam and TF2 suck. Steam is a shitty system and TF2 is just a glorified quake mod, much like every Valve "game".</div><br /><br />I said Steam sucked since it came out.  I just installed it 3 weeks ago for the first time because I wanted to play the Orange Box (9.99$ on sale = almost stealing).  It's actually a fine application that I havn't had any issues with and the Orange box is incredible.  It just made me look like an ass for hating it all this time.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214513" date="Posted: Thu May 14, 2009 3:36 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">FragWeapon wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">The way most gamers are though is they see one company makes an awesome game, the next game they make is decent, but since the last game was so awesome it's got a huge community right off the bat. And that's really where blizzard and valve are right now (in my opinion, please don't try and convince me to change my mind).</div><br /><br />There's a lot of truth to this.<br /><br />Take any popular band (U2, Metalica, whatever...). I've always wondered if later albums would sell nearly as well if they were debut albums. Know what I mean? Most of the record sales comes from fans that would buy it if it was sh*t or not just because its U2. But the reality is that the album probably would not do very well if you slapped any other name on it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214525" date="Posted: Fri May 15, 2009 5:07 am "><author>revility</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://kotaku.com/5255220/take+two-sues-duke-nukem-forever-devs-over-failure-to-deliver?skyline=true&amp;s=x">http://kotaku.com/5255220/take+two-sues ... e=true&amp;s=x</a><!-- m --><br /><br />thats what happens when you spend too much time screwing around  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br />I'm also not a huge fan of valve at all.  What games did they actually make?  HL and HL2.  What games and mods did they buy out? CS, DOD, L4d, TF and portal.  Their not creative, nor are they productive.  They just have a good eye when it comes to buying out other companies.  What about steam?  How many years did it take them to get it working somewhat decent? too many.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214530" date="Posted: Fri May 15, 2009 12:48 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">revility wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">http://kotaku.com/5255220/take+two-sues-duke-nukem-forever-devs-over-failure-to-deliver?skyline=true&amp;s=x<br /><br />thats what happens when you spend too much time screwing around  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br />I'm also not a huge fan of valve at all.  What games did they actually make?  HL and HL2.  What games and mods did they buy out? CS, DOD, L4d, TF and portal.  Their not creative, nor are they productive.  They just have a good eye when it comes to buying out other companies.  What about steam?  How many years did it take them to get it working somewhat decent? too many.</div><br /><br />I'm a bit confused over the hole sue thing.  I thought 3D Realms was a seperate entity of Apogee, just kinda like a 'parent' of it.  I guess it matters who they actually had a contract with?  I also thought, according to 3DR, that they funded all development of all their games internally.  It's a bit of a shock, and disappointment, to see Take 2 mention they spent about $12 million on the development.<br /><br />EDIT<br /><br />From what I gather on the 3DR forums is that Take 2 bought out the company that originally had publishing rights for DNF for $12 million, but that the money didn't actually go for development.  Can they still sue then?  Kinda seems like your own risk.  Probably a bunch more information will come out I guess.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214680" date="Posted: Fri May 22, 2009 12:31 pm "><author>CrimsonHead</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I came across this stuff last night(links below). I don't know if I'm just whistling in the dark but I for one would like to see them find a way to keep going and finish the damn game. <br /><br />I've been seeing all this footage of it lately since this has been going on and I want to return to the Duke universe now more than ever. I've been re-living all kinds of memories of Duke3d this past week, stuff like the first time I found the "Doomed space marine" easter egg, and the shrink ray, the ice gun, the Monsters that said "suck it down", the strippers, and being able to urinate, and many other things too numerous to list. I know it's just a game, but I feel kind of heartsick and struck with grief at the thought of it all dying away.    <br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/technology/2009/05/19/3d-realms-vows-to-fight-take-two-for-duke-nukem-rights-115875-21371925/">http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/technology ... -21371925/</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041752/http://www.shacknews.com/docs/press/20090518_dnf_3dr_.x">http://www.shacknews.com/docs/press/20090518_dnf_3dr_.x</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214746" date="Posted: Sun May 24, 2009 8:35 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There goes a game which I've been waiting for ever...<br /><br />Honestly, it should forever serve as the most advanced portray of feature creep and should get taught at game dev courses on university.<br /><br />A perfect game does not exist, neither will it, so nail down what you want to achieve and stick to the plan. Save the endless stream of ultimate features for the next game.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214761" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 7:29 am "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">There goes a game which I've been waiting for ever...<br /><br />Honestly, it should forever serve as the most advanced portray of feature creep and should get taught at game dev courses on university.<br /><br />A perfect game does not exist, neither will it, so nail down what you want to achieve and stick to the plan. Save the endless stream of ultimate features for the next game.</div><br />True dat. With all the ideas to perfect the franchise, you'd think George Broussard would've just saved that new material for sequels to Forever. Hell, he could've made a whole Duke Nukem Forever trilogy with the time its taken.<br /><br />At least Apogee itself didn't go out of business. I mean, they're the company that helped id get off the ground. It's just an awful shame this had to happen. Everything that keeps me sane has been going down the drain lately. First, my favorite (and only) L.A. radio talk station gets replaced by a Top 40 format to save cash. Next, I can no longer afford to buy all the great games that have come out lately (Left4Dead? How about Left4Broke <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" />). Now, 3d Realms goes bye! I was really looking forward to DNF, and I would've gladly continued waiting.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214767" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 10:47 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">evilartist wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">True dat. With all the ideas to perfect the franchise, you'd think George Broussard would've just saved that new material for sequels to Forever. Hell, he could've made a whole Duke Nukem Forever trilogy with the time its taken.</div><br /><br />That is almost exactly the same answer John Carmack gave on the DNF engine switching loolapalooza (Q2 back then).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214771" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 3:18 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">3d realms is the apogee that helped id, the new apogee is a different company.  But either way, neither are out of business.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214776" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 5:33 pm "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">3d realms is the apogee that helped id, the new apogee is a different company.  But either way, neither are out of business.</div><br />::looks up wikipedia:: Ah, okay. I thought the current Apogee was the same old Apogee. Apparently not.<br /><br />I had just now discovered <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812/http://kotaku.com/5255220/take+two-sues-duke-nukem-forever-devs-over-failure-to-deliver" class="postlink">this article</a>. It's weeks old, so you may already know about it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214778" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 5:38 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yeah, read that.  My assumption is that even though take 2 knows 3drealms has little to no $$, they DO have IP's that take 2 could profit from, so sue &amp; get the ip's transferred in instead of $$.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214783" date="Posted: Mon May 25, 2009 8:53 pm "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">yeah, read that.  My assumption is that even though take 2 knows 3drealms has little to no $$, they DO have IP's that take 2 could profit from, so sue &amp; get the ip's transferred in instead of $$.</div><br />Now <span style="font-style: italic">there's</span> something to get mixed feelings about. On one hand, Take 2 can obtain the rights to Duke and actually find someone to finish the game. On the other hand, it means wishing for Scott and George to burn some more, which I don't want to see happen. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /> Plus, what if Take 2 redoes the game, but butchers the coolness of a Duke FPS and we're left with some half-assed version of what George was trying to make.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214787" date="Posted: Tue May 26, 2009 5:29 am "><author>CrimsonHead</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I really don't like the idea of 2k acquiring and outsourcing it at all, if that happens you will probably see me in forums encouraging people to boycott it (even though I know everyone dismisses me as a nutty corn flake most of the time, I gotta try), it just won't be the same thing. <br /><br />What if hypothetically something happened to a band like Metallica where they could'nt play live anymore and the record company decided to hire another band like say... Megadeth, or someone else like that to cover their music live but still bill the act as "Metallica"? I'm know Dave Mustaine is a very capable musician and would do a wonderful job, but it's just not the same thing, and not what I or a lot of others would want to see.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214796" date="Posted: Tue May 26, 2009 9:06 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">CrimsonHead wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I really don't like the idea of 2k acquiring and outsourcing it at all, if that happens you will probably see me in forums encouraging people to boycott it (even though I know everyone dismisses me as a nutty corn flake most of the time, I gotta try), it just won't be the same thing. </div><br /><br />Running around and encouraning people to boycott something as unmeaningful as a game is a waste of time, talent and resources. In such a case I just ignore it completely and focus on what is important.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">CrimsonHead wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">What if hypothetically something happened to a band like Metallica where they could'nt play live anymore and the record company decided to hire another band like say... Megadeth, or someone else like that to cover their music live but still bill the act as "Metallica"? I'm know Dave Mustaine is a very capable musician and would do a wonderful job, but it's just not the same thing, and not what I or a lot of others would want to see.</div><br /><br />Dave Mustaine wouldn't be Dave Mustaine if he'd submit into becoming a Metallica cover band player.<br />There are hordes of studio musicians unseen to the world who play circles around any of Metallicas band members, but it's not the technical ability to reproduce a sound what makes a band, it's the personalities of the band members. However, transferring an IP over to someone else is like exchanging the lead singer of the band - that could work. You'd end up with something different, but it's still going to be original enough to be excellent.  (AC/DC - just to name one).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214802" date="Posted: Tue May 26, 2009 12:26 pm "><author>Deadite4</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">What if hypothetically something happened to a band like Metallica where they could'nt play live anymore and the record company decided to hire another band like say... Megadeth, or someone else like that to cover their music live but still bill the act as "Metallica"? I'm know Dave Mustaine is a very capable musician and would do a wonderful job, but it's just not the same thing, and not what I or a lot of others would want to see.</div><br /><br />When giving a hypothetical bad situation of a band covering another bands music, you shouldn't use the example cover band whose lead singer/guitarist was the founding lead guitarist of the band they are covering.  Especially when he had influence over much of the first album and writing credits on about 4 songs  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" />...just saying.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p214841" date="Posted: Thu May 28, 2009 12:30 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's the best way possible to put the final nail in the coffin of Duke Nukem Forever (last time i wrote these words in sentence i hope):<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812/http://www.escapistmagazine.com/videos/view/zero-punctuation/748-Duke-Nukem-Forever">http://www.escapistmagazine.com/videos/ ... em-Forever</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214844" date="Posted: Thu May 28, 2009 2:40 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">when I saw that video earlier the only thing that made me think of duke was they said the character was duke.  Besides that, I thought he was talking about HL2.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227120" date="Posted: Mon Sep 06, 2010 9:32 pm "><author>smurkenstein</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hell apprarently chilleth around this time of year:<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812/http://www.dailytech.com/article.aspx?newsid=19544">http://www.dailytech.com/article.aspx?newsid=19544</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812/http://www.reghardware.com/2010/09/03/duke_nukem_forever/">http://www.reghardware.com/2010/09/03/d ... m_forever/</a><!-- m --><br /><br />I had the pleasure to look at this slightly embarassing jpg at work earlier (cursed open offices)<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812im_/http://regmedia.co.uk/2009/05/19/duke_nukem_big.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p227123" date="Posted: Mon Sep 06, 2010 10:04 pm "><author>reko</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Embarrasing jpg? <br />As long as you're a die-hard (not exactly) fan of classic FPS, graphics aren't a matter, the gameplay it's awesome <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p227124" date="Posted: Mon Sep 06, 2010 10:24 pm "><author>smurkenstein</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, graphics have certainly improved - those buns are perfectly rounded &amp; don't look a bit like Betruger's head   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225042812im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
