<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="23138"><title>To all modders here</title><posts><post id="p218638" date="Posted: Sun Sep 13, 2009 2:32 pm "><author>anthonyda</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi guys, <br />Can you please regroup most part of your mods into an ultimate one who can turn this game (SP) into a real sequel of rtcw instead of cod like ?<br /><br />Here is a little list of the requested changelog, feel free to add/remove stuff :<br /><br />HUD<br /><br />- Remove Button Tips on hud (and compass)<br />- Remove Stab icon on hud<br />- Remove health warning from hud<br />- Remove Veil Amulet from hud<br />- Add a health bar on hud.<br /><br />MENU<br /><br />- Shorten transition time for ingame mainmenu<br />- Remove Intel voice-overs (see Language Pack)<br /><br />MISC<br />- Remove all bob&amp;roll<br />- Allow fov to be increased as much as player wants.<br />- Remove the highlight glint from dropped weapons<br />- Increase the lifetime of breakables and dead bodies<br />- Add quick save/load functionality <br />- Add screenshots functionality <br />- Max corpses increased<br />- Sprint bar, tweak the sprint (?)<br />- Nazis speak german / American speak american and so on.<br />- Bring back old health system (no auto regen, medpack on maps, add heatlh bar on hud).<br />- Make ennemy smarter (ex: Decrease the reaction time of enemies from when they see you to when they fire; Increase accuracy of common enemies. )<br /><br />Weapon<br />-Tweak weapons so you don't have an uberspread without using iron sight. (ex: mp40)<br />- Rebalance weapons (?)<br /><br />Most of theses features are already here but split into multiple mods, I wish you could all work together to make this mod <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225005654im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p218642" date="Posted: Sun Sep 13, 2009 3:04 pm "><author>Neurological</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Speakeang for me, I would like to do a thing like that, but there are some problems. Some of the features you wrote, can't be done at the moment without the proper tools.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p218643" date="Posted: Sun Sep 13, 2009 3:21 pm "><author>anthonyda</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I don't really have hope for a SDK for SP mod, only MP imo. Let's see what will happen...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p218645" date="Posted: Sun Sep 13, 2009 3:29 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I think you will have to wait till another Consolstein comes out.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p218646" date="Posted: Sun Sep 13, 2009 3:58 pm "><author>=FF=Sturm</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225005654/http://www.moddb.com/mods/wolfenstein-the-dark-sense-of-war">http://www.moddb.com/mods/wolfenstein-t ... nse-of-war</a><!-- m --><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225005654im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /><br />Add post process effects to quake 4 and doom 3... Quake 4 can handle 32 players easily and run at 60 tick rate. And Doom 3 owns at modding for "SP"<br />Etqw is a laggy factory</div>]]></body></post><post id="p218660" date="Posted: Sun Sep 13, 2009 8:07 pm "><author>anthonyda</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Strum, you already got (almost?) banned from wolf zone because of your troll/post and you are also doing the same here <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225005654im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /> Please at least stay away from me...<br /><br />Anyway, I have another question, do you think that modders will be able to make a coop mod ? Because there is no model for BJ (lol?) it's only 2hands floating where it wasn't in D3/qw/wolf2MP/others.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p218668" date="Posted: Sun Sep 13, 2009 10:41 pm "><author>TinMan</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I suspect they removed networking from wolf sp.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
