<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="23674"><title>Plasmagun</title><posts><post id="p224597" date="Posted: Thu May 27, 2010 9:18 am "><author>Ranger</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What do I need to edit to make the plasmagun's decal appear on NPCs/monsters?<br /><br />In the plasmagun's .def, <br />I added the plasmagun's, plasma-impact-world decal, to the area in the .def where the settings of the plasma hitting a monster/NPC is stored. <br />Ingame, nothing appears on the shot at models. But when I tried with the generic, bullet-impact-metal decal, that decal appeared on those monsters when I shot them with the plasmagun.<br /><br />I tried opening the decals file in the materials folder, but when I compared the plasma-impact-world decal entry, and the bullet-impact-metal decal entry, I found barely any difference. Only: "if (param = 7)", or something like that. But when I copied that to the plasmagun decal and tried ingame, <span style="font-style: italic">still</span> no decal appears at shot monsters.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225122500im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif" alt=":o" title="Surprised" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p225147" date="Posted: Mon Jun 28, 2010 1:06 am "><author>RangerMcFriendly</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi Ranger,<br /><br />Hopefully you will see this. I haven't done this with the plasmagun, but I have with the chaingun.<br /><br />In the Doom 3 Base folder, make a new folder called materials, if you already have not. Open the materials folder, and create a new text fire called "customdecals.mtr". Add this line of code.<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">textures/decals/hurt09<br />{<br /><br />   qer_editorimage textures/decals/hurt02.tga<br />   DECAL_MACRO<br />   decalInfo 0.5 10 ( 1 1 1 10 ) ( -5 -5 -5 0 )      // fade rgb down fast (clamps <br /><br />to 0), but leave alpha clamped at 1 for the first nine seconds<br /><br />        {<br />                blend    add<br />                map textures/decals/ballburn_plasma<br />                clamp<br />        }<br />}</div><br /><br />Save.<br /><br />Now open up the plasmagun .def file. Find "entityDef	damage_plasmablast"<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">entityDef   damage_plasmablast {<br />   "damage"               "30"<br />   "smoke_wound_flesh"         "smoke_wound_plasma.prt"              //"bloodwound.prt"<br />   "gib"                  "1"<br /><br />}</div><br /><br />I modified mine so it will look different than yours, but add this line of code below under '"gib"' <br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">"mtr_wound_flesh"   "textures/decals/hurt09"</div><br /><br />Save.<br /><br />The plasmagun should now leave its glowing decal on the enemy, however, I don't know how to fade it. I've been trying to figure this out on the chaingun. If you need anymore more help just let me know. PM me anytime.<br /><br />Hope this helps.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227545" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2010 4:56 am "><author>Ranger</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah, I got the decals to appear but they don't glow... I don't think Doom 3 properly supports 2 stage (glow) decals on dynamic models (monster/npc models)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227623" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2010 1:19 pm "><author>RangerMcFriendly</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">They do glow. Make sure the other decal isn't rendering over it, obscuring it. It is most noticeable in a very dark room for testing.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
