<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="23708"><title>Predator the heat of the jungle v0.3 (RELEASED)</title><posts><post id="p224971" date="Posted: Sat Jun 19, 2010 2:37 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
  <a href="/web/20100702042925/http://hotfile.com/dl/47017491/a3e3af7/Predator.The.Heat.Of.The.Jungle.alpha.v0.3.zip.html" class="postlink">
    <img src="/web/20100702042925im_/http://i677.photobucket.com/albums/vv140/satisfaction-com/0610/19/1196830370.jpg" alt="Image" />
  </a>
  <br />
  <br />
  <a href="/web/20100702042925/http://tinyurl.com/2ueavyc" class="postlink">Download Predator the heat of the jungle v0.3 for Crysis v1.2</a>
  <br />
  <br />
  <br />
  <span style="font-weight: bold">A small group of commandos, on a mission in a Central American jungle, are sent by the CIA to rescue captured airmen from Guerillas. But it's not the armed terrorists which are the problem. Something hidden in the jungle, something invisible to the naked eye, something not of this earth is the problem. As Dutch and his men head back to transport, they are slowly targeted one by one. Utilizing the most powerful game engine to date - CryEngine 2, will make it an unforgettable journey to the pure Predator universe. Predator - THOTJ is a quick sketch mod, sort of a concept, of how a Predator game on a modern game engine would look like. You will take the role of commando and 3 freely choosable comrades to help you out on the mission. The mod will feature three game modes which will make it a more enjoyable experience.<br /><br />PREDATOR - THE HEAT OF THE JUNGLE v0.3 mod for CRYSIS [SINGLEPLAYER]<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />Features: true to Predator 1987 movie, food system, new sounds, modified menu, modified hud,<br />easter eggs, music, hassle free installer, 3 game modes, removed nanosuit and more.<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />Current version: 0.3 alpha<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />Requirements: This mod requires CRYSIS patched to version 1.2. Other versions than that are not<br />supported. This mod is not compatible with Crysis Warhead/Wars or demo versions. Multiplayer is<br />not supported. Devmode and cheats are not supported. This mod is not supported in the<br />combination with other mods.<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />Bugs: not many<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />Date: 2010 06 07<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />This mod may not be sold, rented or modded. This mod may not be hosted on sites that sell mods<br />or require paid registration to download. The maker of this work is not responsible for the<br />damage this mod may cause. This archive [.exe and .zip] may not be modified or files added.<br />Please distribute this game mod free of charge, in the form of its original installer and<br />archive only.<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />PREDATOR - THE HEAT OF THE JUNGLE modification is in no way affiliated with CryTek, EA or FOX.<br />-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------<br />Thanks to Crytek for making Crysis. Thanks to John McTiernan for making Predator.<br /></span>
  <br />
  <br />
  <a href="/web/20100702042925/http://www.moddb.com/mods/predator-the-heat-of-the-jungle" class="postlink">For more info visit the official mod's site</a>
  <br />
  <br />
  <br />
  <span style="font-size: 7%; line-height: normal">screenshots and videos are coming soon...</span>
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p224972" date="Posted: Sat Jun 19, 2010 3:00 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Does this have the blessing of FOX or will it get FOXed like any other mod based on their IPs?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p224973" date="Posted: Sat Jun 19, 2010 3:06 pm "><author>Hostyle</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Does this have the blessing of FOX or will it get FOXed like any other mod based on their IPs?</div>Fox Interactive didnt like one aliens mod many years ago afaik, but they [FI] don't exist anymore. Fox don't shut down mods. Also there are many Predator mods out there, but most of them die due to lack of this or that and not because they receive cease or decist letters from FOX.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
