<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="23735"><title>Will the "Doom II " film be made?</title><posts><post id="p225175" date="Posted: Tue Jun 29, 2010 4:20 am "><author>EFAN</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I hope another Doom film is made. And better than the first one...<br />What do you think would be the plot for the film?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p225177" date="Posted: Tue Jun 29, 2010 5:46 am "><author>RangerMcFriendly</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hollywood does not know how to make good video game movies. I liked super mario bros the movie though.<br /><br />Doom II movie? If they decide too, I hope it is in CGI so it feels like a video game still.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p225179" date="Posted: Tue Jun 29, 2010 6:25 am "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">RangerMcFriendly wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I liked super mario bros the movie though.</div><br />Seriously!?<br /><br /><br />I think Hollywood should just let Doom go. I thought the first/only Doom was pretty decent, but there's no way a sequel could top it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p225180" date="Posted: Tue Jun 29, 2010 6:46 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">SMB movie is AWESOME.  <img src="/web/20100701041539im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />  Only vid game movie I have on DVD.  <img src="/web/20100701041539im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />  Postal was decent, but one part wrecked the whole movie imho.<br /><br />I like the Doom movie except that it had nothing to do with hell &amp; the demons.  Besides that, it was a fun movie to watch.  If there was a sequel it should pick up just like D2 the game did.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p225190" date="Posted: Tue Jun 29, 2010 11:17 am "><author>obihb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'd love a 2nd Doom movie but made more like Doom with more Doom monsters and more action and less talking with bad accents. The first movie was cool as horror although it was not Doom it was cool horror movie but as with Alien going to Aliens.. do the sequel as action focused. Bring some more CG monsters. There's such a huge choice to pick from the game and lots don't fit human proportions.<br /><br />Everybody says in those interviews from the Doom movie that CG creatures are crap because they have no weight.. etc.., but I totally disagree. Has anybody ever seen Jurassic Park, Hulk, King Kong, Lord of the Rings, Avatar... many, many more..   or should I mention how awesome the pink demon in the first Doom movie was?..  totally CG. How awesome would it be to have a Cyberdemon battle in the Doom movie?..  real awesome of course. Better than a fist fight with the Rock.<br /><br />I think the original vision for the Doom movie might have been reeled in by budget but I think that the game is so huge that there could have been some more influence in some ways to try and push something much bigger. I'd like to see that in a 2nd Doom movie. And it surely doesn't need to be a sequel to the first movie.. just forget about the first one going into a 2nd one.<br /><br />Of course there's no chance of this but I can always just dream. At least Doom4 is on the way and it will be awesome!.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
