<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="24013"><title>Porting RTH Weapons to Quake4</title><posts><post id="p227982" date="Posted: Wed Oct 20, 2010 11:33 pm "><author>mnemjc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hello everybody...<br /><br />i spend the last few hours with importing the Recall to Hell Pistol/Enforcer into Quake4, i got it close to 100% done so far..<br />Only things that are missing is the muzzleflash (easy to do) and a nifty Particle Effect when firing... but that shouldn't be an issue either<br />BUT.... the arms would need to be replaced as those are stock Doom3 assets.<br />It would be awesome if someone more advanced in modelling than me, could replace those with the Strogg/Marine Arms from Q4... is there anybody interested in doing so?<br /><br />2 Shots showing it in Action<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102/http://www.abload.de/image.php?img=shot000015qyl.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.abload.de/thumb/shot000015qyl.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102/http://www.abload.de/image.php?img=shot00002gp8i.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.abload.de/thumb/shot00002gp8i.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br />Obviously i'll share it when its done...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227984" date="Posted: Wed Oct 20, 2010 11:46 pm "><author>reko</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah it looks good, but what reason to port them over Quake 4, which isn't that improved engine over Doom 3. If it was on Wolfenstein or ETQW, then I wouldn't say this.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227985" date="Posted: Thu Oct 21, 2010 12:12 am "><author>mnemjc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There are so few custom models for idTech4, that imho it would be a shame if that weapon wouldn't be used in any mods.<br /><br />And why Q4? Well i only have D3 and Q4 and its already done for D3.. and i am currently working on a small SP map for Q4. And i love the AI Q4 has to offer.. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br />And as far as i know, it wouldn't be too hard to port it to ETQW from Q4.. as both handle the weapons in a similar fashion.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227989" date="Posted: Thu Oct 21, 2010 4:02 pm "><author>Tetzlaff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice! Fits well into Quake4. I hope you find someone to help you with the arms.<br /><br />That beast-like cyborg monster from RTH would also be a great addition to Q4.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227999" date="Posted: Fri Oct 22, 2010 7:40 pm "><author>mnemjc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have created a global model to be shown when the weapon lies on the floor..  alongside an ammo Clip model both derived from the original .md5mesh file.<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102/http://www.abload.de/image.php?img=shot00005ieuo.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.abload.de/thumb/shot00005ieuo.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br /><br />Everything works good so far, however i have an small issue not directly related to this Gun..<br />In my mod i wanted to replace the default blaster with this gun...but it doesn't have infinite ammo.. so basicly you start out with this weapon + 12 bullets in your hands.<br />Now if the Pistol is depleted and it is the only weapon in my inventory (or all the other weapons are empty aswell) and i try to change the gun via the mousewheel the game freezes.. <br />I spent several hours trying to isolate/track the issue down.. but to no avail. I must be missing something awfully obvious... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /><br /><br />Checked the forums search aswell, and found <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?f=67&amp;t=14460" class="postlink">THIS</a> thread where the starter seems to have the same problem, but the solution seems to be a different one.. as i have weapon0_cycle set to "1"<br />I also tried to reproduce the issue with a Stock Q4 Gun, the Napalm Gun.. and yes, it freezes aswell.. <br /><br /><br />here the corresponding player.def lines:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">// weapon slots<br />    "def_weapon0"                        "weapon_enforcer"<br />    "weapon0_best"                        "1"            // whether weapon should be chosen when out of ammo<br />    "weapon0_cycle"                        "1"            // whether weapon should be selected when using next/prev weapon<br />    "weapon0_toggle"                    "0"            // whether selecting weapon twice switches between current and previous weapons<br />    "weapon0_flashlight"                    "0"<br />    "weapon0_allowempty"                    "1"            //whether weapon should be selectable when empty<br /><br /><br />// default weapons<br />	// seperate multiple weapons with commas (no spaces).<br />	// NOTE: default ammo must be specified explicitly.<br />	"weapon"						"weapon_enforcer"	//"weapon_blaster"<br />	"current_weapon"					"0"<br /></div><br /><br />@Tetzlaff<br />If you mean this buddy <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102/http://media.moddb.com/images/mods/1/5/4168/41241.jpg">http://media.moddb.com/images/mods/1/5/4168/41241.jpg</a><!-- m --><br />then yeah, i would love to see it being used somewhere.. but afaik the monster would require a fair amount of work.. (Some missing faces on the model) monster needs to be scripted etc.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228001" date="Posted: Fri Oct 22, 2010 10:27 pm "><author>reko</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mnemjc wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><br />@Tetzlaff<br />If you mean this buddy <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102/http://media.moddb.com/images/mods/1/5/4168/41241.jpg">http://media.moddb.com/images/mods/1/5/4168/41241.jpg</a><!-- m --><br />then yeah, i would love to see it being used somewhere.. but afaik the monster would require a fair amount of work.. (Some missing faces on the model) monster needs to be scripted etc.</div><br /><br />If I get it animated someone could get it in Doom 3?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228010" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2010 4:13 pm "><author>mnemjc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well its already in doom3, but its not 100% done.. as it doesnt have an AI (I'd guess that you could take the one from pinky demon, dunno much about AI stuff) and the model has a few invisible faces which would need to get fixed...<br /><br />Just check out <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?p=219173#p219173" class="postlink">The 600mb Asset Pack</a> personally i'd love to see it done, doesn't matter if its for Q4 or D3..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228011" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2010 8:12 pm "><author>reko</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yar,<br />Got that assetpack <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />And yeah ,I'd like too to see them in D3, but not simple AI. Like the Dark Beast was suposed to take all the light sources (i read somewhere) and make all dark while you fight him.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228012" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2010 9:48 pm "><author>mnemjc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hehe yeah i read that aswell.. however i think that wouldn't be part of the AI but more either hardcoded in the SDK or scripted in the map scripts.<br />Since you mentioned that you are able to animate monsters, could you help me out with the hands for the gun? That would be awesome..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228013" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2010 11:42 pm "><author>reko</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Never tried on a weapon. But I can start here <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> Someone needs to tell me what to do. How to add the new hands from Q4 etc. <br />And I could do that but I don't have much time in the week, maybe at the weekends I can do something. Send me a PM with all I need to know.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228021" date="Posted: Mon Oct 25, 2010 6:45 pm "><author>mnemjc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Sent you a PM, thanks for your help once again <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130320021102im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
