<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="24054"><title>Switching back to D3 from Editor - Steam version/Win7</title><posts><post id="p228423" date="Posted: Tue Nov 16, 2010 4:25 pm "><author>Dogstar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I recently bought D3 and RoE on Steam (time to virtualize my favourite games in 'the cloud'). They both run fine on my Win7 64-bit PC. The D3 Editor also runs fine, map builds work, but the one problem I just can't solve is that I can't switch into D3 game mode while still in the Editor. The game just hangs. I have to quit out of D3 and the Editor and then fire up the game again in order to load my maps for testing.<br /><br />Anyone have any ideas about this? I will also mention that I just can't figure how to set up a desktop shortcut to run the Editor (at the moment I run it by holding down ctrl+alt+¬ and it all seems to function okay, although I have to click to get my mouse cursor to show up) - I suspect it's something to do with the way Steam works. Always used to work fine when I was back on XP.<br /><br />I know a few kind souls still haunt these hallowed forums, so any help or advice will be gratefully received.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228427" date="Posted: Tue Nov 16, 2010 7:32 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I gave up on running the game via the editor just because of graphical glitches, etc.  I made a shortcut that runs D3 in a window so I can load up my map/etc. &amp; see my changes.  If you change a map you just need to reload the map, if you change any other assets you can reload the engine &amp; it should all be changed.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228434" date="Posted: Wed Nov 17, 2010 1:22 am "><author>Dogstar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ah - I figured out I had forgotten to set the game to run in windowed mode. This has helped in switching between the editor and the game (also means I can now bring up the light editor). So many tiny details I've forgotten since I was last playing with the editor. Problem now is that whilst I can generally do two or three 'editor-to-D3-and-back-again' trips, after that the game just hangs or crashes. Hmmm. I figure it's a Win7 thing. Everything else works fine, though, so not all bad!<br /><br />Just reacquainting myself with the editor and enjoying how nice everything looks with a very powerful PC behind it all (something I never had back in 2004). Here's a peep at my little level...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224212614/http://img833.imageshack.us/i/shot00001q.jpg/" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224212614im_/http://img833.imageshack.us/img833/3614/shot00001q.th.jpg" alt="Image" /></a></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
