<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="24059"><title>Rage for iPhone / iPad</title><posts><post id="p228470" date="Posted: Fri Nov 19, 2010 1:51 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's worth noting Apple carries Rage (HD) on the App store. <br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041045/http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/rage-hd/id400707675?mt=8">http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/rage-hd/id400707675?mt=8</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Here's my quick first impression on the iPad:<br /><br />Surprisingly good graphics<br />Arcade Railshooter (only mildly annoying)<br />3 Weapons (Pistol, Machinegun, Shotgun)<br />3 Levels 8 to 10 minutes each<br />Cheap<br />Controls work better than expected<br />No online stats<br />Fast action with not much time to look around<br />Very fluent on the iPad<br /><br />Downside: you can't lower the console and type "editor"<br /><br />It's a nice, small and early glimpse into Rage. Given the pricepoint it's a nobrainer (actually it's the first game I paid for in the App store).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228472" date="Posted: Fri Nov 19, 2010 4:41 am "><author>parsonsbear</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">DL'd it, but my iPhone is too old to play it. I guess the early pre-3G models only run up to iOS 3.1.3, and 3.2 is required.<br /><br />Saaaad. But i did crack it open- the trailer/intro looks damn awesome.<br /><br />Sally's crazy hat is back! (this is, btw, the highest res image available of her, the QCon 2007 video was never released at high quality.<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041045/http://mixomracing.com/sally.jpg" class="postlink">http://mixomracing.com/sally.jpg</a><br /><br />Looks like Sally and Dinny aren't the only female wastelanders either, JK Stiles has some rollerderby looking companions as well:<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041045/http://mixomracing.com/rollerderbyStiles.jpg" class="postlink">http://mixomracing.com/rollerderbyStiles.jpg</a><br /><br />As an aside, it looks very similar to Doom Resurrection in terms of engine- it's still internally referred to as the Cobalt engine, uses compiled LUA for scripting/ui bindings. There's a bunch of PVR's for items/monsters/ui, but the maps and miniMegaTextures are all memory mapped binaries.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228474" date="Posted: Fri Nov 19, 2010 11:07 am "><author>Gzegzolka</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice that id finally made game with good looking female characters <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041045im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />Why that guy in the middle of second picture look like fat zombie for D3?<br />Now I will go and search for gameplay videos on Youtube.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p228478" date="Posted: Fri Nov 19, 2010 2:02 pm "><author>vertex007</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">someone make a windows conversion !  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041045im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225041045im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
