<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="24733"><title>Brink Agents of Change</title><posts><post id="p232197" date="Posted: Sat Jul 30, 2011 12:52 pm "><author>Gzegzolka</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120210083155/http://bethblog.com/index.php/2011/07/29/brink-title-update-today-dlc-next-week/">http://bethblog.com/index.php/2011/07/2 ... next-week/</a><!-- m --><br /><br />If I meet someone from Splash Damage I will kick him in the ass as hard as it is only possible for the wasted potential that this game, for lack of solid single player campaign, for wasting so awesome design style.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232213" date="Posted: Sat Jul 30, 2011 9:33 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">No one forced you to buy it ya know....</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232221" date="Posted: Sun Jul 31, 2011 10:03 am "><author>Gzegzolka</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I know, I know, but just look on those screens, aren't they awesome? I know I won't change anything alone, but I see great potential, Ark is very original place.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232224" date="Posted: Sun Jul 31, 2011 12:18 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I was never really concerned about SP (AI could be better) but I would of loved to see a branching mission structure based on which side lost/won.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232306" date="Posted: Wed Aug 03, 2011 12:00 pm "><author>Gzegzolka</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I lost hype for that game when I hear that there is no SP, only MP or MP with bots. Still I like game design, sure there could be much more modes, maps and skins for models. Developer can make good game, but game become awesome if developer even after relese put some love into that product, make new patches, fix bugs, support mods and community.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232308" date="Posted: Wed Aug 03, 2011 12:23 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Mods would make Brink awesome.  There's a lot people could do, but I know nobody would.  Look at ETQW.  Barely any mods released.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20120210083155im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p232355" date="Posted: Fri Aug 05, 2011 5:25 am "><author>Sikkpin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just wanted to point out that Brink is F2P for the next couple of days (while QuakeCon is going on).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232371" date="Posted: Fri Aug 05, 2011 1:43 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm betting that's how they're doing the Brink tourney for people who don't own it: instead of giving away a copy they're letting everyone use it for free (since you need Steam &amp; need to be online to play MP).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232919" date="Posted: Fri Aug 26, 2011 10:48 pm "><author>Chr1s</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">The Happy Friar wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Mods would make Brink awesome.  There's a lot people could do, but I know nobody would.  Look at ETQW.  Barely any mods released.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20120210083155im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div><br /><br />That was mainly due to ranked servers and delayed custom content support, which was complete shame as the map editor was awesome beans. Gutted that we wont see Brink's iteration of the editor, sounded awesome.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232925" date="Posted: Sat Aug 27, 2011 7:13 am "><author>aardwolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">SDK out yet?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p232941" date="Posted: Sat Aug 27, 2011 10:11 pm "><author>Setlec</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">nah, Brink was a disappointment for it was cool until playing all campaigns then it loses its charm. ETQW on other hand had fewer maps but an awesome gameplay experience! SD dropped support too soon on etqw.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p233126" date="Posted: Sat Sep 10, 2011 12:52 am "><author>Douglas Quaid</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">From what I gather, people on here didn't really like brink. I'm still wondering will I buy it or not. Anyone else here with tall tales to tell the truth about brink?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p233129" date="Posted: Sat Sep 10, 2011 4:08 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I like it.  It's noting super-de-duper like Quake Wars but it's a fun foot soldier MP game.<br /><br />I'd say out of the two of them, get Quake Wars.  If you already have QW then get Brink.  Brink = everything people complained about QW: vehicles, not tactical enough, to complex, etc.  Brink is the answer.<br /><br />I love Brinks customization system, nothing else like it.  I just wish there were vehicles too.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20120210083155im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
