<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="25273"><title>Rotate a model from the def?</title><posts><post id="p237091" date="Posted: Fri Jan 13, 2012 12:56 am "><author>AdmiralTootToot</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Is there a way to rotate a model from a definition file?  Like how the offset of the model can be adjusted like:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   mesh                  models/weapons/blaster/view.md5mesh<br />   offset                  (2 -7 -2)</div><br /><br />for kicks I tried adding:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   rotation                  (-2.68718e-007 -1 -4.03077e-007 3.57628e-007 -4.03077e-007 1 -1 2.68718e-007 3.57628e-007)</div><br /><br /><br />but the model was still using the same rotation.  Is there a way to rotate the model other than altering the model?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p237094" date="Posted: Fri Jan 13, 2012 8:50 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yes, you need to set it's 'angle' key.<br />E.g. 'angle' '270' (point south in the editor).<br /><br />Make sure you delete any rotation keys first, or the angle key will not work.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p237110" date="Posted: Fri Jan 13, 2012 10:51 pm "><author>AdmiralTootToot</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Doesn't angle only change the left to right facing of an object?  I'm looking to rotate on the other axis.  How would I for example flip an object upside down?<br /><br />And I tried adding:<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">   angle   (90)</div><br /><br />under the model's mesh reference just to see if it would change and nothing changed.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p237126" date="Posted: Sat Jan 14, 2012 11:49 am "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just think of it like this, rotation works for any .ase, brush and patchwork. For MD5Meshes you need to set their angle keys (0-360, or -1 and -2).<br />Setting both the rotation and angle key will not work.<br /><br />I don't know what else to say, I've been using this in Grimm since... whenever. And it works. Place the model, go to the entity inspector and set the right angle from there.<br />Perhaps it works differently in Q4.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p237127" date="Posted: Sat Jan 14, 2012 3:35 pm "><author>AdmiralTootToot</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ah I see the confusion here.  It sounds like you're talking about changing the model's rotation in an editor but I'm looking to try to permanently change it from a .def file, without having to actually edit the original md5mesh itself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p237128" date="Posted: Sat Jan 14, 2012 4:03 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ah I see. Then setting the angle key in the entity definition should still work, weird..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p237129" date="Posted: Sat Jan 14, 2012 4:12 pm "><author>Sikkpin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I tried to do this same thing once. Nothing I tried would work. So, my guess is that it's not possible but I'm sure you can add the functionality with the SDK. Never looked into it myself but it should be rather simple to do.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
