<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="26052"><title>[SOLVED] More than one info_player_start in a level?</title><posts><post id="p244625" date="Posted: Sat Dec 01, 2012 12:18 am "><author>Monty</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hello,<br /><br />I'm wondering, is there a way to set up multiple <span style="font-style: italic">info_player_start</span> entities in a map, and somehow choose which one is used to spawn the player?<br /><br />Note: I've noticed that <span style="font-weight: bold">pak000/maps/game/enpro.map</span> has two instances of info_player_start. However, I'm not sure how, or even if both of them are used; there are no references to them in the script file.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246519" date="Posted: Tue Feb 05, 2013 5:23 pm "><author>Monty</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It looks like Doom simply browses the map file in a sequential order (like a text file) and uses the first <span style="font-style: italic">info_player_start</span> it finds as a starting point.<br /><br />I had to change the source code to create a script function that allowed me to choose the next spawn entity. I created a new function in idGameLocal, called SetNextStartEntity(), which took the name of an entity as a parameter.<br /><br />Note: I did this so I could "knock out" (kill) the player, change a few of the map's settings, and have him wake up in the same map, but I ended up creating a second map because it was more practical.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246520" date="Posted: Tue Feb 05, 2013 6:55 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">id uses teleports to put the player where they want at certain times.  IE map level load, when you run a cinematic, etc.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246889" date="Posted: Fri Feb 15, 2013 1:03 am "><author>Monty</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Oh you're right, I just tested it.<br /><br />I hadn't tried using func_teleport entities before. Thank you, that's another entity I can add to my knowledge base!</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
