<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="26061"><title>MD5 Animation doesn't play correctly</title><posts><post id="p244688" date="Posted: Mon Dec 03, 2012 6:32 pm "><author>Chr1s</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm trying to get a simple animation to work however when I test it out the mesh appears to move within a small confined area, when I turned on bounding boxes, the box shown appears to follow the animation I set yet the mesh doesn't. See image in the link.<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130415032929/http://battle-of-wolken.co.uk/images/etqw/wake/boundingbox.jpg" class="postlink">http://battle-of-wolken.co.uk/images/etqw/wake/boundingbox.jpg</a><br /><br />I have only 2 bones, "origin" and "joint1", joint1 is the bone that does the animation with the whole mesh weighted to it, it is just a simple move up and across motion, I had a more elaborate one before but ran into problems whilst trying to resolve this issue.<br /><br />I'm using 3DS Max 2013 and der_ton's exporter <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130415032929/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=1914" class="postlink">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=1914</a><br /><br />Eventually I'll replace the model with my own version to make it look like an earlier version of the ones found in Q4, for now just learning to animate.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p244691" date="Posted: Mon Dec 03, 2012 8:43 pm "><author>Sir Random</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">In 3dsmax, does the origin remain 'fixed' while joint1 moves around?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p244692" date="Posted: Mon Dec 03, 2012 9:47 pm "><author>Chr1s</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah it remains where I placed it, at first I used a bone for the origin but it affected my animation after I linked the other bone to it, now I'm using a helper point instead for the origin which solved the animation problem but the in game problem remained.<br /><br />EDIT: Tried a shorter up and down animation and worked but when increase the distance of the up and down it hits this same invisible barrier, I've tested other animated models using testmodel/anim and they are able to move further than what I can, really puzzling me.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
