<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="26123"><title>Oculus Rift SDK</title><posts><post id="p245027" date="Posted: Fri Dec 28, 2012 1:47 am "><author>S0L0</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I was wondering if anyone who ordered a dev kit for the Oculus Rift is planning on implementing proper "head free-look" support?<br /><br />So the reticle would be controlled by the mouse or right joystick only (as usual) while the player can move the characters head independently of the torso to look around the world.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246395" date="Posted: Wed Jan 30, 2013 2:48 pm "><author>zoost</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The basic control schemes with the Oculus Rift and Doom3 BFG are allready available in Doom 3 BFG, I think. <br /><br />Torso and weapon aim = Mouse<br />Head (pitch, roll, yaw)  = Oculus<br />Move forward, etc = WASD<br /><br /><br />The Developer Kit is brought to developers to learn about the optimal control schemes, and the influence it has on gameplay design, control schemes and HUD (for example). Here is a forum post of JC concerning stereo.<br /><br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">We struggled a lot with the gun in stereoscopic views. FPS guns are almost always positioned in a physically unrealistic position to maximize 2D artistic impact, which is a big problem in stereo. With lots of guns and lots of animations, there isn't as much freedom to move them around as we would like. For the shipping game it was important that they never show clipped geometry, never penetrate into a wall, always allow the ammo readouts to be visible, and not have the muzzle firing point be too far away from the standard position. If you are willing to compromise some or all of those factors, you can improve the 3D effect.<br /><br />Next game, we will be designing for stereo from the start.<br /><br />I like fully realistic separation, but that actually exceeds one platform's submission guidelines, and we have been told that most people don't really want that much separation.<br /><br />The stereoRender_deGhost variable does nothing in the shipping code. Earlier, I experimented with reducing the contrast and subtracting a fraction of the opposite eye, but it still wouldn't turn a bad 3D monitor into a good one, and I decided to just pull it out.<br /><br />John Carmack</div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p246396" date="Posted: Wed Jan 30, 2013 2:50 pm "><author>zoost</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Does anyone has any experience in playing Doom3 in stereo (side by side, anaglyph, or 3D monitor)?</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
