<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="26336"><title>Doom 3 BFG performance testing on custom map</title><posts><post id="p245623" date="Posted: Sun Jan 06, 2013 4:27 am "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qPRs-OQi1_g">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qPRs-OQi1_g</a><!-- m --><br /><br />Finally, got my map from Steel Storm 2 into BFG. What can I say? BFG suck when it comes to messing up textures (maybe there is another way, but currently it automatically compresses TGA into some sh#t format with bad artifacts; especially noticeable on the sky and clouds). Ambient lighting doesn't work, same as in Doom 3. And spawning monsters at times is tricky. I got lucky and managed to spawn Imps. At the end of the video you will see how view got messed up when I spawned Zsec with machinegun. I think idSoftware slapped BFG together rather dirty and quickly. If you want to play it, it works. If you want to do anything else (including recording demos), it fails. A lot of things don't work or crash the game.<br /><br />Performance wise BFG blows Doom 3 out of the water. I mentioned in YouTube comments that Fraps cuts fps in half. So I was running at 60 fps before I set off Imps. So I would assume instead of 20 fps that you see on the screen during gun fights it would be ~40fps. Even though fps went down, it didn't feel that way. The game smooth all the way through. In other words, when BFG engine is ready to be used in production, one can make a game with bunch on enemies seen on the screen at one, like in good ol' Doom <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br /><br />That was with GF 670 GTX. I need to plug in my GF8800 and see how that work.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p245625" date="Posted: Sun Jan 06, 2013 4:46 am "><author>reckless</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Tried the BFG engine with a 6600 gtx runs quite nicely but a tad slower, was pretty much expected though this gfx card is pretty old by now.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p245626" date="Posted: Sun Jan 06, 2013 4:49 am "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Aye, but vanilla Doom 3 runs quite well on most nowadays PCs because you see maybe a couple of enemies on screen at once.<br /><br />The point of this test was to determine how BFG handles a lot of enemies with a lot of projectile lights that also cast shadows.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p245764" date="Posted: Mon Jan 07, 2013 3:27 pm "><author>reckless</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Back when i still got my 8800GTX it murdered Vanilla (was even faster than my current gfx Card due to a larger pipeline) on a 6600gtx im not sure since it does have considerably  less ram and shader processors so anything complex like tons of shadow volumes would probably kill performance considerably. <br />I suspect the 8800 would have quite a nice time with BFG <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p247094" date="Posted: Thu Feb 21, 2013 2:32 pm "><author>NX-317</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for this post. I didn't know that original Doom 3 BFG can run custom maps, I thought only Taken can do it.<br /><br />Using original Doom 3 BFG edition, I managed to run <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iN5qryQzcYI" class="postlink">Investigation map.</a> It worked...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418/http://img254.imageshack.us/img254/1906/doom3bfg201301062209445.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://imageshack.us/scaled/thumb/254/doom3bfg201301062209445.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br />...but not without bugs and glitches.<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418/http://img708.imageshack.us/img708/6908/doom3bfg201301062209182.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://imageshack.us/scaled/thumb/708/doom3bfg201301062209182.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418/http://img33.imageshack.us/img33/5996/doom3bfg201301062220269.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://imageshack.us/scaled/thumb/33/doom3bfg201301062220269.jpg" alt="Image" /></a><br /><br />Speaking of dirty and quickly, look at the flashlight: they simply placed the weapon_flashlight worldmodel on Marine's model without any editing, so the flashlight goes right through his shoulder!<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418/http://img713.imageshack.us/img713/5161/doom3bfg201301062155041.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://imageshack.us/scaled/thumb/713/doom3bfg201301062155041.jpg" alt="Image" /></a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p247186" date="Posted: Wed Feb 27, 2013 3:22 pm "><author>vertex007</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">so is there a way to load monoxead and wulfen textures with BFG ?<br /><br />or phrozo particle mod ?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p247192" date="Posted: Wed Feb 27, 2013 8:25 pm "><author>NX-317</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It should be possible to load textures, but only with a custom map. When you'll be copying original Doom3's resources from .pk4 files to Doom 3 BFG Edition\base folder, just copy wulfen and monoxead textures there instead of original Doom 3 ones, then copy the custom map's files (map, proc, cm, etc) to Doom 3 BFG Edition\base\maps folder, then launch BFG and run the custom map through the console like you would with original Doom 3.<br /><br />Want to play original Doom 3's maps in BFG with new textures? Then you can try to take maps from original Doom3's pk4s and load them in BFG as custom maps.<br /><br />As for the particles, I believe it's not possible. Now I'm browsing generated folder that was created after I ran <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iN5qryQzcYI" class="postlink">Investigation</a>, and I don't see anything related to particles there. This leads me to conclusion that particles are located in _common.resources and _ordered.resources, and it's not possible to modify them, because there's currently no method to pack the files into the .resources format.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p247193" date="Posted: Wed Feb 27, 2013 8:52 pm "><author>vertex007</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@NX-317<br /><br />ok, thanks ....seems like a pain in the xss.... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mrgreen.gif" alt=":mrgreen:" title="Mr. Green" /><br />just wanted to play the lost missions levels with better textures and particles...<br />how about the other way around ?<br />take the lost mission levels and make those maps work in regular D3 ? maybe with sikkmod and everything ?<br />I bet also almost impossible due to the .resources format etc...<br />too bad BFG is really just a pain to mod ... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319224418im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p247194" date="Posted: Wed Feb 27, 2013 9:13 pm "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You can extract .resources, and perhaps .map files are not binarized, but .cm files are. So if you can get map files for lost missions, and unbinarized decls, maybe you can recompile maps in Doom 3 and run lost missions there.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p247195" date="Posted: Wed Feb 27, 2013 9:33 pm "><author>NX-317</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Should work, but Lost Missions have some new textures (examples that I remember: deltalabs textures repainted to red, also I saw one new Hell texture) and models (examples that I remember: terrains and structures in Hell levels), so these should be redone or somehow re-binarised. Or replaced with something else, in the worst case.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p247196" date="Posted: Wed Feb 27, 2013 9:35 pm "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I am not sure BFG can de-binarize assets. If it's even possible, the code is there for some one to make a tool that reconstruct original assets.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p247209" date="Posted: Thu Feb 28, 2013 11:33 am "><author>Tr3B</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It cannot convert back binary files to ascii files.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
