<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="26498"><title>DarkRadiant 1.7.3 released</title><posts><post id="p246480" date="Posted: Mon Feb 04, 2013 5:50 am "><author>LDAsh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">2013-02-02 DarkRadiant 1.7.3 released<br />This release contains a fix for a subtle but serious data corruption bug which caused non-worldspawn brush geometry to become corrupted after multiple save operations.<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130212115759/http://darkradiant.sourceforge.net/" class="postlink">http://darkradiant.sourceforge.net/</a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p246488" date="Posted: Mon Feb 04, 2013 1:43 pm "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for the update.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246494" date="Posted: Mon Feb 04, 2013 7:10 pm "><author>nbohr1more</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Greebo, the (retired) lead coder for The Dark Mod has been primarily absent from<br />the project on the coding side. He was responsible for about 99% of Dark Radiant's development<br />since branching from GTK Radiant.<br /><br />We were fortunate that Orbweaver, Tels, Grayman, Sotha, and (newcomer) Obsttorte worked<br />together to fix this bug. Obsttorte in particular wrote the corrected math translation code.<br /><br />Hopefully we'll see Greebo return briefly to help release Dark Radiant 1.8.<br /><br />I urge anyone with interest in helping with Dark Radiant development to stop by The Dark Mod forums or post here<br />and let us know.<br /><br /><br />Thanks,<br /><br />nbohr1more</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246496" date="Posted: Mon Feb 04, 2013 11:11 pm "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Cool stuff. Although it would be nice to fix animation playback for md5 models and func_door issues ( <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130212115759/https://github.com/orbweaver/DarkRadiant/issues?state=open">https://github.com/orbweaver/DarkRadian ... state=open</a><!-- m --> )<br /><br />Btw, is bugtracker kaput?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246497" date="Posted: Tue Feb 05, 2013 12:03 am "><author>nbohr1more</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Bugtracker is not kaput but the parties involved in fixing issues are very limited.<br /><br />If you post a thread in the forums about your issue it might get more visibility.<br /><br />That said, looking at the md5 preview report, I don't see replication steps.<br /><br />Did you try preview with Doom 3 base assets?<br /><br />It could be that something in Blender (etc) md5 formats is not quite compatible?<br /><br />If you attach a test map with an example md5 it would help evaluate.<br /><br />Beyond that I think that Dark Radiant may generally have problem producing much beyond brushes, patches,<br />particles, and trigger entities for non Dark Mod maps. The advised workflow would be to build your geometry in<br />Dark Radiant then add Doom 3 entities in Doom Edit for non Dark Mod maps AFAIK. I haven't heard much<br />one way or another?<br /><br />I suppose that (thus far) Doom 3 modders haven't been outspoken about this that much since they<br />are happy to have a better brush\patch editor than Doom Edit from a UI stance. But it might be good<br />to gather more Doom 3 oriented folks to the project and further delineate the Doom 3 project mode.<br /><br />Greebo has previously stated that he is not interested in merging Dark Radiant into the native Radiant<br />in Doom Edit but I think it would be a cool project. <br /><br /><br />Rant:<br /><br />It seems that other folks are more interested in starting from scratch and creating their own editing tools. <br />(At least that was how the ioDoom3 IRC was...)<br />More power to 'em but seeing those same said authors' projects' go idle seems to indicate how big of a task "starting from scratch" is. <br />If at least one of the tool makers just joined to help Dark Radiant it would make a world of difference to an already great tool. <br /><br />But I guess that's it... When you are trying to make a name for yourself, you don't wanna just slightly improve something that's good. <br />You wanna prove that you can make something radically new and bold. <br />Thus we have a bunch 'o fork projects all re-inventing the wheel rather than collaborating for the common good.<br />("I'm not gonna fix your smelly old code! I'm gonna write mine from scratch to run my way... the good way..." etc. )<br /><br />I am still interested in what some of the leading coders (left?) will show in terms of tools.<br />Jmarshall appears to have built quite a set already...<br />Tr3b, IIRC, was planning on selling his tools?<br /><br />At worst it'll just mean there are more diverse options for mappers. Though most will probably<br />gravitate to the ones with the most features rather than the "best" coded ones (stable, clean,<br />fast, etc.) Though Dark Radiant itself is a behemoth and might fall into that "most features" category <br />so "stones in glass houses" I suppose... (I think it's at least more light weight and clean than Doom Edit... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130212115759im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /> )<br /><br />End rant...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246498" date="Posted: Tue Feb 05, 2013 12:26 am "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There shouldn't be any issue regardless where MD5 comes from. Blender's exporter works extremely well and produces exactly the same MD5 files. Otherwise models wouldn't work in Doom 3.<br /><br />I tried loading vanilla Doom 3 models and the model viewer shows them fine. I have no idea how else would I play animation besides going into Entity &gt; MD5 Animation viewer &gt; selecting model def and then animation. Nothing is being rendered in the window. It doesn't work with vanilla Doom 3. Am I doing something wrong? <br /><br />I find DarkRadiant is pleasant to work with. DoomRadiant is horrible. Who came up with that z-window? o.O Plus, DarkRadiant is cross platform, and there is no way to have that happen with DoomRadiant without complete rewrite.<br /><br />Well, needless to say, there are a lot of folks like that in the FOSS community - rewrite is the thing (which doesn't make sense). Look at dhewm3 fork. Yeah, they made it cross platform, but because they don't like Windows they f$^ked it up so badly that we are still untangling ungodly SDL mess to get tools working again. Don't get me wrong, dhewm3 is the cleanest leanest fork of Doom 3 out there, but such approach has ruined it.<br /><br />Anyhow, not like MD5 animation support stops us from mapping, but it would be nice to have it working. And the func_door issue is really outrageous one, but since you mention math was rewritten in DarkRadiant, maybe in 1.7.3 it will work fine (haven't tried it yet).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246529" date="Posted: Wed Feb 06, 2013 9:01 pm "><author>gb_remake</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm using Netradiant for brushwork / patchwork in my current Doom 3 map, and Darkradiant for editing lights, sounds, particle effects etc. I prefer those to the built-in editor because my entire workflow is in Linux (also for my main project).<br /><br />Thanks for the update; what I'd really need a fix for is the problem where I cannot drag-resize brushes (and lights even) in DarkRadiant.<br /><br />I might have to finish my map under Windows with the built in editor. It looks like Doom 3 mapping is, for the foreseeable future, requiring Windows.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130212115759im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_neutral.gif" alt=":|" title="Neutral" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p246530" date="Posted: Wed Feb 06, 2013 9:14 pm "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Or run Doom 3 under WINE, that works too <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130212115759im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p246537" date="Posted: Thu Feb 07, 2013 2:34 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">gb_remake wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Thanks for the update; what I'd really need a fix for is the problem where I cannot drag-resize brushes (and lights even) in DarkRadiant.</div><br /><br />That's not a bug, it's a feature!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130212115759im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />View - entity list<br /><br />Then select the brush that's an entity (ie a func_static, door, whatever).  That entity is autoselected in the entity list.<br /><br />Click the "+" next to it and you'll see the work "Brush" appear below it.  Click on this and then you can change the brush properties.<br /><br />It makes sense from a technical point of view (you can't resize model entities after all) but from a practical POV I find it annoying.<br /><br />Since I'm on Windows I just use doomedit, but I use GTK 1.5 for my Quake 2 stuff, so I'd most likely use GTK 1.5 for D3 stuff if I needed to.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246544" date="Posted: Thu Feb 07, 2013 9:18 pm "><author>gb_remake</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, I can't drag resize <span style="font-style: italic">worldspawn brushes</span> (in Ubuntu 12.04), which kills it for me. But I can do that in netradiant I guess.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246547" date="Posted: Fri Feb 08, 2013 2:27 am "><author>motorsep</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It works for me. Just make sure you grab edge outside of the volume.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p246548" date="Posted: Fri Feb 08, 2013 2:31 am "><author>The Happy Friar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Or use the scale only function.  That's easier at times.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
