<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="2909"><title>ALERT: Official Doom3 Game bug report thread</title><posts><post id="p28523" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 7:22 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Please report all (suspected) bugs related to the GAME here.
<br /><br />Make sure to also include your system specs as follows:
<br /><br />CPU
<br />GPU (+used driver version)
<br />RAM
<br />Soundcard
<br />OS
<br />Overclocked anything - if yes, what if no then post: O/C no
<br />Any special cvar settings you've made
<br />FSAA - if yes, which setting</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28571" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 9:50 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-weight: bold">Server browser bug</span>
<br /><br />I've noticed the ingame server browser has a few problems when attempting to sort or filter the list in any way, and actually misreports selected servers. If the server browser is left alone, each listed server is correct - but attempting to resort that list in any way, causes your client to connect to the wrong server.
<br /><br />For instance, I sort the servers by ping and attempt to join a local server with no players and an 80ms ping - I end up joining a server halfway across the world with players already in it, and an astronomical ping time.
<br /><br />This doesn't seem to be related to configuration or specific hardware settings, as I've seen this issue manifest on a wide number of systems. I suspect that it effects everyone, and have gotten lots of complaints about lag when on Australian servers by Americans who attempted to join more local servers. But for reference's sake, here's my specs:
<br /><br />CPU: Pentium 4 3GHz, 800FSB (Northwood).
<br />MOBO: ASUS P4P800 Deluxe, 865PE chipset.
<br />GPU: Sapphire branded Radeon 9800XT, 256MB model plus Catalyst 4.7's and beta 4.9's.
<br />RAM: 1024MB (2x512MB) DDR400 Kingmax.
<br />Sound: Creative Audigy 2 ZS Platinum Pro.
<br />OS: Windows XP Pro SP1, up to date.
<br /><br />No overclockings. No real CVAR modifications. No FSAA used.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28586" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 10:55 pm "><author>eskimo roll</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There's also the Snow bug? that may be a driver/overclocking issue, or whatever.
<br />Here's a screenie of the problem:
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920im_/http://levi.me.uk/_levi/d3/img/d3_snow.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Read this thread to find out more on that one:
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2851">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2851</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28596" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 11:28 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">eskimo roll wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">There's also the Snow bug? that may be a driver/overclocking issue, or whatever.</div>
<br /><br />That looks like a video card problem. It can come from overclocking or overheating, but can also be a hardware fault with the card/chipset itself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28613" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 12:05 am "><author>duff_moss</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have an issue which I originally reported as snow, but not like the screenshot above - it's more like static. Others are seeing this also, and from  the limited knowledge about the issue, it appears at this stage to be an issue with the ATI OpenGL driver on certain cards.
<br /><br />ATI Radeon 9800 Pro (128Meg - currently using Cat 4.7 but tired many others, including Omega 2.5.88)
<br />2.8GHz Pentium IV
<br />1Gig DDR400 RAM
<br />200Gig SATA Hard Drive
<br />Gigabyte Motherboard (GA-8I series of some sort)
<br />Windows XP SP1</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28712" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 3:07 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Basically, "use" in the PDA GUI is bound to "fire" instead of defaulting to the L-mouse button. Which is stupid and awkward, but not a game-breaker. <br /><br />In other words, to click on something on the PDA screen, I have to move the mouse pointer to the right place, and then hit my "fire" key (which is "E" on the keyboard). In order to scroll through a PDA email, I need to hold down fire/E while moving the mouse. <br /><br />They should have just had *all* mouse behavior revert to normal while using the PDA, but probably didn't anticipate/test with an unusual config. Bleh. </div>
<br />Thanks pjw for reporting this!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28787" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:49 am "><author>mudvin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">sizeDown command sizes viewport down, and moves it to the left lower corner, while it should be centered. This is obvious a bug.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28802" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:30 am "><author>shalstus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Im using a:
<br /><br />ati radeon 9700 mobility 128 mb
<br />512mb ram
<br />sigmatel audio driver
<br />2.8 ghz
<br />windows xp
<br />no overclocking
<br />the only thing i tried was changing the cachemeg from 20 to 64 but i only got slightly longer gameplay (5-10 mins.)
<br /><br />constantly locking up at random points during gameplay.
<br />i tried my standard drivers as well as the beta catalyst driver to no avail.
<br />please HELP!!!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28812" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:56 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Link to Activision support page for Doom3
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt/" class="postlink">Link</a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28814" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:58 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">_shank wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt" class="postlink">Link to Activison support for Doom3</a></div>
<br /><br />Should we consider that as a bug?
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28817" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 8:01 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">_shank wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt" class="postlink">Link to Activison support for Doom3</a></div><br /><br />Should we consider that as a bug?<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>
<br /><br />its away to resolve the bug's (bbcode is so picky...took me some time to get the link made)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28891" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 1:09 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">ok, the fix to enable 5.1 sound is to change the settings in the control panel. But what does that mean? Do I now every time I want to watch a dvd go back to 7.1 (I guess so)? Or should this setting even be 5.1 for 5.1 movies? Shouldn't Doom3 accept 7.1 as a setting and switch to 5.1 internally (if yes, a fix please, id!). I don't mind that my centre back speaker is mute for Doom3, but I like to still watch my 6.1 dvds in 6.1, without changing the setting all the time!!!</div>
<br />Thanks fergusdog for reporting this in!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28894" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 1:24 pm "><author>Qwertys</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i killed an IMP in a doorway and i don't remember if the door just opened or not but the imp got stuck and was spinning rapidly before it melted. kinda wierd seems a bug in the physics code.
<br /><br />On my video card (PNY Geforce 4 4200) the game was olmost pitch black at default settings, all i could see was lighting flares and GUI's. after changing the r_renderer to NV10 it went away (it was using a default NV20 path).
<br />Intel 2.5ghz on Intel D865PERL
<br />Audigy2
<br />1gb ram
<br />WinXP SP1.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28936" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 3:35 pm "><author>mattwill1</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I can open the game and play for five minutes at most, but then it closes and goes back to windows with no error or anything. All drivers are the most up to date from manufacturer's website and windows display settings match those in the game.  I've tried everything. Help!!! 
<br /><br />System: 
<br />CPU - Athalon XP 2200+ 1.8Ghz
<br />GPU - NVidia GeForce3 Ti 200    Driver = v62.11
<br />RAM - 512 MB DDR
<br />Sound Card - Vinyl AC'97
<br />O/C no</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28980" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 5:09 pm "><author>dhughes</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The game installed without a problem, and seemed to be fine when it first started (id intro was perfect)... then, when the next screens came up all the graphics turned into a garbled mess! The cursor, text, and other images come and go and I can't see what I'm doing at all. I've read through other posts that mention anything about weird graphics and done whatever they suggested for those (updated all drivers, etc.) and no matter what, I still have the same garbled graphics. 
<br /><br />I also thought that maybe if I got past the setup screens, the game might be okay... nope, the same thing happens even when I start a new game. 
<br /><br />Please help, I'd like to at least play the game~ 
<br />dhughes 
<br /><br />btw.. i ran dxdiag.. and it didn't show anything was wrong. 
<br />no overclocking either~ 
<br /><br />win xp sp1 
<br />2.8 ghz 
<br />512 ram 
<br />ati 9700 pro 4.7 
<br />sblive 5.1
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222920/http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v431/dhughes_/garbledgraphics.jpg">http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v431/ ... aphics.jpg</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />!!!Just wanted to post the outcome... turns out my Dell video card, was defective from the beginning. I saw little signs (and didn't recognize them as such) from day one, but because the programs I normally run didn't seem affected, I didn't question the occasional "artifacting"~ After weeks of trying A to Z to "fix" the graphics for Doom 3~ I switched cards, first with an identical ATI 9700 pro 128 (this one purchased from retail store) ... results.. no problems, no artifacts... then, I put my OLD Nvidia Ti 500 in, with the same results (although a bit slower), no artifacts.
<br /><br />So, I can now play Doom 3~ and will NOT BE purchasing any more systems from Dell.com!
<br /><br />Thanks for everyones input...
<br />dhughes</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29012" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:24 pm "><author>Feffer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Doom3 crashes after the cut scenes if they are allowed to play to completion, completely freezing the computer and requiring a hard reboot (removing the battery on the laptop).  It also runs choppy prior to this point.
<br /><br />The laptop is a dell (i'm sorry i don't have the make and model currently as it isn't mine, i will edit it in when i can to add more information).
<br /><br />Processor: Pentium 3.4 EE (i believe)
<br />Ram: at least 1gb
<br />Video Card: Radeon 9700 128mb
<br />Sound: unsure
<br />OS: WinXP home
<br /><br />Nothing has been overclocked unless it shipped that way.  We have attempted loading all the newest drivers (mb, sound, ati) to ensure that is not the problem.  We are also going to try the other recommendations from the activsion help site, and if any solution is found i'll edit and post here.  Any help is required (my father is dying to play this and won't be home to his home pc till next week).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29068" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 8:34 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Feffer wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Processor: Pentium 3.4 EE (i believe)</div>
<br /><br />On a laptop? I don't think so.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29130" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 10:55 pm "><author>DudeMiester</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok multiplayer has stopped working entirely for me. Whenever I click to join a server and it connect, Doom 3 shuts down. However, I can create servers with no problem. What's even stranger is that it was working fine before, and now it has died. I have made no multiplayer or networking modifications to the DoomConfig.
<br /><br />Another bug. When using com_allowConsole 1 and -nointro, the main menu doesn't load, only the console shows up and it takes up the entire screen. However, when you type com_allowConsole 0 into the console, the main menu loads, and you can use Doom 3 like normal.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29327" date="Posted: Fri Aug 06, 2004 9:11 am "><author>Skitso</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">My system:
<br /><br />Gf Ti4200 64MB
<br />AMD 2600+
<br />512Mt RAM
<br /><br />The problem: The game seems to use rasterized lighting, smoke and shadow effects like the game wouldn't be in 32-bit mode. The game looks just fine and smooth in my friends computer that has Radeon 9700.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29584" date="Posted: Fri Aug 06, 2004 7:52 pm "><author>organic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have crashes which happen at the same points in the game every single time.  For example, in mars_city2, I step up to one particular door and it hangs; in the next level after that, there's a cutscene when you walk out of the elevator and the camera flies through an airvent and shows the bald guy w/ sunglasses talking to someone else, well the game hangs every single time when the bald heads come into the frame... wierdness...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179720" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 10:15 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've been loading some maps using the console and when I finish the particular part of a map and it's time to go to the next part, I keep a console error unable to find "current map name".proc  This has happened to me with three different maps. Does anyone have any idea as to what's happening here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179784" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:29 am "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Here's what I think it is.  1.3.1. has been built with the 64 bit vista in mind and it's dumb-founded when ran on a 32 bit os. Doom 3 was built for 32 bits and so was all the patches up to 1.3.1.  It's appearing to me, that it's a case of 'either, or'... not 'both' when it comes to software, especially in this case.  Personally, I think that 1.3.1. is a beta and hasn't been tested properly.  I'm not a pro here, nor do I claim to be a 'puter wiz', but there are times where it doesn't take a 'rocket scientist' to see what's going on, just one to explain it!  I want to help with this and I'll do my best.</div>
<br /><br />To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a>
<br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.
<br /><br />The Mac developers Aspyr did an independent QA test of their build.
<br /><br />We've been running the patch on our servers since release with no problems. My mod server has had nearly 400 individual players connect to it since it was upgraded to 1.3.1.
<br /><br />Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.
<br /><br />I think it is also useful to clear up some terminology. A "crash" is when the game does something unexpected and can't recover from it. Like simply dropping back to the desktop or giving you one of those error boxes like you have seen.
<br /><br />Other problems, such as the DLL API message, are not "crashes" but are genuine error conditions that the game has detected and reported to you (a mod built for a different release in this case).
<br /><br />One thing you could try is to do disable EAX/OpenAL. I've had one player recently whose D3 would crash on startup when these were enabled.
<br /><br />You can do this by editing DoomConfig.cfg and making sure the appropriate values are set to zero.
<br /><br />  seta s_useEAXReverb "0"
<br />  seta s_useOpenAL "0"
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179812" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 4:47 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.</div>
<br /><br />Thank you for the correction in a professional manner.  You are correct, I used the wrong term.  "<span style="color: red"><span style="font-style: italic">Freezes</span></span>" explains it exactly.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179817" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 6:20 pm "><author>AnthonyJa</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/images/m005.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div>
<br /><br />Agreed that in general they're not too helpful. However you can sometimes get some info from them. If you click the "click here" link, you'll get another dialog which shows some basic information about the crash. Significantly, it shows the module, which can sometimes point you at the problem (eg if its "nvogl.dll" then its probably an nVidia OpenGL issue).
<br /><br />If its in gamex86.dll, and you're running a mod, the mod author may be able to use the "faulting address" to tell you something about the crash.
<br /><br />Also while its open, depending on how your Windows is configured there might be a .mdmp file hanging around in your temp directory associated with this crash, which might be helpful to a programmer to trace the issue. It'll probably get deleted as you close the dialog though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179822" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 7:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div>
<br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179839" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 9:49 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div><br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>
<br /><br />Yes, I realise that. I was linking so you could read the info about the release straight from the developer who created it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179842" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:37 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />Thank you, [for me] reading that garble doesn't help me any... I wish it does.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179849" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 11:02 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hehe im not at all surprised im one of the few (?)
<br />people who has problems with the new patch, i had the same
<br />bs with the 1.32 patch for far cry (altho THAT patch was so flawed
<br />crytec or whatever theyre called actually withdrew it),
<br />i also had serious issues with that MoH box (dont rememebr the name but it had 4 cd-s in it) but i googled that and many had issues with that
<br />as well, sometimes i just wanna take the comp and chuck it
<br />through the window and just "retire" to some console   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br />For the time being, if not forever, im sticking with the 1.3 patch</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180031" date="Posted: Wed Jun 06, 2007 9:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Could anyone tell me why when I go to activate the EAX in the sound options menu, it freezes my system?  I have the Audigy 2 zs Platinum SB sound card with <span style="color: red"><span style="font-weight: bold">ALL</span></span> the updated bells and whistles.  EAX console, DTS, the whole nine yards.  There's no logical reason why this option should freeze my system.  I saw an eax update for doom3, but there's no way I'm going to uninstall my current Creative software and drivers to install this crap.  There has to be some way to activate this feature, I have this option in my current software. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p180102" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 11:52 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The cvar for enabling EAX is s_useEAXReverb. You could try adding...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">s_useEAXReverb 1</div>
<br /><br />... to DoomConfig.cfg</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180138" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 6:18 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I did and it froze Doom 3 while I tried to apply the setting within the menu and entering the attribute within the cfg file gives me this.  Doom 3 doesn't even load... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://i199.photobucket.com/albums/aa319/mac53_2007/error1.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />Issue resolved thanks to Doomworld.  This is an issue pertaining just to Creative "Soundblaster" Audigy series cards.  If you using Creative and want the EAX reverb and are not able to get it to function, then here is a link that will answer many questions pertaining to this.
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432/http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster">http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />There's also a software that installs the proper API to make Doom 3's EAX HD reverb functional.  If I get enough requests, I can upload this API software and post the link to it here.
<br /><br />EAX issue resolved. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205013" date="Posted: Wed Sep 17, 2008 8:12 pm "><author>undergroundleo</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi, im new to this forum...<br /><br />I builded a new pc and these are the specs:<br /><br />CPU: AMD phenom 9850 2.5Ghz<br />Memory: Corsair XMS2 DDR2 800Mhz<br />Video: 2x EVGA 9800GT in SLI mode<br />Motherboard: Asus M3N-HT Deluxe<br />HDD: Western Digital Caviar 250GB<br /><br />When i play doom 3, i get to play for about a minute or two, and then my PC shuts down completely... i need to power it on and then wait till it shows some video, sometimes i need to reset it 2 or 3 times because it doesnt show any video at all...<br /><br />I think i have a Drivers issue, but i want to know how can i fix it... please help...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205028" date="Posted: Thu Sep 18, 2008 7:12 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It abruptly powers off? That sounds like a hardware issue. How long have you had this new PC? A few days?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p241890" date="Posted: Sun Aug 19, 2012 3:38 pm "><author>justukyte</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have problems with the display. All characters appear to be half in light and half in shadow.<br /><br />Here's a screenshot of what it looks like:<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222432im_/http://s10.postimage.org/f5uksl3zd/graphics_problem.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />My system:<br />CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.80 GHZ<br />RAM: 4 GB DDR2<br />GPU: Intel G41 Express Chipset (driver version 8.15.10.2555)<br />Sound card: Realtek HD audio<br />OS: Windows 7 Ultimate x64 bit SP1<br />No overclock</div>]]></body></post><post id="p241892" date="Posted: Sun Aug 19, 2012 3:48 pm "><author>=FF=Sturm</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Not a fan of integrated video cards, but I guess that your problem is caused by video drivers.<br /><br />Check for updates.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179720" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 10:15 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've been loading some maps using the console and when I finish the particular part of a map and it's time to go to the next part, I keep a console error unable to find "current map name".proc  This has happened to me with three different maps. Does anyone have any idea as to what's happening here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179784" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:29 am "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Here's what I think it is.  1.3.1. has been built with the 64 bit vista in mind and it's dumb-founded when ran on a 32 bit os. Doom 3 was built for 32 bits and so was all the patches up to 1.3.1.  It's appearing to me, that it's a case of 'either, or'... not 'both' when it comes to software, especially in this case.  Personally, I think that 1.3.1. is a beta and hasn't been tested properly.  I'm not a pro here, nor do I claim to be a 'puter wiz', but there are times where it doesn't take a 'rocket scientist' to see what's going on, just one to explain it!  I want to help with this and I'll do my best.</div>
<br /><br />To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a>
<br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.
<br /><br />The Mac developers Aspyr did an independent QA test of their build.
<br /><br />We've been running the patch on our servers since release with no problems. My mod server has had nearly 400 individual players connect to it since it was upgraded to 1.3.1.
<br /><br />Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.
<br /><br />I think it is also useful to clear up some terminology. A "crash" is when the game does something unexpected and can't recover from it. Like simply dropping back to the desktop or giving you one of those error boxes like you have seen.
<br /><br />Other problems, such as the DLL API message, are not "crashes" but are genuine error conditions that the game has detected and reported to you (a mod built for a different release in this case).
<br /><br />One thing you could try is to do disable EAX/OpenAL. I've had one player recently whose D3 would crash on startup when these were enabled.
<br /><br />You can do this by editing DoomConfig.cfg and making sure the appropriate values are set to zero.
<br /><br />  seta s_useEAXReverb "0"
<br />  seta s_useOpenAL "0"
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179812" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 4:47 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.</div>
<br /><br />Thank you for the correction in a professional manner.  You are correct, I used the wrong term.  "<span style="color: red"><span style="font-style: italic">Freezes</span></span>" explains it exactly.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179817" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 6:20 pm "><author>AnthonyJa</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233im_/http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/images/m005.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div>
<br /><br />Agreed that in general they're not too helpful. However you can sometimes get some info from them. If you click the "click here" link, you'll get another dialog which shows some basic information about the crash. Significantly, it shows the module, which can sometimes point you at the problem (eg if its "nvogl.dll" then its probably an nVidia OpenGL issue).
<br /><br />If its in gamex86.dll, and you're running a mod, the mod author may be able to use the "faulting address" to tell you something about the crash.
<br /><br />Also while its open, depending on how your Windows is configured there might be a .mdmp file hanging around in your temp directory associated with this crash, which might be helpful to a programmer to trace the issue. It'll probably get deleted as you close the dialog though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179822" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 7:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div>
<br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179839" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 9:49 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div><br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>
<br /><br />Yes, I realise that. I was linking so you could read the info about the release straight from the developer who created it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179842" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:37 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />Thank you, [for me] reading that garble doesn't help me any... I wish it does.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179849" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 11:02 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hehe im not at all surprised im one of the few (?)
<br />people who has problems with the new patch, i had the same
<br />bs with the 1.32 patch for far cry (altho THAT patch was so flawed
<br />crytec or whatever theyre called actually withdrew it),
<br />i also had serious issues with that MoH box (dont rememebr the name but it had 4 cd-s in it) but i googled that and many had issues with that
<br />as well, sometimes i just wanna take the comp and chuck it
<br />through the window and just "retire" to some console   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br />For the time being, if not forever, im sticking with the 1.3 patch</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180031" date="Posted: Wed Jun 06, 2007 9:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Could anyone tell me why when I go to activate the EAX in the sound options menu, it freezes my system?  I have the Audigy 2 zs Platinum SB sound card with <span style="color: red"><span style="font-weight: bold">ALL</span></span> the updated bells and whistles.  EAX console, DTS, the whole nine yards.  There's no logical reason why this option should freeze my system.  I saw an eax update for doom3, but there's no way I'm going to uninstall my current Creative software and drivers to install this crap.  There has to be some way to activate this feature, I have this option in my current software. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p180102" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 11:52 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The cvar for enabling EAX is s_useEAXReverb. You could try adding...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">s_useEAXReverb 1</div>
<br /><br />... to DoomConfig.cfg</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180138" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 6:18 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I did and it froze Doom 3 while I tried to apply the setting within the menu and entering the attribute within the cfg file gives me this.  Doom 3 doesn't even load... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233im_/http://i199.photobucket.com/albums/aa319/mac53_2007/error1.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />Issue resolved thanks to Doomworld.  This is an issue pertaining just to Creative "Soundblaster" Audigy series cards.  If you using Creative and want the EAX reverb and are not able to get it to function, then here is a link that will answer many questions pertaining to this.
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233/http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster">http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />There's also a software that installs the proper API to make Doom 3's EAX HD reverb functional.  If I get enough requests, I can upload this API software and post the link to it here.
<br /><br />EAX issue resolved. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224200233im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205013" date="Posted: Wed Sep 17, 2008 8:12 pm "><author>undergroundleo</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi, im new to this forum...<br /><br />I builded a new pc and these are the specs:<br /><br />CPU: AMD phenom 9850 2.5Ghz<br />Memory: Corsair XMS2 DDR2 800Mhz<br />Video: 2x EVGA 9800GT in SLI mode<br />Motherboard: Asus M3N-HT Deluxe<br />HDD: Western Digital Caviar 250GB<br /><br />When i play doom 3, i get to play for about a minute or two, and then my PC shuts down completely... i need to power it on and then wait till it shows some video, sometimes i need to reset it 2 or 3 times because it doesnt show any video at all...<br /><br />I think i have a Drivers issue, but i want to know how can i fix it... please help...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205028" date="Posted: Thu Sep 18, 2008 7:12 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It abruptly powers off? That sounds like a hardware issue. How long have you had this new PC? A few days?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28523" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 7:22 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Please report all (suspected) bugs related to the GAME here.
<br /><br />Make sure to also include your system specs as follows:
<br /><br />CPU
<br />GPU (+used driver version)
<br />RAM
<br />Soundcard
<br />OS
<br />Overclocked anything - if yes, what if no then post: O/C no
<br />Any special cvar settings you've made
<br />FSAA - if yes, which setting</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28571" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 9:50 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-weight: bold">Server browser bug</span>
<br /><br />I've noticed the ingame server browser has a few problems when attempting to sort or filter the list in any way, and actually misreports selected servers. If the server browser is left alone, each listed server is correct - but attempting to resort that list in any way, causes your client to connect to the wrong server.
<br /><br />For instance, I sort the servers by ping and attempt to join a local server with no players and an 80ms ping - I end up joining a server halfway across the world with players already in it, and an astronomical ping time.
<br /><br />This doesn't seem to be related to configuration or specific hardware settings, as I've seen this issue manifest on a wide number of systems. I suspect that it effects everyone, and have gotten lots of complaints about lag when on Australian servers by Americans who attempted to join more local servers. But for reference's sake, here's my specs:
<br /><br />CPU: Pentium 4 3GHz, 800FSB (Northwood).
<br />MOBO: ASUS P4P800 Deluxe, 865PE chipset.
<br />GPU: Sapphire branded Radeon 9800XT, 256MB model plus Catalyst 4.7's and beta 4.9's.
<br />RAM: 1024MB (2x512MB) DDR400 Kingmax.
<br />Sound: Creative Audigy 2 ZS Platinum Pro.
<br />OS: Windows XP Pro SP1, up to date.
<br /><br />No overclockings. No real CVAR modifications. No FSAA used.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28586" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 10:55 pm "><author>eskimo roll</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There's also the Snow bug? that may be a driver/overclocking issue, or whatever.
<br />Here's a screenie of the problem:
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144im_/http://levi.me.uk/_levi/d3/img/d3_snow.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Read this thread to find out more on that one:
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2851">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2851</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28596" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 11:28 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">eskimo roll wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">There's also the Snow bug? that may be a driver/overclocking issue, or whatever.</div>
<br /><br />That looks like a video card problem. It can come from overclocking or overheating, but can also be a hardware fault with the card/chipset itself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28613" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 12:05 am "><author>duff_moss</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have an issue which I originally reported as snow, but not like the screenshot above - it's more like static. Others are seeing this also, and from  the limited knowledge about the issue, it appears at this stage to be an issue with the ATI OpenGL driver on certain cards.
<br /><br />ATI Radeon 9800 Pro (128Meg - currently using Cat 4.7 but tired many others, including Omega 2.5.88)
<br />2.8GHz Pentium IV
<br />1Gig DDR400 RAM
<br />200Gig SATA Hard Drive
<br />Gigabyte Motherboard (GA-8I series of some sort)
<br />Windows XP SP1</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28712" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 3:07 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Basically, "use" in the PDA GUI is bound to "fire" instead of defaulting to the L-mouse button. Which is stupid and awkward, but not a game-breaker. <br /><br />In other words, to click on something on the PDA screen, I have to move the mouse pointer to the right place, and then hit my "fire" key (which is "E" on the keyboard). In order to scroll through a PDA email, I need to hold down fire/E while moving the mouse. <br /><br />They should have just had *all* mouse behavior revert to normal while using the PDA, but probably didn't anticipate/test with an unusual config. Bleh. </div>
<br />Thanks pjw for reporting this!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28787" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:49 am "><author>mudvin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">sizeDown command sizes viewport down, and moves it to the left lower corner, while it should be centered. This is obvious a bug.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28802" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:30 am "><author>shalstus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Im using a:
<br /><br />ati radeon 9700 mobility 128 mb
<br />512mb ram
<br />sigmatel audio driver
<br />2.8 ghz
<br />windows xp
<br />no overclocking
<br />the only thing i tried was changing the cachemeg from 20 to 64 but i only got slightly longer gameplay (5-10 mins.)
<br /><br />constantly locking up at random points during gameplay.
<br />i tried my standard drivers as well as the beta catalyst driver to no avail.
<br />please HELP!!!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28812" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:56 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Link to Activision support page for Doom3
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt/" class="postlink">Link</a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28814" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:58 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">_shank wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt" class="postlink">Link to Activison support for Doom3</a></div>
<br /><br />Should we consider that as a bug?
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28817" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 8:01 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">_shank wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt" class="postlink">Link to Activison support for Doom3</a></div><br /><br />Should we consider that as a bug?<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>
<br /><br />its away to resolve the bug's (bbcode is so picky...took me some time to get the link made)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28891" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 1:09 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">ok, the fix to enable 5.1 sound is to change the settings in the control panel. But what does that mean? Do I now every time I want to watch a dvd go back to 7.1 (I guess so)? Or should this setting even be 5.1 for 5.1 movies? Shouldn't Doom3 accept 7.1 as a setting and switch to 5.1 internally (if yes, a fix please, id!). I don't mind that my centre back speaker is mute for Doom3, but I like to still watch my 6.1 dvds in 6.1, without changing the setting all the time!!!</div>
<br />Thanks fergusdog for reporting this in!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28894" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 1:24 pm "><author>Qwertys</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i killed an IMP in a doorway and i don't remember if the door just opened or not but the imp got stuck and was spinning rapidly before it melted. kinda wierd seems a bug in the physics code.
<br /><br />On my video card (PNY Geforce 4 4200) the game was olmost pitch black at default settings, all i could see was lighting flares and GUI's. after changing the r_renderer to NV10 it went away (it was using a default NV20 path).
<br />Intel 2.5ghz on Intel D865PERL
<br />Audigy2
<br />1gb ram
<br />WinXP SP1.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28936" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 3:35 pm "><author>mattwill1</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I can open the game and play for five minutes at most, but then it closes and goes back to windows with no error or anything. All drivers are the most up to date from manufacturer's website and windows display settings match those in the game.  I've tried everything. Help!!! 
<br /><br />System: 
<br />CPU - Athalon XP 2200+ 1.8Ghz
<br />GPU - NVidia GeForce3 Ti 200    Driver = v62.11
<br />RAM - 512 MB DDR
<br />Sound Card - Vinyl AC'97
<br />O/C no</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28980" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 5:09 pm "><author>dhughes</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The game installed without a problem, and seemed to be fine when it first started (id intro was perfect)... then, when the next screens came up all the graphics turned into a garbled mess! The cursor, text, and other images come and go and I can't see what I'm doing at all. I've read through other posts that mention anything about weird graphics and done whatever they suggested for those (updated all drivers, etc.) and no matter what, I still have the same garbled graphics. 
<br /><br />I also thought that maybe if I got past the setup screens, the game might be okay... nope, the same thing happens even when I start a new game. 
<br /><br />Please help, I'd like to at least play the game~ 
<br />dhughes 
<br /><br />btw.. i ran dxdiag.. and it didn't show anything was wrong. 
<br />no overclocking either~ 
<br /><br />win xp sp1 
<br />2.8 ghz 
<br />512 ram 
<br />ati 9700 pro 4.7 
<br />sblive 5.1
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v431/dhughes_/garbledgraphics.jpg">http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v431/ ... aphics.jpg</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />!!!Just wanted to post the outcome... turns out my Dell video card, was defective from the beginning. I saw little signs (and didn't recognize them as such) from day one, but because the programs I normally run didn't seem affected, I didn't question the occasional "artifacting"~ After weeks of trying A to Z to "fix" the graphics for Doom 3~ I switched cards, first with an identical ATI 9700 pro 128 (this one purchased from retail store) ... results.. no problems, no artifacts... then, I put my OLD Nvidia Ti 500 in, with the same results (although a bit slower), no artifacts.
<br /><br />So, I can now play Doom 3~ and will NOT BE purchasing any more systems from Dell.com!
<br /><br />Thanks for everyones input...
<br />dhughes</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29012" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:24 pm "><author>Feffer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Doom3 crashes after the cut scenes if they are allowed to play to completion, completely freezing the computer and requiring a hard reboot (removing the battery on the laptop).  It also runs choppy prior to this point.
<br /><br />The laptop is a dell (i'm sorry i don't have the make and model currently as it isn't mine, i will edit it in when i can to add more information).
<br /><br />Processor: Pentium 3.4 EE (i believe)
<br />Ram: at least 1gb
<br />Video Card: Radeon 9700 128mb
<br />Sound: unsure
<br />OS: WinXP home
<br /><br />Nothing has been overclocked unless it shipped that way.  We have attempted loading all the newest drivers (mb, sound, ati) to ensure that is not the problem.  We are also going to try the other recommendations from the activsion help site, and if any solution is found i'll edit and post here.  Any help is required (my father is dying to play this and won't be home to his home pc till next week).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29068" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 8:34 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Feffer wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Processor: Pentium 3.4 EE (i believe)</div>
<br /><br />On a laptop? I don't think so.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29130" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 10:55 pm "><author>DudeMiester</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok multiplayer has stopped working entirely for me. Whenever I click to join a server and it connect, Doom 3 shuts down. However, I can create servers with no problem. What's even stranger is that it was working fine before, and now it has died. I have made no multiplayer or networking modifications to the DoomConfig.
<br /><br />Another bug. When using com_allowConsole 1 and -nointro, the main menu doesn't load, only the console shows up and it takes up the entire screen. However, when you type com_allowConsole 0 into the console, the main menu loads, and you can use Doom 3 like normal.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29327" date="Posted: Fri Aug 06, 2004 9:11 am "><author>Skitso</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">My system:
<br /><br />Gf Ti4200 64MB
<br />AMD 2600+
<br />512Mt RAM
<br /><br />The problem: The game seems to use rasterized lighting, smoke and shadow effects like the game wouldn't be in 32-bit mode. The game looks just fine and smooth in my friends computer that has Radeon 9700.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29584" date="Posted: Fri Aug 06, 2004 7:52 pm "><author>organic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have crashes which happen at the same points in the game every single time.  For example, in mars_city2, I step up to one particular door and it hangs; in the next level after that, there's a cutscene when you walk out of the elevator and the camera flies through an airvent and shows the bald guy w/ sunglasses talking to someone else, well the game hangs every single time when the bald heads come into the frame... wierdness...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179720" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 10:15 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've been loading some maps using the console and when I finish the particular part of a map and it's time to go to the next part, I keep a console error unable to find "current map name".proc  This has happened to me with three different maps. Does anyone have any idea as to what's happening here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179784" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:29 am "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Here's what I think it is.  1.3.1. has been built with the 64 bit vista in mind and it's dumb-founded when ran on a 32 bit os. Doom 3 was built for 32 bits and so was all the patches up to 1.3.1.  It's appearing to me, that it's a case of 'either, or'... not 'both' when it comes to software, especially in this case.  Personally, I think that 1.3.1. is a beta and hasn't been tested properly.  I'm not a pro here, nor do I claim to be a 'puter wiz', but there are times where it doesn't take a 'rocket scientist' to see what's going on, just one to explain it!  I want to help with this and I'll do my best.</div>
<br /><br />To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a>
<br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.
<br /><br />The Mac developers Aspyr did an independent QA test of their build.
<br /><br />We've been running the patch on our servers since release with no problems. My mod server has had nearly 400 individual players connect to it since it was upgraded to 1.3.1.
<br /><br />Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.
<br /><br />I think it is also useful to clear up some terminology. A "crash" is when the game does something unexpected and can't recover from it. Like simply dropping back to the desktop or giving you one of those error boxes like you have seen.
<br /><br />Other problems, such as the DLL API message, are not "crashes" but are genuine error conditions that the game has detected and reported to you (a mod built for a different release in this case).
<br /><br />One thing you could try is to do disable EAX/OpenAL. I've had one player recently whose D3 would crash on startup when these were enabled.
<br /><br />You can do this by editing DoomConfig.cfg and making sure the appropriate values are set to zero.
<br /><br />  seta s_useEAXReverb "0"
<br />  seta s_useOpenAL "0"
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179812" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 4:47 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.</div>
<br /><br />Thank you for the correction in a professional manner.  You are correct, I used the wrong term.  "<span style="color: red"><span style="font-style: italic">Freezes</span></span>" explains it exactly.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179817" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 6:20 pm "><author>AnthonyJa</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/images/m005.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div>
<br /><br />Agreed that in general they're not too helpful. However you can sometimes get some info from them. If you click the "click here" link, you'll get another dialog which shows some basic information about the crash. Significantly, it shows the module, which can sometimes point you at the problem (eg if its "nvogl.dll" then its probably an nVidia OpenGL issue).
<br /><br />If its in gamex86.dll, and you're running a mod, the mod author may be able to use the "faulting address" to tell you something about the crash.
<br /><br />Also while its open, depending on how your Windows is configured there might be a .mdmp file hanging around in your temp directory associated with this crash, which might be helpful to a programmer to trace the issue. It'll probably get deleted as you close the dialog though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179822" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 7:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div>
<br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179839" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 9:49 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div><br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>
<br /><br />Yes, I realise that. I was linking so you could read the info about the release straight from the developer who created it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179842" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:37 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />Thank you, [for me] reading that garble doesn't help me any... I wish it does.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179849" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 11:02 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hehe im not at all surprised im one of the few (?)
<br />people who has problems with the new patch, i had the same
<br />bs with the 1.32 patch for far cry (altho THAT patch was so flawed
<br />crytec or whatever theyre called actually withdrew it),
<br />i also had serious issues with that MoH box (dont rememebr the name but it had 4 cd-s in it) but i googled that and many had issues with that
<br />as well, sometimes i just wanna take the comp and chuck it
<br />through the window and just "retire" to some console   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br />For the time being, if not forever, im sticking with the 1.3 patch</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180031" date="Posted: Wed Jun 06, 2007 9:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Could anyone tell me why when I go to activate the EAX in the sound options menu, it freezes my system?  I have the Audigy 2 zs Platinum SB sound card with <span style="color: red"><span style="font-weight: bold">ALL</span></span> the updated bells and whistles.  EAX console, DTS, the whole nine yards.  There's no logical reason why this option should freeze my system.  I saw an eax update for doom3, but there's no way I'm going to uninstall my current Creative software and drivers to install this crap.  There has to be some way to activate this feature, I have this option in my current software. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p180102" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 11:52 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The cvar for enabling EAX is s_useEAXReverb. You could try adding...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">s_useEAXReverb 1</div>
<br /><br />... to DoomConfig.cfg</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180138" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 6:18 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I did and it froze Doom 3 while I tried to apply the setting within the menu and entering the attribute within the cfg file gives me this.  Doom 3 doesn't even load... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://i199.photobucket.com/albums/aa319/mac53_2007/error1.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />Issue resolved thanks to Doomworld.  This is an issue pertaining just to Creative "Soundblaster" Audigy series cards.  If you using Creative and want the EAX reverb and are not able to get it to function, then here is a link that will answer many questions pertaining to this.
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster">http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />There's also a software that installs the proper API to make Doom 3's EAX HD reverb functional.  If I get enough requests, I can upload this API software and post the link to it here.
<br /><br />EAX issue resolved. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205013" date="Posted: Wed Sep 17, 2008 8:12 pm "><author>undergroundleo</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi, im new to this forum...<br /><br />I builded a new pc and these are the specs:<br /><br />CPU: AMD phenom 9850 2.5Ghz<br />Memory: Corsair XMS2 DDR2 800Mhz<br />Video: 2x EVGA 9800GT in SLI mode<br />Motherboard: Asus M3N-HT Deluxe<br />HDD: Western Digital Caviar 250GB<br /><br />When i play doom 3, i get to play for about a minute or two, and then my PC shuts down completely... i need to power it on and then wait till it shows some video, sometimes i need to reset it 2 or 3 times because it doesnt show any video at all...<br /><br />I think i have a Drivers issue, but i want to know how can i fix it... please help...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205028" date="Posted: Thu Sep 18, 2008 7:12 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It abruptly powers off? That sounds like a hardware issue. How long have you had this new PC? A few days?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p241890" date="Posted: Sun Aug 19, 2012 3:38 pm "><author>justukyte</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have problems with the display. All characters appear to be half in light and half in shadow.<br /><br />Here's a screenshot of what it looks like:<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://s10.postimage.org/f5uksl3zd/graphics_problem.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />My system:<br />CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.80 GHZ<br />RAM: 4 GB DDR2<br />GPU: Intel G41 Express Chipset (driver version 8.15.10.2555)<br />Sound card: Realtek HD audio<br />OS: Windows 7 Ultimate x64 bit SP1<br />No overclock</div>]]></body></post><post id="p241892" date="Posted: Sun Aug 19, 2012 3:48 pm "><author>=FF=Sturm</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Not a fan of integrated video cards, but I guess that your problem is caused by video drivers.<br /><br />Check for updates.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178419" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 5:54 am "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How do I explain this?  When playing Doom 3 and I'm walking through doing my thing, all of a sudden the run mode locks in and won't return to normal unless I exit out of the game.  Then when I'm back at my desk-top, at least 15 or so icons are blue as if they were all selected.  I can't turn this off.  I tried "Ctrl", "Alt" &amp; "Del" and the "task manager" doesn't open, so I can't see what's going on.  Start, "Turn Off Computer", doesn't function either.  The only way I can reboot my computer is to hit the "reset" button and this is the only way that will get me out of this situation.  This happens ALOT!   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><br /><br />Edited:  I have patches 1, 2, &amp; 3 installed along with "ROE" expansion.
<br />I'm running WinXP Home, SP2 on 64 bit hardware.
<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkblue">ASUS K8V SE DELUXE &gt;  Motherboard<br />AMD ATHLON "64", 3200+ &gt; Processor<br />2 gig memory &gt; dual channel<br />VIA K8T800 &gt; MB Drivers<br />MAXTOR 6L3000RO &gt; Drive &gt; not overclocked<br />NVIDIA GeForce 7600 GS &gt; 256 &gt; not overclocked</span></span></span>
<br /><br />Finally my system crashes.  I went into my "System Information" and found this error log.
<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: red">5/18/2007 12:00 AM	Application Error	Faulting application doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, faulting module doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, fault address 0x00085ff6.&amp;#x000d;&amp;#x000a;</span></span>
<br /><br />I just finished with a fresh install and here it is again:
<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkred">5/18/2007 1:06 AM	Application Error	Faulting application doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, faulting module doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, fault address 0x0001e03f.&amp;#x000d;&amp;#x000a;</span></span>
<br /><br />Man, what's going on here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><br /><br />My last report:
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1302 win-x86 May 12 2005 10:40:52<br />2002 MHz AMD CPU with MMX &amp; 3DNow! &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2<br />2048 MB System Memory<br />256 MB Video Memory<br />Winsock Initialized<br />Found interface: {64B2528E-7662-44E9-A250-AFC1E4178E39} Marvell Yukon Gigabit Ethernet 10/100/1000Base-T Adapter, Copper RJ-45 - Packet Scheduler Miniport - 10.0.0.4/255.255.255.0<br />Sys_InitNetworking: adding loopback interface<br />doom using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br />------ Initializing File System ------<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 with checksum 0x29cdb978<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 with checksum 0xc9d99db8<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 with checksum 0x40244be0<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 with checksum 0x64243cc7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 with checksum 0x79bee669<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 with checksum 0x765e4f8b<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 with checksum 0x8ffc3621<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 with checksum 0x95b65ab<br />Current search path:<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3/base<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 (48 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 (63 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 (5137 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 (4676 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 (6120 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 (8972 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 (2698 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 (2 files)<br />game DLL: 0x0 in pak: 0x0<br />Addon pk4s:<br />file system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- Initializing Decls -----<br />------------------------------<br />------- Initializing renderSystem --------<br />using ARB renderSystem<br />renderSystem initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />5180 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />Couldn't open journal files<br />execing editor.cfg<br />execing default.cfg<br />execing DoomConfig.cfg<br />couldn't exec autoexec.cfg<br />5180 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />----- Initializing Sound System ------<br />sound system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- R_InitOpenGL -----<br />Initializing OpenGL subsystem<br />...registered window class<br />...registered fake window class<br />...initializing QGL<br />...calling LoadLibrary( 'opengl32' ): succeeded<br />...calling CDS: ok<br />...created window @ 0,0 (1280x1024)<br />Initializing OpenGL driver<br />...getting DC: succeeded<br />...PIXELFORMAT 10 selected<br />...creating GL context: succeeded<br />...making context current: succeeded<br /><br />------- Input Initialization -------<br />Initializing DirectInput...<br />mouse: DirectInput initialized.<br />keyboard: DirectInput initialized.<br />------------------------------------<br />sound: STEREO<br />...using GL_ARB_multitexture<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_combine<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_cube_map<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_dot3<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_add<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_non_power_of_two<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_compression<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_compression_s3tc<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_filter_anisotropic<br />   maxTextureAnisotropy: 16.000000<br />...using GL_1.4_texture_lod_bias<br />X..GL_EXT_shared_texture_palette not found<br />...using GL_EXT_texture3D<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_wrap<br />...using GL_NV_register_combiners<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_two_side<br />X..GL_ATI_fragment_shader not found<br />X..GL_ATI_text_fragment_shader not found<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_buffer_object<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_program<br />...using GL_ARB_fragment_program<br />...using EXT_depth_bounds_test<br />---------- R_NV20_Init ----------<br />---------------------------------<br />----------- R200_Init -----------<br />Not available.<br />---------- R_ARB2_Init ----------<br />Available.<br />---------------------------------<br />----- R_ReloadARBPrograms -----<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/shadow.vp<br />glprogs/R200_interaction.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_bumpAndLight.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_specularColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseAndSpecularColor.vp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/arbVP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />glprogs/arbFP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />-------------------------------<br />using ARB_vertex_buffer_object memory<br />using ARB2 renderSystem<br />found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4/gamex86.dll<br />copy gamex86.dll to C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\gamex86.dll<br />0 0 1280 1024<br />Regenerated world, staticAllocCount = 0.<br />Shutting down sound hardware<br />idRenderSystem::Shutdown()<br />Shutting down OpenGL subsystem<br />...wglMakeCurrent( NULL, NULL ): success<br />...deleting GL context: success<br />...releasing DC: success<br />...destroying window<br />...shutting down QGL<br />...unloading OpenGL DLL<br />wrong game DLL API version</div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178425" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 8:42 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm not sure what's going on there but this is curious...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">wrong game DLL API version</div>
<br /><br />Generally this error message means the game library and main executable are not the same version.
<br /><br />It's pretty common to see this error message creep up when dealing with mods but I assume you're running the vanilla game, in which case it sounds more like the latest patch didn't install correctly.
<br /><br />I would suggest reinstalling the game from scratch, installing ROE, and then installing the 1.3.1 patch.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178451" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 3:21 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The problem is that I'm running into this <span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkred">ALL THE TIME</span></span>!  I have uninstalled and reinstalled this game atleast four to five times, each with the same issue.  I use all the patches and yes you are correct, I am running a mod, [Annihilation X], to be exact.  Did you read the very beginning where the game locks up in the running mode on me?  I have a lot of strange sh!t going on here. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178458" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 6:06 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">My last report:<br /><br />DOOM 1.3.1302 win-x86 May 12 2005 10:40:52<br /><br />... snip ...<br /><br />------ Initializing File System ------<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 with checksum 0x29cdb978<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 with checksum 0xc9d99db8<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 with checksum 0x40244be0<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 with checksum 0x64243cc7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 with checksum 0x79bee669<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 with checksum 0x765e4f8b<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 with checksum 0x8ffc3621<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 with checksum 0x95b65ab<br />Current search path:<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3/base<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 (48 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 (63 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 (5137 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 (4676 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 (6120 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 (8972 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 (2698 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 (2 files)<br />game DLL: 0x0 in pak: 0x0<br /><br />.. snip ...<br /><br />found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4/gamex86.dll<br />copy gamex86.dll to C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\gamex86.dll <br /><br /></div>
<br /><br />You have a misconfigured install here. "DOOM 1.3.1302" means you are running the EXE from the 1.3 patch (May 2005).
<br /><br />In your "base" folder you should also have the following files...
<br /><br />    pak007.pk4
<br />    game01.pk4
<br />    game02.pk4
<br />    game03.pk4
<br /><br />You're using Windows, it should be trying to load the gamex86.dll file from game03.pk4 but what is happening is that it is using the one from game00.pk4 (from 1.0, 1.1 or 1.2) which is not compatible with the EXE you have in the "C:\Program Files\Doom 3" folder.
<br /><br />Also, the log you posted here isn't running the Annihilation-X mod, just standard Doom 3.
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178459" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 6:11 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmm... I just read the info on the the Annihilation-X mod. It looks to me as though they've included copyrighted music tracks within the game. Naughty naughty. Unless they got permission from KorN et al of course.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178462" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 6:49 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Hmm... I just read the info on the the Annihilation-X mod. It looks to me as though they've included copyrighted music tracks within the game. Naughty naughty. Unless they got permission from KorN et al of course.</div><br /><br />Hmm...!  I don't know about that part. Actually, yes I do!  I'll unpak the pk4 file they're in and get rid of the SOB's, then just repak the file without them.  Now, that you had brought that up has me in doubt!  I don't like that music anyway! <br /><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Also, the log you posted here isn't running the Annihilation-X mod, just standard Doom 3.</div>  Well, that's really strange, because It's running the mod that has caused much of this issue... second thought, it's not only the mod I was having these issues with.  In the beginning statement of my post, where the forward - run mode would lock on, started when I was playing just the Doom3 game! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" />   Any suggestions? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br /><br />Added:  I'm getting to go through another fresh install using all three patches.  I'll screenshot my directory's folder and show what files are in them.  Hopefully this will help to figure out what's going on. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178465" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:04 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What folder did the mod install itself in? Or did you do a manual install? If so, where did you put it?
<br /><br />Mods should go in their own folder e.g.
<br /><br />"C:\Program Files\Doom 3\AnnX"
<br /><br />and then you start doom with a fs_game parameter
<br /><br />doom3.exe +set fs_game AnnX
<br /><br />or just load it from the mods menu.
<br /><br />NEVER install a full mod into the "base" folder. The <span style="font-style: italic">only</span> PK4 files you should find in there (other than the standard ones) are custom MP mods.
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178466" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:08 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here's my directory...
<br /><br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\Annihilation X
<br /><br />I put nothing in my Doom 3 base directory.  If mods are full versions, then they get dropped into the Doom 3 directory in their own folders and I load them from the "Mods" menu. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />I'll be back... doing a fresh install and going to test it... <span style="text-decoration: underline"><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkred">again!!</span></span></span></span></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178470" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:43 pm "><author>LDAsh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If you're getting a suddenly-running-all-the-time "bug" then it might be evil StickyKeys because you're holding shift for a number of seconds, or can happen when playing with the process priority from the task manager.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178472" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:59 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">LDAsh wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">If you're getting a suddenly-running-all-the-time "bug" then it might be evil StickyKeys because you're holding shift for a number of seconds, or can happen when playing with the process priority from the task manager.</div>
<br /><br />Thank you... but I have "StickyKeys" turned off. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178474" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 8:02 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok.. here's what my directories look like.
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">Contents of base folder after first install and no patch applied:<br /><br />doomkey<br />game00.pk4<br />pak000.pk4<br />pak001.pk4<br />pak002.pk4<br />pak003.pk4<br />pak004.pk4<br />-----------------------------------------------------<br />Applying [D3_1_1.exe]<br /><br />pak005.pk4  -  added<br />----------------------------------------------------<br />Installing [D3_ROE] and the inevitable [D3_1_2.exe] patch.<br /><br />pak006.pk4  -  added<br />xpkey  -  added<br /><br />Including the directory:  C:\Program Files\Doom 3\d3xp   which contains;<br /><br />game00.pk4<br />pak000.pk4<br />--------------------------------------------------------<br /><br />Installing the [DOOM3_1.3.1.exe] patch.<br /><br />Added to base folder;<br /><br />game01.pk4<br />game02.pk4<br />game03.pk4<br />pak007.pk4<br />pak008.pk4<br />----------------------------------------------------------<br /><br />Added to d3xp folder;<br /><br />game01.pk4<br />game02.pk4<br />game03.pk4<br />pak001.pk4</div>
<br /><br /><br />These are the files I have in both directories after installing Doom3, ROE and all three patches.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178484" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 9:47 pm "><author>Hex</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Crazy idea:  Just install d3.  no ROE or any other mod.  just plain D3.
<br /><br />Does the problem happen then?  
<br /><br />if no, install a (one) mod.  
<br /><br />Does the problem happen then?
<br /><br />etc</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178486" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 10:04 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Hex wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Crazy idea:  Just install d3.  no ROE or any other mod.  just plain D3.<br /><br />Does the problem happen then?  <br /><br />if no, install a (one) mod.  <br /><br />Does the problem happen then?<br /><br />etc</div>
<br /><br /><br />Hmm... Not a bad idea! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />I do have this issue though.  It won't F5 "quicksave" for me.  Here's the console report.  Edited:  Actually, let me be a little more clear about what I'm saying here.  When I try to load a save that I attempted a "F5" save, this is what I've been getting.
<br /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://img408.imageshack.us/img408/2702/errorbd9.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />Any help here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178517" date="Posted: Sat May 19, 2007 8:39 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That issue is likely derivative of the issue we discussed initially. The main executable and the game library being loaded are not compatible. Because of this discrepancy, you may find all sorts of features that don't function properly. Saving and loading games is not an exception.
<br /><br />Prior to reinstallation, if you haven't already, delete the Doom 3 folder and all it's contents. You don't need any stray files from a previous install present possibly causing the problem to reoccur.
<br /><br />For the time being, don't concern yourself with any mods. Your goal is simply to get Doom 3 working.
<br /><br />Also, don't bother with the intermediate updates. Simply install the game and then immediately update to 1.3.1. Delete any patches you currently have on your desktop and download the 1.3.1 patch from a reputable source if not directly from id itself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178538" date="Posted: Sat May 19, 2007 4:08 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Okay...  Thank you very much... I'll do exactly as you say!  Your patients and understanding is highly appreciated. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />Edited:  I just checked Id Software's site for offical updates as you suggested.  Unfortunately, they don't carry it anymore.  I ran into a dead link there. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178564" date="Posted: Sat May 19, 2007 11:06 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I just checked Id Software's site for offical updates as you suggested.  Unfortunately, they don't carry it anymore.  I ran into a dead link there. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>
<br /><br />The only "official" word from id Software about the 1.3.1 patch has been in Timothee Besset's .plan...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178654" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 1:07 am "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">How do I explain this?  When playing Doom 3 and I'm walking through doing my thing, all of a sudden the run mode locks in and won't return to normal unless I exit out of the game.  Then when I'm back at my desk-top, at least 15 or so icons are blue as if they were all selected.  I can't turn this off.  I tried "Ctrl", "Alt" &amp; "Del" and the "task manager" doesn't open, so I can't see what's going on.  Start, "Turn Off Computer", doesn't function either.  The only way I can reboot my computer is to hit the "reset" button and this is the only way that will get me out of this situation.  This happens ALOT!   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div><br /><br />Then <div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">For the time being, don't concern yourself with any mods. Your goal is simply to get Doom 3 working. <br /><br />Also, don't bother with the intermediate updates. Simply install the game and then immediately update to 1.3.1. Delete any patches you currently have on your desktop and download the 1.3.1 patch from a reputable source if not directly from id itself.</div>
<br /><br />I followed your instructions, this time I installed Doom 3 with just the [DOOM3-1.3.1] patch and no mods.  Started to play the game and into the third map when it did it again.  This time I was able to "screenshot" the Desktop.
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://img237.imageshack.us/img237/9474/error2qp4.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br />What do I do now?... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178662" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 6:03 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Launch the game and type "conDump test" into the console. Then browse to your Doom 3 installation directory, open the base folder and locate a file named test.txt.
<br /><br />Open this file. This will be a dump of all the output from the console. Locate the following lines...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll</div>
<br /><br />The first line should read "DOOM 1.3.1.1304" as you have installed the latest patch. The second line should read "game03.pk4" as it should be loading the version of gamex86.dll from that pk4.
<br /><br />If these two lines match the criteria outlined above, then the patch has been installed successfully and it's time to rule out the game itself as the cause of your problems.
<br /><br />That said, it sounds to me like the game is losing focus and your input is being inadvertently interpreted by windows as clicking and dragging about on the desktop. That would explain the stuck key and the selected icons on your desktop.
<br /><br />The question however is why the game would lose focus and that's hard to answer. Obviously it's some process running in the background that's at fault. But it's pretty much impossible to determine which without knowing everything that you have installed and subsequently the common faults experienced with each of those applications.
<br /><br />The best I can tell you is to try running the game with as few background processes running as possible. You might try running windows in safe mode permitted Doom 3 will run under those conditions.
<br /><br />I'm not saying that's going to solve your problems but it will verify that the problem is indeed caused by some external program. From that point you will have to isolate the offending program by via trial and error.
<br /><br />I suggest learning how to prevent programs from launching alongside windows by using "msconfig". Google it if need be.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178698" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 4:41 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i never seen a desktop with more icons on it ever <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br />in my experience its best to have as few things on desktop
<br />as possible, better to have them on the quickstart down left
<br />next to start, just a friendly advice <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178715" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 8:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">i never seen a desktop with more icons on it ever <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br />in my experience its best to have as few things on desktop<br />as possible, better to have them on the quickstart down left<br />next to start, just a friendly advice <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>
<br /><br />You think that's a lot!!!  You should have seen some of the other computers I have seen.  Icons on the desktop is just a thing of preference, that's all. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179508" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 5:23 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Launch the game and type "conDump test" into the console. Then browse to your Doom 3 installation directory, open the base folder and locate a file named test.txt.<br /><br />Open this file. This will be a dump of all the output from the console. Locate the following lines...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll</div><br /><br />The first line should read "DOOM 1.3.1.1304" as you have installed the latest patch. The second line should read "game03.pk4" as it should be loading the version of gamex86.dll from that pk4.<br /><br />If these two lines match the criteria outlined above, then the patch has been installed successfully and it's time to rule out the game itself as the cause of your problems.<br /><br />That said, it sounds to me like the game is losing focus and your input is being inadvertently interpreted by windows as clicking and dragging about on the desktop. That would explain the stuck key and the selected icons on your desktop.<br /><br />The question however is why the game would lose focus and that's hard to answer. Obviously it's some process running in the background that's at fault. But it's pretty much impossible to determine which without knowing everything that you have installed and subsequently the common faults experienced with each of those applications.<br /><br />The best I can tell you is to try running the game with as few background processes running as possible. You might try running windows in safe mode permitted Doom 3 will run under those conditions.<br /><br />I'm not saying that's going to solve your problems but it will verify that the problem is indeed caused by some external program. From that point you will have to isolate the offending program by via trial and error.<br /><br />I suggest learning how to prevent programs from launching alongside windows by using "msconfig". Google it if need be.</div><br /><br /><br />Ok guys, sorry to have taken so long in getting back to you with this, it's just the [whole-ball-of-wax] just frustrated me and I had to walk away for awhile.<br /><br />rich_is_bored...[Hmm... I bet it is] <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />   I did the con dump you taught me to do and here's the whole 'nine-yards', because it wrote to notepad.  I have a problem!  Here's the report:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">Con Test wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51<br />2002 MHz AMD CPU with MMX &amp; 3DNow! &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2<br />2048 MB System Memory<br />256 MB Video Memory<br />Winsock Initialized<br />Found interface: {64B2528E-7662-44E9-A250-AFC1E4178E39} Marvell Yukon Gigabit<br />Ethernet 10/100/1000Base-T Adapter, Copper RJ-45 - Packet Scheduler Miniport -<br /> 10.0.0.4/255.255.255.0<br />Sys_InitNetworking: adding loopback interface<br />doom using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br /><br />Section Edited:  Too much info...</div>
<br /><br />What now, buddy? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179518" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 7:53 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">So exactly what goes wrong now? That dump looks fine for base D3 using 1.3.1.1304. And it connected OK to the master server at id to set your guid value.
<br /><br />What happens next that is wrong?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179519" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 7:58 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />If you don't mind taking the time and starting here:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2909&amp;postdays=0&amp;postorder=asc&amp;start=60">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewto ... c&amp;start=60</a><!-- m -->
<br />and reading through because there are numerous issues occuring.
<br /><br />The last one is that Doom 3 is totally crashing when I load a mod... any mod, doesn't matter!
<br /><br />now, according to "rich_is_bored" he had stated that when a con test is conducted that these two lines should appear at the top of the test
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll</div>
<br /><br /><br />Look at the test results I posted, the second code I listed here, never ocurred, so it is apparent that there's an issue going on here.
<br /><br />You need to read to catch up, budddy.
<br />------------------------------------------------------------------
<br /><br />Edited:
<br /><br />Reinstalled Doom3 w/ ROE &amp;   DOOM3-1.3.1.exe  update patch.
<br /><br />Everthing looked fine in the test report except at the bottom where I have it posted here.
<br /><div class="quotetitle">condump test wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51<br />2002 MHz AMD CPU with MMX &amp; 3DNow! &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2<br />2048 MB System Memory<br />256 MB Video Memory<br />Winsock Initialized<br />Found interface: {64B2528E-7662-44E9-A250-AFC1E4178E39} Marvell Yukon Gigabit<br />Ethernet 10/100/1000Base-T Adapter, Copper RJ-45 - Packet Scheduler Miniport -<br /> 10.0.0.4/255.255.255.0<br />Sys_InitNetworking: adding loopback interface<br />doom using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br />------ Initializing File System ------<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 with checksum 0x29cdb978<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game01.pk4 with checksum 0x51c6981f<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game02.pk4 with checksum 0xf3ec6f7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4 with checksum 0x5d4230ea<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 with checksum 0x2cb26dc3<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 with checksum 0x40244be0<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 with checksum 0x64243cc7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 with checksum 0x79bee669<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 with checksum 0x765e4f8b<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 with checksum 0x8ffc3621<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 with checksum 0x95b65ab<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak007.pk4 with checksum 0x666bdb3c<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak008.pk4 with checksum 0x23ae5993<br />Current search path:<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3/base<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak008.pk4 (3 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak007.pk4 (38 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 (48 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 (63 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 (5137 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 (4676 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 (6120 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 (8972 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 (2698 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4 (2 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game02.pk4 (2 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game01.pk4 (2 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 (2 files)<br />game DLL: 0x0 in pak: 0x0<br />Addon pk4s:<br />file system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- Initializing Decls -----<br />------------------------------<br />------- Initializing renderSystem --------<br />using ARB renderSystem<br />renderSystem initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />5206 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />Couldn't open journal files<br />execing editor.cfg<br />execing default.cfg<br />execing DoomConfig.cfg<br />couldn't exec autoexec.cfg<br />5206 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />----- Initializing Sound System ------<br />sound system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- R_InitOpenGL -----<br />Initializing OpenGL subsystem<br />...registered window class<br />...registered fake window class<br />...initializing QGL<br />...calling LoadLibrary( 'opengl32' ): succeeded<br />...calling CDS: ok<br />...created window @ 0,0 (1024x768)<br />Initializing OpenGL driver<br />...getting DC: succeeded<br />...PIXELFORMAT 10 selected<br />...creating GL context: succeeded<br />...making context current: succeeded<br /><br />------- Input Initialization -------<br />Initializing DirectInput...<br />mouse: DirectInput initialized.<br />keyboard: DirectInput initialized.<br />------------------------------------<br />sound: STEREO<br />...using GL_ARB_multitexture<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_combine<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_cube_map<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_dot3<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_add<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_non_power_of_two<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_compression<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_compression_s3tc<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_filter_anisotropic<br />   maxTextureAnisotropy: 16.000000<br />...using GL_1.4_texture_lod_bias<br />X..GL_EXT_shared_texture_palette not found<br />...using GL_EXT_texture3D<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_wrap<br />...using GL_NV_register_combiners<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_two_side<br />X..GL_ATI_fragment_shader not found<br />X..GL_ATI_text_fragment_shader not found<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_buffer_object<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_program<br />...using GL_ARB_fragment_program<br />...using EXT_depth_bounds_test<br />---------- R_NV20_Init ----------<br />---------------------------------<br />----------- R200_Init -----------<br />Not available.<br />---------- R_ARB2_Init ----------<br />Available.<br />---------------------------------<br />----- R_ReloadARBPrograms -----<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/shadow.vp<br />glprogs/R200_interaction.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_bumpAndLight.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_specularColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseAndSpecularColor.vp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/arbVP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />glprogs/arbFP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />-------------------------------<br />using ARB_vertex_buffer_object memory<br />using ARB2 renderSystem<br />found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll<br />copy gamex86.dll to C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\gamex86.dll<br />game using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br />--------- Initializing Game ----------<br />gamename: baseDOOM-1<br />gamedate: Jan 16 2007<br />Initializing event system<br />...473 event definitions<br />Initializing class hierarchy<br />...142 classes, 191092 bytes for event callbacks<br />Initializing scripts<br />Compiled 'interpolateShaderParm': 1355.1 ms<br />---------- Compile stats ----------<br /><br />Memory usage:<br />     Strings: 79, 9648 bytes<br />  Statements: 67875, 1357500 bytes<br />   Functions: 2109, 250532 bytes<br />   Variables: 147376 bytes<br />    Mem used: 2476344 bytes<br /> Static data: 2277552 bytes<br />   Allocated: 3281600 bytes<br /> Thread size: 7068 bytes<br /><br />...6 aas types<br />game initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />-------- Initializing Session --------<br />WARNING: idChoiceWindow::InitVars: gui 'guis/mainmenu.gui' window 'SNDBPrimary<br />' references undefined cvar 's_driver'<br />session initialized<br />--------------------------------------<br />--- Common Initialization Complete ---<br />------------- Warnings ---------------<br />during DOOM 3 initialization...<br />WARNING: idChoiceWindow::InitVars: gui 'guis/mainmenu.gui' window 'SNDBPrimary<br />' references undefined cvar 's_driver'<br />1 warnings<br />guid set to lC2fU1LyeEE<br />]condump test<br />Dumped console text to test.txt.<br /><br /></div>
<br /><br /><br />Is this something to be concerned about?  Doom 3 is still crashing when I try to launch a mod from the opening screen. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179529" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 10:41 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The warning at the end is fine, just ignore it. The menus reference a CVar that only exists in the Linux build of the game.
<br /><br />As for your other problem the log you posted has been edited so I can't check through it now.
<br /><br />As for mods not working, have the ones you tried been updated to work with the new D3 1.3.1 patch that you're using?
<br /><br />Edit: I just checked with one of the Annihilation-X team; it is only for D3 1.3 right now. They're working on a 1.3.1 compatible version.
<br /><br />Edit Again: Apparently he was misinformed. There are no gamecode changes in A-X so it should work with 1.3 or 1.3.1. I downloaded it from here...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://doom3.filefront.com/file/Annihilation_X;76651">http://doom3.filefront.com/file/Annihilation_X;76651</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />... and got not problems starting it up.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179534" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 12:09 am "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />I have "AnnihilationX" and it also is crashing Doom3. I have reposted the "conDump test" for your review.  But, not matter what I do, I just can't run <span style="color: red"><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="font-weight: bold">any</span></span></span> mods no matter what they are, without me getting a "Doom3 has to shut down, now" warning.  I don't know what the hell going on.  Before, when I first started to run into problems, there were other [different] issues happening..., now I can't even get to the point where the first ones ocurred without it crashing on me first. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_redface.gif" alt=":oops:" title="Embarassed" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179550" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 7:47 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've looked at your condump and both lines are present and match the criteria I outlined originally. For all intensive purposes, Doom 3 appears to be up to date and it should run without issue.
<br /><br />That said, I'm assuming the game itself runs without any problems. It's only when you try to launch a mod that the game crashes.
<br /><br />And judging from your description you end up staring at a dialog like this...
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/images/m005.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.
<br /><br />The only thing I can do is suggest an alternative way to launch mods. One that hopefully avoids whatever causes the crash.
<br /><br />That said, you can try making a shortcut to launch Doom 3 with the appropriate command line parameters to launch each mod.
<br /><br />General instructions are here...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Startup_parameters#Windows">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Startup_parameters#Windows</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />What you're aiming for is something like this...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">"C:\Program Files\Doom3.exe" +set fs_game [name of mod folder]</div>
<br /><br />Aside from that, I have no clue what to suggest.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179562" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 9:36 am "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div>
<br /><br />If you click on the "click here" you'll get some basic error info.
<br /><br />Under the "Error signature" section you'll see ModName. This is nothing to do with game "mods", it is the name of the windows module in which the error occurred. That may help you locate the source of the problem.
<br /><br />If ModName is doom3.exe or gamex86.dll then the problem is <span style="font-style: italic">probably</span> just doom related. If ModName is something else do a google search on the name and see what turns up.
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179573" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 2:30 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div><br /><br />If you click on the "click here" you'll get some basic error info.<br /><br />Under the "Error signature" section you'll see ModName. This is nothing to do with game "mods", it is the name of the windows module in which the error occurred. That may help you locate the source of the problem.<br /><br />If ModName is doom3.exe or gamex86.dll then the problem is <span style="font-style: italic">probably</span> just doom related. If ModName is something else do a google search on the name and see what turns up.<br /><br />Sim</div>
<br /><br /><br />I did do that and it was Doom3.exe... anyway, I really would like to thank you guys for being there during this "wonderful" moment, you really helped me to try to funnel this down.  Someone told me that the 3.1.1 patch was the blame and not to use it, just use the 3.1 patch instead. Well, I followed his instructions with a new install and using the 3.1..., it doesn't crash anymore and I'm actually running mods now.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179586" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 6:59 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">nice  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /><br />im also avoiding that 1.31 patch, it totally screwed me
<br />over too and im having no issues with anything with
<br />"only" the 1.3 patch installed <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179597" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 10:21 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">nice  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /><br />it totally screwed me over too </div>
<br /><br />Can you be more specific? Would be useful to add your issues to the "knowledge base" of problems people have with 1.3.1.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179603" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 11:50 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">nice  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /><br />it totally screwed me over too </div><br /><br />Can you be more specific? Would be useful to add your issues to the "knowledge base" of problems people have with 1.3.1.</div>
<br /><br />There's really not much to add as far as details...except...<span style="font-size: 150%; line-height: normal"><span style="color: red"><span style="font-weight: bold"> don't use it.</span></span></span></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179634" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 5:33 am "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol  very succinct there mac ^^
<br />well to put it short, i dl the 1.31 patch,
<br />patched my doom3 and then crahsboombang sorta,
<br />nada worked, tried to run my doom modded stuff with fs_game
<br />as per usual, crashed, tried to run vanilla doom by start-programs-doom3
<br />ie NOT any desktop shortcut, crashed, tried to run doom via
<br />an unaltered shortcut, crashed, thats about it, well that and 
<br />some language i cannot really write here, it ended with me
<br />simply flushing doom from my computer as well as the
<br />1,31 patch, now i reinstalled doom with 1.3 only,
<br />dont wanna repeat meself but 1.31 wont get near my
<br />doom again EVERRRR !  
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" />  Thats 4 things now ill never have on my computer as long
<br />as i can draw breath, patch 1.31, xp-lite, steam and vista  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /><br />Well, five things actually, if i reinstall far Cry their 1.32 patch
<br />(if you know FC you know how that one SUcK) wont be
<br />in my registry either  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><br /><br />thats MY 2 cents, or five cents if you will  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179638" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 5:48 am "><author>Marineofuac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Notice how idsoftware's site (and the doom 3 update system) says nothing about the new patch. I think thier waiting for that one moment to say "oh all teh mods is 1.3.1 now and all teh peoples having teh vista or updated stuffs" for them to acknowledge its exsistence.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179681" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 4:04 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">then crahsboombang sorta</div>
<br /><br />I was hoping for something a little <span style="font-style: italic">more</span> specific than that. Were you getting an actual crash like mac53 or just an error ("DLL API Error" is most common when using non-updated mods).
<br /><br />As for the lack of publicity on the patch, this is something I'm pursuing with id. If I hear anything further I'll post some news.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179684" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 4:55 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I was hoping for something a little <span style="font-style: italic">more</span> specific than that. Were you getting an actual crash like mac53 or just an error ("DLL API Error" is most common when using non-updated mods).<br /><br />As for the lack of publicity on the patch, this is something I'm pursuing with id. If I hear anything further I'll post some news.</div><br /><br />Your comment on the mods... now that I am not using the 1.3.1. patch, I have absolutely <span style="font-weight: bold">no</span> problems with either playing Doom 3 itself or any mods,... none at all!<br /><br />The only thing I can say here is, if you click <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2909&amp;postdays=0&amp;postorder=asc&amp;start=60" class="postlink">here</a> it will take you to the very first report of mine when I started to have these issues and trust me, there were numerous different types. Ranging from the crashing when I tried to play a mod, to numerous icons being locked in activate mode on my desktop.  The date of this first post was 05/17!! and finally in June after walking away for about a week, someone helped with an idea that hit the target! I know I have re-installed the game atleast a dozen times within this time frame, not to mention that I even tried shutting down my anti-virus software and other background running processes down to just the os, and still had crashes and problems.<br /><br />Here's what I think it is.  1.3.1. has been built with the 64 bit vista in mind and it's dumb-founded when ran on a 32 bit os. Doom 3 was built for 32 bits and so was all the patches up to 1.3.1.  It's appearing to me, that it's a case of 'either, or'... not 'both' when it comes to software, especially in this case.  Personally, I think that 1.3.1. is a beta and hasn't been tested properly.  I'm not a pro here, nor do I claim to be a 'puter wiz', but there are times where it doesn't take a 'rocket scientist' to see what's going on, just one to explain it!  I want to help with this and I'll do my best.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">tried to run vanilla doom</div>
<br /><br /><br />What the hell is "Vanilla Doom"?  I see it mentioned everywhere on forums, being used in different terms.  Especially in the Doom 2 world. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_redface.gif" alt=":oops:" title="Embarassed" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179692" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:10 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">for me "vanilla doom" means the original game, no roe and no mods whatsoever, just "pure"doom3.exe, i may be wrong on how others perceieve that use of "vanilla doom" but for me, thats the intent of the term
<br /><br />edit
<br /><br />I was hoping for something a little more specific than that. Were you getting an actual crash like mac53 or just an error ("DLL API Error" is most common when using non-updated mods). "
<br /><br />lil of both kinda, actually i have a hard time remembering EXACTLY
<br />what happened, the term "seeing red" kicked in, sooooo ....   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179694" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:19 pm "><author>Mordenkainen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">for me "vanilla doom" means the original game, no roe and no mods whatsoever, just "pure"doom3.exe, i may be wrong on how others perceieve that use of "vanilla doom" but for me, thats the intent of the term</div>
<br /><br />That's it.
<br /><br />Anyway, as a general tip if anyone is having problems the first thing I would suggest is installing the game on a path without spaces. Sometimes they don't causes problems but other times they do, especially if you're into modding.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179696" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:27 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Mordenkainen wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">That's it. <br /><br />Anyway, as a general tip if anyone is having problems the first thing I would suggest is installing the game on a path without spaces. Sometimes they don't causes problems but other times they do, especially if you're into modding.</div>
<br /><br />You know... I thought about that and did this, first.  Directory was
<br />C:\Doom 3\... instead of the default in the program files, but the problem with that is that when the installer writes the program folder, it writes as Doom 3, [with space anyway]! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179697" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:30 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">for me "vanilla doom" means the original game, no roe and no mods whatsoever, just "pure"doom3.exe, i may be wrong on how others perceieve that use of "vanilla doom" but for me, thats the intent of the term</div>
<br /><br />Thanks "Vin"... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179713" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 9:43 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Youre welcome Mac53   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br />lets form a "anti-patch 1.31 club" lol   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28523" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 7:22 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Please report all (suspected) bugs related to the GAME here.
<br /><br />Make sure to also include your system specs as follows:
<br /><br />CPU
<br />GPU (+used driver version)
<br />RAM
<br />Soundcard
<br />OS
<br />Overclocked anything - if yes, what if no then post: O/C no
<br />Any special cvar settings you've made
<br />FSAA - if yes, which setting</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28571" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 9:50 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-weight: bold">Server browser bug</span>
<br /><br />I've noticed the ingame server browser has a few problems when attempting to sort or filter the list in any way, and actually misreports selected servers. If the server browser is left alone, each listed server is correct - but attempting to resort that list in any way, causes your client to connect to the wrong server.
<br /><br />For instance, I sort the servers by ping and attempt to join a local server with no players and an 80ms ping - I end up joining a server halfway across the world with players already in it, and an astronomical ping time.
<br /><br />This doesn't seem to be related to configuration or specific hardware settings, as I've seen this issue manifest on a wide number of systems. I suspect that it effects everyone, and have gotten lots of complaints about lag when on Australian servers by Americans who attempted to join more local servers. But for reference's sake, here's my specs:
<br /><br />CPU: Pentium 4 3GHz, 800FSB (Northwood).
<br />MOBO: ASUS P4P800 Deluxe, 865PE chipset.
<br />GPU: Sapphire branded Radeon 9800XT, 256MB model plus Catalyst 4.7's and beta 4.9's.
<br />RAM: 1024MB (2x512MB) DDR400 Kingmax.
<br />Sound: Creative Audigy 2 ZS Platinum Pro.
<br />OS: Windows XP Pro SP1, up to date.
<br /><br />No overclockings. No real CVAR modifications. No FSAA used.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28586" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 10:55 pm "><author>eskimo roll</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">There's also the Snow bug? that may be a driver/overclocking issue, or whatever.
<br />Here's a screenie of the problem:
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144im_/http://levi.me.uk/_levi/d3/img/d3_snow.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Read this thread to find out more on that one:
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2851">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2851</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28596" date="Posted: Wed Aug 04, 2004 11:28 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">eskimo roll wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">There's also the Snow bug? that may be a driver/overclocking issue, or whatever.</div>
<br /><br />That looks like a video card problem. It can come from overclocking or overheating, but can also be a hardware fault with the card/chipset itself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28613" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 12:05 am "><author>duff_moss</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have an issue which I originally reported as snow, but not like the screenshot above - it's more like static. Others are seeing this also, and from  the limited knowledge about the issue, it appears at this stage to be an issue with the ATI OpenGL driver on certain cards.
<br /><br />ATI Radeon 9800 Pro (128Meg - currently using Cat 4.7 but tired many others, including Omega 2.5.88)
<br />2.8GHz Pentium IV
<br />1Gig DDR400 RAM
<br />200Gig SATA Hard Drive
<br />Gigabyte Motherboard (GA-8I series of some sort)
<br />Windows XP SP1</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28712" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 3:07 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Basically, "use" in the PDA GUI is bound to "fire" instead of defaulting to the L-mouse button. Which is stupid and awkward, but not a game-breaker. <br /><br />In other words, to click on something on the PDA screen, I have to move the mouse pointer to the right place, and then hit my "fire" key (which is "E" on the keyboard). In order to scroll through a PDA email, I need to hold down fire/E while moving the mouse. <br /><br />They should have just had *all* mouse behavior revert to normal while using the PDA, but probably didn't anticipate/test with an unusual config. Bleh. </div>
<br />Thanks pjw for reporting this!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28787" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:49 am "><author>mudvin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">sizeDown command sizes viewport down, and moves it to the left lower corner, while it should be centered. This is obvious a bug.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28802" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:30 am "><author>shalstus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Im using a:
<br /><br />ati radeon 9700 mobility 128 mb
<br />512mb ram
<br />sigmatel audio driver
<br />2.8 ghz
<br />windows xp
<br />no overclocking
<br />the only thing i tried was changing the cachemeg from 20 to 64 but i only got slightly longer gameplay (5-10 mins.)
<br /><br />constantly locking up at random points during gameplay.
<br />i tried my standard drivers as well as the beta catalyst driver to no avail.
<br />please HELP!!!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28812" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:56 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Link to Activision support page for Doom3
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt/" class="postlink">Link</a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28814" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:58 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">_shank wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt" class="postlink">Link to Activison support for Doom3</a></div>
<br /><br />Should we consider that as a bug?
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p28817" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 8:01 am "><author>_shank</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">_shank wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/https://activision.custhelp.com/cgi-bin/activision.cfg/php/enduser/std_alp.php?p_sid=CCSZp8ih&amp;p_lva=&amp;p_li=&amp;p_page=1&amp;p_prod_lvl1=1&amp;p_prod_lvl2=389&amp;p_search_text=&amp;p_new_search=1&amp;p_search_type=search_nl&amp;p_sort_by=dflt" class="postlink">Link to Activison support for Doom3</a></div><br /><br />Should we consider that as a bug?<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>
<br /><br />its away to resolve the bug's (bbcode is so picky...took me some time to get the link made)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28891" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 1:09 pm "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">ok, the fix to enable 5.1 sound is to change the settings in the control panel. But what does that mean? Do I now every time I want to watch a dvd go back to 7.1 (I guess so)? Or should this setting even be 5.1 for 5.1 movies? Shouldn't Doom3 accept 7.1 as a setting and switch to 5.1 internally (if yes, a fix please, id!). I don't mind that my centre back speaker is mute for Doom3, but I like to still watch my 6.1 dvds in 6.1, without changing the setting all the time!!!</div>
<br />Thanks fergusdog for reporting this in!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28894" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 1:24 pm "><author>Qwertys</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i killed an IMP in a doorway and i don't remember if the door just opened or not but the imp got stuck and was spinning rapidly before it melted. kinda wierd seems a bug in the physics code.
<br /><br />On my video card (PNY Geforce 4 4200) the game was olmost pitch black at default settings, all i could see was lighting flares and GUI's. after changing the r_renderer to NV10 it went away (it was using a default NV20 path).
<br />Intel 2.5ghz on Intel D865PERL
<br />Audigy2
<br />1gb ram
<br />WinXP SP1.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28936" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 3:35 pm "><author>mattwill1</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I can open the game and play for five minutes at most, but then it closes and goes back to windows with no error or anything. All drivers are the most up to date from manufacturer's website and windows display settings match those in the game.  I've tried everything. Help!!! 
<br /><br />System: 
<br />CPU - Athalon XP 2200+ 1.8Ghz
<br />GPU - NVidia GeForce3 Ti 200    Driver = v62.11
<br />RAM - 512 MB DDR
<br />Sound Card - Vinyl AC'97
<br />O/C no</div>]]></body></post><post id="p28980" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 5:09 pm "><author>dhughes</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The game installed without a problem, and seemed to be fine when it first started (id intro was perfect)... then, when the next screens came up all the graphics turned into a garbled mess! The cursor, text, and other images come and go and I can't see what I'm doing at all. I've read through other posts that mention anything about weird graphics and done whatever they suggested for those (updated all drivers, etc.) and no matter what, I still have the same garbled graphics. 
<br /><br />I also thought that maybe if I got past the setup screens, the game might be okay... nope, the same thing happens even when I start a new game. 
<br /><br />Please help, I'd like to at least play the game~ 
<br />dhughes 
<br /><br />btw.. i ran dxdiag.. and it didn't show anything was wrong. 
<br />no overclocking either~ 
<br /><br />win xp sp1 
<br />2.8 ghz 
<br />512 ram 
<br />ati 9700 pro 4.7 
<br />sblive 5.1
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223144/http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v431/dhughes_/garbledgraphics.jpg">http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v431/ ... aphics.jpg</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />!!!Just wanted to post the outcome... turns out my Dell video card, was defective from the beginning. I saw little signs (and didn't recognize them as such) from day one, but because the programs I normally run didn't seem affected, I didn't question the occasional "artifacting"~ After weeks of trying A to Z to "fix" the graphics for Doom 3~ I switched cards, first with an identical ATI 9700 pro 128 (this one purchased from retail store) ... results.. no problems, no artifacts... then, I put my OLD Nvidia Ti 500 in, with the same results (although a bit slower), no artifacts.
<br /><br />So, I can now play Doom 3~ and will NOT BE purchasing any more systems from Dell.com!
<br /><br />Thanks for everyones input...
<br />dhughes</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29012" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:24 pm "><author>Feffer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Doom3 crashes after the cut scenes if they are allowed to play to completion, completely freezing the computer and requiring a hard reboot (removing the battery on the laptop).  It also runs choppy prior to this point.
<br /><br />The laptop is a dell (i'm sorry i don't have the make and model currently as it isn't mine, i will edit it in when i can to add more information).
<br /><br />Processor: Pentium 3.4 EE (i believe)
<br />Ram: at least 1gb
<br />Video Card: Radeon 9700 128mb
<br />Sound: unsure
<br />OS: WinXP home
<br /><br />Nothing has been overclocked unless it shipped that way.  We have attempted loading all the newest drivers (mb, sound, ati) to ensure that is not the problem.  We are also going to try the other recommendations from the activsion help site, and if any solution is found i'll edit and post here.  Any help is required (my father is dying to play this and won't be home to his home pc till next week).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29068" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 8:34 pm "><author>Jaymz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Feffer wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Processor: Pentium 3.4 EE (i believe)</div>
<br /><br />On a laptop? I don't think so.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29130" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 10:55 pm "><author>DudeMiester</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok multiplayer has stopped working entirely for me. Whenever I click to join a server and it connect, Doom 3 shuts down. However, I can create servers with no problem. What's even stranger is that it was working fine before, and now it has died. I have made no multiplayer or networking modifications to the DoomConfig.
<br /><br />Another bug. When using com_allowConsole 1 and -nointro, the main menu doesn't load, only the console shows up and it takes up the entire screen. However, when you type com_allowConsole 0 into the console, the main menu loads, and you can use Doom 3 like normal.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29327" date="Posted: Fri Aug 06, 2004 9:11 am "><author>Skitso</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">My system:
<br /><br />Gf Ti4200 64MB
<br />AMD 2600+
<br />512Mt RAM
<br /><br />The problem: The game seems to use rasterized lighting, smoke and shadow effects like the game wouldn't be in 32-bit mode. The game looks just fine and smooth in my friends computer that has Radeon 9700.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29584" date="Posted: Fri Aug 06, 2004 7:52 pm "><author>organic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have crashes which happen at the same points in the game every single time.  For example, in mars_city2, I step up to one particular door and it hangs; in the next level after that, there's a cutscene when you walk out of the elevator and the camera flies through an airvent and shows the bald guy w/ sunglasses talking to someone else, well the game hangs every single time when the bald heads come into the frame... wierdness...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179720" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 10:15 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've been loading some maps using the console and when I finish the particular part of a map and it's time to go to the next part, I keep a console error unable to find "current map name".proc  This has happened to me with three different maps. Does anyone have any idea as to what's happening here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179784" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:29 am "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Here's what I think it is.  1.3.1. has been built with the 64 bit vista in mind and it's dumb-founded when ran on a 32 bit os. Doom 3 was built for 32 bits and so was all the patches up to 1.3.1.  It's appearing to me, that it's a case of 'either, or'... not 'both' when it comes to software, especially in this case.  Personally, I think that 1.3.1. is a beta and hasn't been tested properly.  I'm not a pro here, nor do I claim to be a 'puter wiz', but there are times where it doesn't take a 'rocket scientist' to see what's going on, just one to explain it!  I want to help with this and I'll do my best.</div>
<br /><br />To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a>
<br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.
<br /><br />The Mac developers Aspyr did an independent QA test of their build.
<br /><br />We've been running the patch on our servers since release with no problems. My mod server has had nearly 400 individual players connect to it since it was upgraded to 1.3.1.
<br /><br />Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.
<br /><br />I think it is also useful to clear up some terminology. A "crash" is when the game does something unexpected and can't recover from it. Like simply dropping back to the desktop or giving you one of those error boxes like you have seen.
<br /><br />Other problems, such as the DLL API message, are not "crashes" but are genuine error conditions that the game has detected and reported to you (a mod built for a different release in this case).
<br /><br />One thing you could try is to do disable EAX/OpenAL. I've had one player recently whose D3 would crash on startup when these were enabled.
<br /><br />You can do this by editing DoomConfig.cfg and making sure the appropriate values are set to zero.
<br /><br />  seta s_useEAXReverb "0"
<br />  seta s_useOpenAL "0"
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179812" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 4:47 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Now, I don't deny that you and vinnie_jones do have some sort of problem but you're the only two people I've heard from that could not get 1.3.1 running.</div>
<br /><br />Thank you for the correction in a professional manner.  You are correct, I used the wrong term.  "<span style="color: red"><span style="font-style: italic">Freezes</span></span>" explains it exactly.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179817" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 6:20 pm "><author>AnthonyJa</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/images/m005.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div>
<br /><br />Agreed that in general they're not too helpful. However you can sometimes get some info from them. If you click the "click here" link, you'll get another dialog which shows some basic information about the crash. Significantly, it shows the module, which can sometimes point you at the problem (eg if its "nvogl.dll" then its probably an nVidia OpenGL issue).
<br /><br />If its in gamex86.dll, and you're running a mod, the mod author may be able to use the "faulting address" to tell you something about the crash.
<br /><br />Also while its open, depending on how your Windows is configured there might be a .mdmp file hanging around in your temp directory associated with this crash, which might be helpful to a programmer to trace the issue. It'll probably get deleted as you close the dialog though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179822" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 7:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div>
<br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179839" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 9:49 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">To the best of my knowledge the Vista changes were related to detecting whether a OpenGL ICD is installed. If not you should get a warning relating to performance if you're using the Vista OpenGL wrapper without driver support. Can't be 100% on that as I never tried on Vista without an ICD. I linked to it before, but Timothee Besset's plan has the full release info...<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/" class="postlink">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><br /><br />Doom 3 is still 32-bit (Vista still comes as both, don't forget). As for testing it <span style="font-style: italic">did</span> have a full QA pass. I used each of the test releases with no problems from early Dec 2006 until it was released in Feb 2007. I played the RoE expansion pack right through just in case.</div><br /><br /><br />The link you posted here, takes you to the version that I was using, and causing the posted issues.</div>
<br /><br />Yes, I realise that. I was linking so you could read the info about the release straight from the developer who created it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179842" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 10:37 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />Thank you, [for me] reading that garble doesn't help me any... I wish it does.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179849" date="Posted: Mon Jun 04, 2007 11:02 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hehe im not at all surprised im one of the few (?)
<br />people who has problems with the new patch, i had the same
<br />bs with the 1.32 patch for far cry (altho THAT patch was so flawed
<br />crytec or whatever theyre called actually withdrew it),
<br />i also had serious issues with that MoH box (dont rememebr the name but it had 4 cd-s in it) but i googled that and many had issues with that
<br />as well, sometimes i just wanna take the comp and chuck it
<br />through the window and just "retire" to some console   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br />For the time being, if not forever, im sticking with the 1.3 patch</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180031" date="Posted: Wed Jun 06, 2007 9:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Could anyone tell me why when I go to activate the EAX in the sound options menu, it freezes my system?  I have the Audigy 2 zs Platinum SB sound card with <span style="color: red"><span style="font-weight: bold">ALL</span></span> the updated bells and whistles.  EAX console, DTS, the whole nine yards.  There's no logical reason why this option should freeze my system.  I saw an eax update for doom3, but there's no way I'm going to uninstall my current Creative software and drivers to install this crap.  There has to be some way to activate this feature, I have this option in my current software. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p180102" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 11:52 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The cvar for enabling EAX is s_useEAXReverb. You could try adding...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">s_useEAXReverb 1</div>
<br /><br />... to DoomConfig.cfg</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180138" date="Posted: Thu Jun 07, 2007 6:18 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I did and it froze Doom 3 while I tried to apply the setting within the menu and entering the attribute within the cfg file gives me this.  Doom 3 doesn't even load... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://i199.photobucket.com/albums/aa319/mac53_2007/error1.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />Issue resolved thanks to Doomworld.  This is an issue pertaining just to Creative "Soundblaster" Audigy series cards.  If you using Creative and want the EAX reverb and are not able to get it to function, then here is a link that will answer many questions pertaining to this.
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932/http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster">http://forums.creative.com/creative...id=soundblaster</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />There's also a software that installs the proper API to make Doom 3's EAX HD reverb functional.  If I get enough requests, I can upload this API software and post the link to it here.
<br /><br />EAX issue resolved. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p205013" date="Posted: Wed Sep 17, 2008 8:12 pm "><author>undergroundleo</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi, im new to this forum...<br /><br />I builded a new pc and these are the specs:<br /><br />CPU: AMD phenom 9850 2.5Ghz<br />Memory: Corsair XMS2 DDR2 800Mhz<br />Video: 2x EVGA 9800GT in SLI mode<br />Motherboard: Asus M3N-HT Deluxe<br />HDD: Western Digital Caviar 250GB<br /><br />When i play doom 3, i get to play for about a minute or two, and then my PC shuts down completely... i need to power it on and then wait till it shows some video, sometimes i need to reset it 2 or 3 times because it doesnt show any video at all...<br /><br />I think i have a Drivers issue, but i want to know how can i fix it... please help...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p205028" date="Posted: Thu Sep 18, 2008 7:12 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It abruptly powers off? That sounds like a hardware issue. How long have you had this new PC? A few days?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p241890" date="Posted: Sun Aug 19, 2012 3:38 pm "><author>justukyte</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have problems with the display. All characters appear to be half in light and half in shadow.<br /><br />Here's a screenshot of what it looks like:<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319222932im_/http://s10.postimage.org/f5uksl3zd/graphics_problem.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />My system:<br />CPU: Intel Core 2 Duo 2.80 GHZ<br />RAM: 4 GB DDR2<br />GPU: Intel G41 Express Chipset (driver version 8.15.10.2555)<br />Sound card: Realtek HD audio<br />OS: Windows 7 Ultimate x64 bit SP1<br />No overclock</div>]]></body></post><post id="p241892" date="Posted: Sun Aug 19, 2012 3:48 pm "><author>=FF=Sturm</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Not a fan of integrated video cards, but I guess that your problem is caused by video drivers.<br /><br />Check for updates.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178419" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 5:54 am "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How do I explain this?  When playing Doom 3 and I'm walking through doing my thing, all of a sudden the run mode locks in and won't return to normal unless I exit out of the game.  Then when I'm back at my desk-top, at least 15 or so icons are blue as if they were all selected.  I can't turn this off.  I tried "Ctrl", "Alt" &amp; "Del" and the "task manager" doesn't open, so I can't see what's going on.  Start, "Turn Off Computer", doesn't function either.  The only way I can reboot my computer is to hit the "reset" button and this is the only way that will get me out of this situation.  This happens ALOT!   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><br /><br />Edited:  I have patches 1, 2, &amp; 3 installed along with "ROE" expansion.
<br />I'm running WinXP Home, SP2 on 64 bit hardware.
<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkblue">ASUS K8V SE DELUXE &gt;  Motherboard<br />AMD ATHLON "64", 3200+ &gt; Processor<br />2 gig memory &gt; dual channel<br />VIA K8T800 &gt; MB Drivers<br />MAXTOR 6L3000RO &gt; Drive &gt; not overclocked<br />NVIDIA GeForce 7600 GS &gt; 256 &gt; not overclocked</span></span></span>
<br /><br />Finally my system crashes.  I went into my "System Information" and found this error log.
<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: red">5/18/2007 12:00 AM	Application Error	Faulting application doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, faulting module doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, fault address 0x00085ff6.&amp;#x000d;&amp;#x000a;</span></span>
<br /><br />I just finished with a fresh install and here it is again:
<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkred">5/18/2007 1:06 AM	Application Error	Faulting application doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, faulting module doom3.exe, version 1.0.0.1, fault address 0x0001e03f.&amp;#x000d;&amp;#x000a;</span></span>
<br /><br />Man, what's going on here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><br /><br />My last report:
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1302 win-x86 May 12 2005 10:40:52<br />2002 MHz AMD CPU with MMX &amp; 3DNow! &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2<br />2048 MB System Memory<br />256 MB Video Memory<br />Winsock Initialized<br />Found interface: {64B2528E-7662-44E9-A250-AFC1E4178E39} Marvell Yukon Gigabit Ethernet 10/100/1000Base-T Adapter, Copper RJ-45 - Packet Scheduler Miniport - 10.0.0.4/255.255.255.0<br />Sys_InitNetworking: adding loopback interface<br />doom using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br />------ Initializing File System ------<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 with checksum 0x29cdb978<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 with checksum 0xc9d99db8<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 with checksum 0x40244be0<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 with checksum 0x64243cc7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 with checksum 0x79bee669<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 with checksum 0x765e4f8b<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 with checksum 0x8ffc3621<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 with checksum 0x95b65ab<br />Current search path:<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3/base<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 (48 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 (63 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 (5137 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 (4676 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 (6120 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 (8972 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 (2698 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 (2 files)<br />game DLL: 0x0 in pak: 0x0<br />Addon pk4s:<br />file system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- Initializing Decls -----<br />------------------------------<br />------- Initializing renderSystem --------<br />using ARB renderSystem<br />renderSystem initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />5180 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />Couldn't open journal files<br />execing editor.cfg<br />execing default.cfg<br />execing DoomConfig.cfg<br />couldn't exec autoexec.cfg<br />5180 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />----- Initializing Sound System ------<br />sound system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- R_InitOpenGL -----<br />Initializing OpenGL subsystem<br />...registered window class<br />...registered fake window class<br />...initializing QGL<br />...calling LoadLibrary( 'opengl32' ): succeeded<br />...calling CDS: ok<br />...created window @ 0,0 (1280x1024)<br />Initializing OpenGL driver<br />...getting DC: succeeded<br />...PIXELFORMAT 10 selected<br />...creating GL context: succeeded<br />...making context current: succeeded<br /><br />------- Input Initialization -------<br />Initializing DirectInput...<br />mouse: DirectInput initialized.<br />keyboard: DirectInput initialized.<br />------------------------------------<br />sound: STEREO<br />...using GL_ARB_multitexture<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_combine<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_cube_map<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_dot3<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_add<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_non_power_of_two<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_compression<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_compression_s3tc<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_filter_anisotropic<br />   maxTextureAnisotropy: 16.000000<br />...using GL_1.4_texture_lod_bias<br />X..GL_EXT_shared_texture_palette not found<br />...using GL_EXT_texture3D<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_wrap<br />...using GL_NV_register_combiners<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_two_side<br />X..GL_ATI_fragment_shader not found<br />X..GL_ATI_text_fragment_shader not found<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_buffer_object<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_program<br />...using GL_ARB_fragment_program<br />...using EXT_depth_bounds_test<br />---------- R_NV20_Init ----------<br />---------------------------------<br />----------- R200_Init -----------<br />Not available.<br />---------- R_ARB2_Init ----------<br />Available.<br />---------------------------------<br />----- R_ReloadARBPrograms -----<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/shadow.vp<br />glprogs/R200_interaction.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_bumpAndLight.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_specularColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseAndSpecularColor.vp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/arbVP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />glprogs/arbFP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />-------------------------------<br />using ARB_vertex_buffer_object memory<br />using ARB2 renderSystem<br />found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4/gamex86.dll<br />copy gamex86.dll to C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\gamex86.dll<br />0 0 1280 1024<br />Regenerated world, staticAllocCount = 0.<br />Shutting down sound hardware<br />idRenderSystem::Shutdown()<br />Shutting down OpenGL subsystem<br />...wglMakeCurrent( NULL, NULL ): success<br />...deleting GL context: success<br />...releasing DC: success<br />...destroying window<br />...shutting down QGL<br />...unloading OpenGL DLL<br />wrong game DLL API version</div></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178425" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 8:42 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm not sure what's going on there but this is curious...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">wrong game DLL API version</div>
<br /><br />Generally this error message means the game library and main executable are not the same version.
<br /><br />It's pretty common to see this error message creep up when dealing with mods but I assume you're running the vanilla game, in which case it sounds more like the latest patch didn't install correctly.
<br /><br />I would suggest reinstalling the game from scratch, installing ROE, and then installing the 1.3.1 patch.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178451" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 3:21 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The problem is that I'm running into this <span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkred">ALL THE TIME</span></span>!  I have uninstalled and reinstalled this game atleast four to five times, each with the same issue.  I use all the patches and yes you are correct, I am running a mod, [Annihilation X], to be exact.  Did you read the very beginning where the game locks up in the running mode on me?  I have a lot of strange sh!t going on here. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178458" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 6:06 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">My last report:<br /><br />DOOM 1.3.1302 win-x86 May 12 2005 10:40:52<br /><br />... snip ...<br /><br />------ Initializing File System ------<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 with checksum 0x29cdb978<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 with checksum 0xc9d99db8<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 with checksum 0x40244be0<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 with checksum 0x64243cc7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 with checksum 0x79bee669<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 with checksum 0x765e4f8b<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 with checksum 0x8ffc3621<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 with checksum 0x95b65ab<br />Current search path:<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3/base<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 (48 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 (63 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 (5137 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 (4676 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 (6120 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 (8972 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 (2698 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 (2 files)<br />game DLL: 0x0 in pak: 0x0<br /><br />.. snip ...<br /><br />found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4/gamex86.dll<br />copy gamex86.dll to C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\gamex86.dll <br /><br /></div>
<br /><br />You have a misconfigured install here. "DOOM 1.3.1302" means you are running the EXE from the 1.3 patch (May 2005).
<br /><br />In your "base" folder you should also have the following files...
<br /><br />    pak007.pk4
<br />    game01.pk4
<br />    game02.pk4
<br />    game03.pk4
<br /><br />You're using Windows, it should be trying to load the gamex86.dll file from game03.pk4 but what is happening is that it is using the one from game00.pk4 (from 1.0, 1.1 or 1.2) which is not compatible with the EXE you have in the "C:\Program Files\Doom 3" folder.
<br /><br />Also, the log you posted here isn't running the Annihilation-X mod, just standard Doom 3.
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178459" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 6:11 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmm... I just read the info on the the Annihilation-X mod. It looks to me as though they've included copyrighted music tracks within the game. Naughty naughty. Unless they got permission from KorN et al of course.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178462" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 6:49 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Hmm... I just read the info on the the Annihilation-X mod. It looks to me as though they've included copyrighted music tracks within the game. Naughty naughty. Unless they got permission from KorN et al of course.</div><br /><br />Hmm...!  I don't know about that part. Actually, yes I do!  I'll unpak the pk4 file they're in and get rid of the SOB's, then just repak the file without them.  Now, that you had brought that up has me in doubt!  I don't like that music anyway! <br /><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Also, the log you posted here isn't running the Annihilation-X mod, just standard Doom 3.</div>  Well, that's really strange, because It's running the mod that has caused much of this issue... second thought, it's not only the mod I was having these issues with.  In the beginning statement of my post, where the forward - run mode would lock on, started when I was playing just the Doom3 game! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" />   Any suggestions? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br /><br />Added:  I'm getting to go through another fresh install using all three patches.  I'll screenshot my directory's folder and show what files are in them.  Hopefully this will help to figure out what's going on. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178465" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:04 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What folder did the mod install itself in? Or did you do a manual install? If so, where did you put it?
<br /><br />Mods should go in their own folder e.g.
<br /><br />"C:\Program Files\Doom 3\AnnX"
<br /><br />and then you start doom with a fs_game parameter
<br /><br />doom3.exe +set fs_game AnnX
<br /><br />or just load it from the mods menu.
<br /><br />NEVER install a full mod into the "base" folder. The <span style="font-style: italic">only</span> PK4 files you should find in there (other than the standard ones) are custom MP mods.
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178466" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:08 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here's my directory...
<br /><br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\Annihilation X
<br /><br />I put nothing in my Doom 3 base directory.  If mods are full versions, then they get dropped into the Doom 3 directory in their own folders and I load them from the "Mods" menu. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />I'll be back... doing a fresh install and going to test it... <span style="text-decoration: underline"><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="color: darkred">again!!</span></span></span></span></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178470" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:43 pm "><author>LDAsh</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If you're getting a suddenly-running-all-the-time "bug" then it might be evil StickyKeys because you're holding shift for a number of seconds, or can happen when playing with the process priority from the task manager.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178472" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 7:59 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">LDAsh wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">If you're getting a suddenly-running-all-the-time "bug" then it might be evil StickyKeys because you're holding shift for a number of seconds, or can happen when playing with the process priority from the task manager.</div>
<br /><br />Thank you... but I have "StickyKeys" turned off. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178474" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 8:02 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok.. here's what my directories look like.
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">Contents of base folder after first install and no patch applied:<br /><br />doomkey<br />game00.pk4<br />pak000.pk4<br />pak001.pk4<br />pak002.pk4<br />pak003.pk4<br />pak004.pk4<br />-----------------------------------------------------<br />Applying [D3_1_1.exe]<br /><br />pak005.pk4  -  added<br />----------------------------------------------------<br />Installing [D3_ROE] and the inevitable [D3_1_2.exe] patch.<br /><br />pak006.pk4  -  added<br />xpkey  -  added<br /><br />Including the directory:  C:\Program Files\Doom 3\d3xp   which contains;<br /><br />game00.pk4<br />pak000.pk4<br />--------------------------------------------------------<br /><br />Installing the [DOOM3_1.3.1.exe] patch.<br /><br />Added to base folder;<br /><br />game01.pk4<br />game02.pk4<br />game03.pk4<br />pak007.pk4<br />pak008.pk4<br />----------------------------------------------------------<br /><br />Added to d3xp folder;<br /><br />game01.pk4<br />game02.pk4<br />game03.pk4<br />pak001.pk4</div>
<br /><br /><br />These are the files I have in both directories after installing Doom3, ROE and all three patches.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178484" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 9:47 pm "><author>Hex</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Crazy idea:  Just install d3.  no ROE or any other mod.  just plain D3.
<br /><br />Does the problem happen then?  
<br /><br />if no, install a (one) mod.  
<br /><br />Does the problem happen then?
<br /><br />etc</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178486" date="Posted: Fri May 18, 2007 10:04 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Hex wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Crazy idea:  Just install d3.  no ROE or any other mod.  just plain D3.<br /><br />Does the problem happen then?  <br /><br />if no, install a (one) mod.  <br /><br />Does the problem happen then?<br /><br />etc</div>
<br /><br /><br />Hmm... Not a bad idea! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /><br /><br />I do have this issue though.  It won't F5 "quicksave" for me.  Here's the console report.  Edited:  Actually, let me be a little more clear about what I'm saying here.  When I try to load a save that I attempted a "F5" save, this is what I've been getting.
<br /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://img408.imageshack.us/img408/2702/errorbd9.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br /><br />Any help here? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178517" date="Posted: Sat May 19, 2007 8:39 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That issue is likely derivative of the issue we discussed initially. The main executable and the game library being loaded are not compatible. Because of this discrepancy, you may find all sorts of features that don't function properly. Saving and loading games is not an exception.
<br /><br />Prior to reinstallation, if you haven't already, delete the Doom 3 folder and all it's contents. You don't need any stray files from a previous install present possibly causing the problem to reoccur.
<br /><br />For the time being, don't concern yourself with any mods. Your goal is simply to get Doom 3 working.
<br /><br />Also, don't bother with the intermediate updates. Simply install the game and then immediately update to 1.3.1. Delete any patches you currently have on your desktop and download the 1.3.1 patch from a reputable source if not directly from id itself.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178538" date="Posted: Sat May 19, 2007 4:08 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Okay...  Thank you very much... I'll do exactly as you say!  Your patients and understanding is highly appreciated. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />Edited:  I just checked Id Software's site for offical updates as you suggested.  Unfortunately, they don't carry it anymore.  I ran into a dead link there. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178564" date="Posted: Sat May 19, 2007 11:06 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I just checked Id Software's site for offical updates as you suggested.  Unfortunately, they don't carry it anymore.  I ran into a dead link there. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>
<br /><br />The only "official" word from id Software about the 1.3.1 patch has been in Timothee Besset's .plan...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116/http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/">http://www.bluesnews.com/plans/476/</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178654" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 1:07 am "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">mac53 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">How do I explain this?  When playing Doom 3 and I'm walking through doing my thing, all of a sudden the run mode locks in and won't return to normal unless I exit out of the game.  Then when I'm back at my desk-top, at least 15 or so icons are blue as if they were all selected.  I can't turn this off.  I tried "Ctrl", "Alt" &amp; "Del" and the "task manager" doesn't open, so I can't see what's going on.  Start, "Turn Off Computer", doesn't function either.  The only way I can reboot my computer is to hit the "reset" button and this is the only way that will get me out of this situation.  This happens ALOT!   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div><br /><br />Then <div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">For the time being, don't concern yourself with any mods. Your goal is simply to get Doom 3 working. <br /><br />Also, don't bother with the intermediate updates. Simply install the game and then immediately update to 1.3.1. Delete any patches you currently have on your desktop and download the 1.3.1 patch from a reputable source if not directly from id itself.</div>
<br /><br />I followed your instructions, this time I installed Doom 3 with just the [DOOM3-1.3.1] patch and no mods.  Started to play the game and into the third map when it did it again.  This time I was able to "screenshot" the Desktop.
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://img237.imageshack.us/img237/9474/error2qp4.png" alt="Image" /><br /><br />What do I do now?... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178662" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 6:03 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Launch the game and type "conDump test" into the console. Then browse to your Doom 3 installation directory, open the base folder and locate a file named test.txt.
<br /><br />Open this file. This will be a dump of all the output from the console. Locate the following lines...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll</div>
<br /><br />The first line should read "DOOM 1.3.1.1304" as you have installed the latest patch. The second line should read "game03.pk4" as it should be loading the version of gamex86.dll from that pk4.
<br /><br />If these two lines match the criteria outlined above, then the patch has been installed successfully and it's time to rule out the game itself as the cause of your problems.
<br /><br />That said, it sounds to me like the game is losing focus and your input is being inadvertently interpreted by windows as clicking and dragging about on the desktop. That would explain the stuck key and the selected icons on your desktop.
<br /><br />The question however is why the game would lose focus and that's hard to answer. Obviously it's some process running in the background that's at fault. But it's pretty much impossible to determine which without knowing everything that you have installed and subsequently the common faults experienced with each of those applications.
<br /><br />The best I can tell you is to try running the game with as few background processes running as possible. You might try running windows in safe mode permitted Doom 3 will run under those conditions.
<br /><br />I'm not saying that's going to solve your problems but it will verify that the problem is indeed caused by some external program. From that point you will have to isolate the offending program by via trial and error.
<br /><br />I suggest learning how to prevent programs from launching alongside windows by using "msconfig". Google it if need be.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p178698" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 4:41 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i never seen a desktop with more icons on it ever <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br />in my experience its best to have as few things on desktop
<br />as possible, better to have them on the quickstart down left
<br />next to start, just a friendly advice <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p178715" date="Posted: Mon May 21, 2007 8:41 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">i never seen a desktop with more icons on it ever <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /><br />in my experience its best to have as few things on desktop<br />as possible, better to have them on the quickstart down left<br />next to start, just a friendly advice <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>
<br /><br />You think that's a lot!!!  You should have seen some of the other computers I have seen.  Icons on the desktop is just a thing of preference, that's all. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223116im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179508" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 5:23 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Launch the game and type "conDump test" into the console. Then browse to your Doom 3 installation directory, open the base folder and locate a file named test.txt.<br /><br />Open this file. This will be a dump of all the output from the console. Locate the following lines...<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll</div><br /><br />The first line should read "DOOM 1.3.1.1304" as you have installed the latest patch. The second line should read "game03.pk4" as it should be loading the version of gamex86.dll from that pk4.<br /><br />If these two lines match the criteria outlined above, then the patch has been installed successfully and it's time to rule out the game itself as the cause of your problems.<br /><br />That said, it sounds to me like the game is losing focus and your input is being inadvertently interpreted by windows as clicking and dragging about on the desktop. That would explain the stuck key and the selected icons on your desktop.<br /><br />The question however is why the game would lose focus and that's hard to answer. Obviously it's some process running in the background that's at fault. But it's pretty much impossible to determine which without knowing everything that you have installed and subsequently the common faults experienced with each of those applications.<br /><br />The best I can tell you is to try running the game with as few background processes running as possible. You might try running windows in safe mode permitted Doom 3 will run under those conditions.<br /><br />I'm not saying that's going to solve your problems but it will verify that the problem is indeed caused by some external program. From that point you will have to isolate the offending program by via trial and error.<br /><br />I suggest learning how to prevent programs from launching alongside windows by using "msconfig". Google it if need be.</div><br /><br /><br />Ok guys, sorry to have taken so long in getting back to you with this, it's just the [whole-ball-of-wax] just frustrated me and I had to walk away for awhile.<br /><br />rich_is_bored...[Hmm... I bet it is] <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />   I did the con dump you taught me to do and here's the whole 'nine-yards', because it wrote to notepad.  I have a problem!  Here's the report:<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">Con Test wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51<br />2002 MHz AMD CPU with MMX &amp; 3DNow! &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2<br />2048 MB System Memory<br />256 MB Video Memory<br />Winsock Initialized<br />Found interface: {64B2528E-7662-44E9-A250-AFC1E4178E39} Marvell Yukon Gigabit<br />Ethernet 10/100/1000Base-T Adapter, Copper RJ-45 - Packet Scheduler Miniport -<br /> 10.0.0.4/255.255.255.0<br />Sys_InitNetworking: adding loopback interface<br />doom using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br /><br />Section Edited:  Too much info...</div>
<br /><br />What now, buddy? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179518" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 7:53 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">So exactly what goes wrong now? That dump looks fine for base D3 using 1.3.1.1304. And it connected OK to the master server at id to set your guid value.
<br /><br />What happens next that is wrong?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179519" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 7:58 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />If you don't mind taking the time and starting here:
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2909&amp;postdays=0&amp;postorder=asc&amp;start=60">http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewto ... c&amp;start=60</a><!-- m -->
<br />and reading through because there are numerous issues occuring.
<br /><br />The last one is that Doom 3 is totally crashing when I load a mod... any mod, doesn't matter!
<br /><br />now, according to "rich_is_bored" he had stated that when a con test is conducted that these two lines should appear at the top of the test
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51</div><br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll</div>
<br /><br /><br />Look at the test results I posted, the second code I listed here, never ocurred, so it is apparent that there's an issue going on here.
<br /><br />You need to read to catch up, budddy.
<br />------------------------------------------------------------------
<br /><br />Edited:
<br /><br />Reinstalled Doom3 w/ ROE &amp;   DOOM3-1.3.1.exe  update patch.
<br /><br />Everthing looked fine in the test report except at the bottom where I have it posted here.
<br /><div class="quotetitle">condump test wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">DOOM 1.3.1.1304 win-x86 Jan 16 2007 15:36:51<br />2002 MHz AMD CPU with MMX &amp; 3DNow! &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2<br />2048 MB System Memory<br />256 MB Video Memory<br />Winsock Initialized<br />Found interface: {64B2528E-7662-44E9-A250-AFC1E4178E39} Marvell Yukon Gigabit<br />Ethernet 10/100/1000Base-T Adapter, Copper RJ-45 - Packet Scheduler Miniport -<br /> 10.0.0.4/255.255.255.0<br />Sys_InitNetworking: adding loopback interface<br />doom using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br />------ Initializing File System ------<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 with checksum 0x29cdb978<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game01.pk4 with checksum 0x51c6981f<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game02.pk4 with checksum 0xf3ec6f7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4 with checksum 0x5d4230ea<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 with checksum 0x2cb26dc3<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 with checksum 0x40244be0<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 with checksum 0x64243cc7<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 with checksum 0x79bee669<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 with checksum 0x765e4f8b<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 with checksum 0x8ffc3621<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 with checksum 0x95b65ab<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak007.pk4 with checksum 0x666bdb3c<br />Loaded pk4 C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak008.pk4 with checksum 0x23ae5993<br />Current search path:<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3/base<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak008.pk4 (3 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak007.pk4 (38 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak006.pk4 (48 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak005.pk4 (63 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak004.pk4 (5137 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak003.pk4 (4676 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak002.pk4 (6120 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak001.pk4 (8972 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\pak000.pk4 (2698 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4 (2 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game02.pk4 (2 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game01.pk4 (2 files)<br />C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game00.pk4 (2 files)<br />game DLL: 0x0 in pak: 0x0<br />Addon pk4s:<br />file system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- Initializing Decls -----<br />------------------------------<br />------- Initializing renderSystem --------<br />using ARB renderSystem<br />renderSystem initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />5206 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />Couldn't open journal files<br />execing editor.cfg<br />execing default.cfg<br />execing DoomConfig.cfg<br />couldn't exec autoexec.cfg<br />5206 strings read from strings/english.lang<br />----- Initializing Sound System ------<br />sound system initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />----- R_InitOpenGL -----<br />Initializing OpenGL subsystem<br />...registered window class<br />...registered fake window class<br />...initializing QGL<br />...calling LoadLibrary( 'opengl32' ): succeeded<br />...calling CDS: ok<br />...created window @ 0,0 (1024x768)<br />Initializing OpenGL driver<br />...getting DC: succeeded<br />...PIXELFORMAT 10 selected<br />...creating GL context: succeeded<br />...making context current: succeeded<br /><br />------- Input Initialization -------<br />Initializing DirectInput...<br />mouse: DirectInput initialized.<br />keyboard: DirectInput initialized.<br />------------------------------------<br />sound: STEREO<br />...using GL_ARB_multitexture<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_combine<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_cube_map<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_dot3<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_env_add<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_non_power_of_two<br />...using GL_ARB_texture_compression<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_compression_s3tc<br />...using GL_EXT_texture_filter_anisotropic<br />   maxTextureAnisotropy: 16.000000<br />...using GL_1.4_texture_lod_bias<br />X..GL_EXT_shared_texture_palette not found<br />...using GL_EXT_texture3D<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_wrap<br />...using GL_NV_register_combiners<br />...using GL_EXT_stencil_two_side<br />X..GL_ATI_fragment_shader not found<br />X..GL_ATI_text_fragment_shader not found<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_buffer_object<br />...using GL_ARB_vertex_program<br />...using GL_ARB_fragment_program<br />...using EXT_depth_bounds_test<br />---------- R_NV20_Init ----------<br />---------------------------------<br />----------- R200_Init -----------<br />Not available.<br />---------- R_ARB2_Init ----------<br />Available.<br />---------------------------------<br />----- R_ReloadARBPrograms -----<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/test.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/interaction.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/bumpyEnvironment.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/ambientLight.vfp<br />glprogs/shadow.vp<br />glprogs/R200_interaction.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_bumpAndLight.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_specularColor.vp<br />glprogs/nv20_diffuseAndSpecularColor.vp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/environment.vfp<br />glprogs/arbVP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />glprogs/arbFP_glasswarp.txt: File not found<br />-------------------------------<br />using ARB_vertex_buffer_object memory<br />using ARB2 renderSystem<br />found DLL in pak file: C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\game03.pk4/gamex86.dll<br />copy gamex86.dll to C:\Program Files\Doom 3\base\gamex86.dll<br />game using MMX &amp; SSE &amp; SSE2 for SIMD processing<br />enabled Flush-To-Zero mode<br />enabled Denormals-Are-Zero mode<br />--------- Initializing Game ----------<br />gamename: baseDOOM-1<br />gamedate: Jan 16 2007<br />Initializing event system<br />...473 event definitions<br />Initializing class hierarchy<br />...142 classes, 191092 bytes for event callbacks<br />Initializing scripts<br />Compiled 'interpolateShaderParm': 1355.1 ms<br />---------- Compile stats ----------<br /><br />Memory usage:<br />     Strings: 79, 9648 bytes<br />  Statements: 67875, 1357500 bytes<br />   Functions: 2109, 250532 bytes<br />   Variables: 147376 bytes<br />    Mem used: 2476344 bytes<br /> Static data: 2277552 bytes<br />   Allocated: 3281600 bytes<br /> Thread size: 7068 bytes<br /><br />...6 aas types<br />game initialized.<br />--------------------------------------<br />-------- Initializing Session --------<br />WARNING: idChoiceWindow::InitVars: gui 'guis/mainmenu.gui' window 'SNDBPrimary<br />' references undefined cvar 's_driver'<br />session initialized<br />--------------------------------------<br />--- Common Initialization Complete ---<br />------------- Warnings ---------------<br />during DOOM 3 initialization...<br />WARNING: idChoiceWindow::InitVars: gui 'guis/mainmenu.gui' window 'SNDBPrimary<br />' references undefined cvar 's_driver'<br />1 warnings<br />guid set to lC2fU1LyeEE<br />]condump test<br />Dumped console text to test.txt.<br /><br /></div>
<br /><br /><br />Is this something to be concerned about?  Doom 3 is still crashing when I try to launch a mod from the opening screen. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179529" date="Posted: Fri Jun 01, 2007 10:41 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The warning at the end is fine, just ignore it. The menus reference a CVar that only exists in the Linux build of the game.
<br /><br />As for your other problem the log you posted has been edited so I can't check through it now.
<br /><br />As for mods not working, have the ones you tried been updated to work with the new D3 1.3.1 patch that you're using?
<br /><br />Edit: I just checked with one of the Annihilation-X team; it is only for D3 1.3 right now. They're working on a 1.3.1 compatible version.
<br /><br />Edit Again: Apparently he was misinformed. There are no gamecode changes in A-X so it should work with 1.3 or 1.3.1. I downloaded it from here...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://doom3.filefront.com/file/Annihilation_X;76651">http://doom3.filefront.com/file/Annihilation_X;76651</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />... and got not problems starting it up.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179534" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 12:09 am "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">@simulation
<br /><br />I have "AnnihilationX" and it also is crashing Doom3. I have reposted the "conDump test" for your review.  But, not matter what I do, I just can't run <span style="color: red"><span style="font-style: italic"><span style="font-weight: bold">any</span></span></span> mods no matter what they are, without me getting a "Doom3 has to shut down, now" warning.  I don't know what the hell going on.  Before, when I first started to run into problems, there were other [different] issues happening..., now I can't even get to the point where the first ones ocurred without it crashing on me first. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_redface.gif" alt=":oops:" title="Embarassed" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_evil.gif" alt=":evil:" title="Evil or Very Mad" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179550" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 7:47 am "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've looked at your condump and both lines are present and match the criteria I outlined originally. For all intensive purposes, Doom 3 appears to be up to date and it should run without issue.
<br /><br />That said, I'm assuming the game itself runs without any problems. It's only when you try to launch a mod that the game crashes.
<br /><br />And judging from your description you end up staring at a dialog like this...
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.ciac.org/ciac/bulletins/images/m005.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.
<br /><br />The only thing I can do is suggest an alternative way to launch mods. One that hopefully avoids whatever causes the crash.
<br /><br />That said, you can try making a shortcut to launch Doom 3 with the appropriate command line parameters to launch each mod.
<br /><br />General instructions are here...
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Startup_parameters#Windows">http://www.modwiki.net/wiki/Startup_parameters#Windows</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />What you're aiming for is something like this...
<br /><br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">"C:\Program Files\Doom3.exe" +set fs_game [name of mod folder]</div>
<br /><br />Aside from that, I have no clue what to suggest.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179562" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 9:36 am "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div>
<br /><br />If you click on the "click here" you'll get some basic error info.
<br /><br />Under the "Error signature" section you'll see ModName. This is nothing to do with game "mods", it is the name of the windows module in which the error occurred. That may help you locate the source of the problem.
<br /><br />If ModName is doom3.exe or gamex86.dll then the problem is <span style="font-style: italic">probably</span> just doom related. If ModName is something else do a google search on the name and see what turns up.
<br /><br />Sim</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179573" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 2:30 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">rich_is_bored wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Unfortunately, those dialogs are worthless. I couldn't begin to tell you what the problem is.</div><br /><br />If you click on the "click here" you'll get some basic error info.<br /><br />Under the "Error signature" section you'll see ModName. This is nothing to do with game "mods", it is the name of the windows module in which the error occurred. That may help you locate the source of the problem.<br /><br />If ModName is doom3.exe or gamex86.dll then the problem is <span style="font-style: italic">probably</span> just doom related. If ModName is something else do a google search on the name and see what turns up.<br /><br />Sim</div>
<br /><br /><br />I did do that and it was Doom3.exe... anyway, I really would like to thank you guys for being there during this "wonderful" moment, you really helped me to try to funnel this down.  Someone told me that the 3.1.1 patch was the blame and not to use it, just use the 3.1 patch instead. Well, I followed his instructions with a new install and using the 3.1..., it doesn't crash anymore and I'm actually running mods now.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179586" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 6:59 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">nice  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /><br />im also avoiding that 1.31 patch, it totally screwed me
<br />over too and im having no issues with anything with
<br />"only" the 1.3 patch installed <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179597" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 10:21 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">nice  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /><br />it totally screwed me over too </div>
<br /><br />Can you be more specific? Would be useful to add your issues to the "knowledge base" of problems people have with 1.3.1.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179603" date="Posted: Sat Jun 02, 2007 11:50 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">nice  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /><br />it totally screwed me over too </div><br /><br />Can you be more specific? Would be useful to add your issues to the "knowledge base" of problems people have with 1.3.1.</div>
<br /><br />There's really not much to add as far as details...except...<span style="font-size: 150%; line-height: normal"><span style="color: red"><span style="font-weight: bold"> don't use it.</span></span></span></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179634" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 5:33 am "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">lol  very succinct there mac ^^
<br />well to put it short, i dl the 1.31 patch,
<br />patched my doom3 and then crahsboombang sorta,
<br />nada worked, tried to run my doom modded stuff with fs_game
<br />as per usual, crashed, tried to run vanilla doom by start-programs-doom3
<br />ie NOT any desktop shortcut, crashed, tried to run doom via
<br />an unaltered shortcut, crashed, thats about it, well that and 
<br />some language i cannot really write here, it ended with me
<br />simply flushing doom from my computer as well as the
<br />1,31 patch, now i reinstalled doom with 1.3 only,
<br />dont wanna repeat meself but 1.31 wont get near my
<br />doom again EVERRRR !  
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" />  Thats 4 things now ill never have on my computer as long
<br />as i can draw breath, patch 1.31, xp-lite, steam and vista  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_rolleyes.gif" alt=":roll:" title="Rolling Eyes" /><br />Well, five things actually, if i reinstall far Cry their 1.32 patch
<br />(if you know FC you know how that one SUcK) wont be
<br />in my registry either  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /><br /><br />thats MY 2 cents, or five cents if you will  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179638" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 5:48 am "><author>Marineofuac</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Notice how idsoftware's site (and the doom 3 update system) says nothing about the new patch. I think thier waiting for that one moment to say "oh all teh mods is 1.3.1 now and all teh peoples having teh vista or updated stuffs" for them to acknowledge its exsistence.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179681" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 4:04 pm "><author>simulation</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">then crahsboombang sorta</div>
<br /><br />I was hoping for something a little <span style="font-style: italic">more</span> specific than that. Were you getting an actual crash like mac53 or just an error ("DLL API Error" is most common when using non-updated mods).
<br /><br />As for the lack of publicity on the patch, this is something I'm pursuing with id. If I hear anything further I'll post some news.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179684" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 4:55 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">simulation wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I was hoping for something a little <span style="font-style: italic">more</span> specific than that. Were you getting an actual crash like mac53 or just an error ("DLL API Error" is most common when using non-updated mods).<br /><br />As for the lack of publicity on the patch, this is something I'm pursuing with id. If I hear anything further I'll post some news.</div><br /><br />Your comment on the mods... now that I am not using the 1.3.1. patch, I have absolutely <span style="font-weight: bold">no</span> problems with either playing Doom 3 itself or any mods,... none at all!<br /><br />The only thing I can say here is, if you click <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=2909&amp;postdays=0&amp;postorder=asc&amp;start=60" class="postlink">here</a> it will take you to the very first report of mine when I started to have these issues and trust me, there were numerous different types. Ranging from the crashing when I tried to play a mod, to numerous icons being locked in activate mode on my desktop.  The date of this first post was 05/17!! and finally in June after walking away for about a week, someone helped with an idea that hit the target! I know I have re-installed the game atleast a dozen times within this time frame, not to mention that I even tried shutting down my anti-virus software and other background running processes down to just the os, and still had crashes and problems.<br /><br />Here's what I think it is.  1.3.1. has been built with the 64 bit vista in mind and it's dumb-founded when ran on a 32 bit os. Doom 3 was built for 32 bits and so was all the patches up to 1.3.1.  It's appearing to me, that it's a case of 'either, or'... not 'both' when it comes to software, especially in this case.  Personally, I think that 1.3.1. is a beta and hasn't been tested properly.  I'm not a pro here, nor do I claim to be a 'puter wiz', but there are times where it doesn't take a 'rocket scientist' to see what's going on, just one to explain it!  I want to help with this and I'll do my best.<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">tried to run vanilla doom</div>
<br /><br /><br />What the hell is "Vanilla Doom"?  I see it mentioned everywhere on forums, being used in different terms.  Especially in the Doom 2 world. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_redface.gif" alt=":oops:" title="Embarassed" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179692" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:10 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">for me "vanilla doom" means the original game, no roe and no mods whatsoever, just "pure"doom3.exe, i may be wrong on how others perceieve that use of "vanilla doom" but for me, thats the intent of the term
<br /><br />edit
<br /><br />I was hoping for something a little more specific than that. Were you getting an actual crash like mac53 or just an error ("DLL API Error" is most common when using non-updated mods). "
<br /><br />lil of both kinda, actually i have a hard time remembering EXACTLY
<br />what happened, the term "seeing red" kicked in, sooooo ....   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179694" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:19 pm "><author>Mordenkainen</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">for me "vanilla doom" means the original game, no roe and no mods whatsoever, just "pure"doom3.exe, i may be wrong on how others perceieve that use of "vanilla doom" but for me, thats the intent of the term</div>
<br /><br />That's it.
<br /><br />Anyway, as a general tip if anyone is having problems the first thing I would suggest is installing the game on a path without spaces. Sometimes they don't causes problems but other times they do, especially if you're into modding.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179696" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:27 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Mordenkainen wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">That's it. <br /><br />Anyway, as a general tip if anyone is having problems the first thing I would suggest is installing the game on a path without spaces. Sometimes they don't causes problems but other times they do, especially if you're into modding.</div>
<br /><br />You know... I thought about that and did this, first.  Directory was
<br />C:\Doom 3\... instead of the default in the program files, but the problem with that is that when the installer writes the program folder, it writes as Doom 3, [with space anyway]! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179697" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 6:30 pm "><author>mac53</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">vinnie_jones wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">for me "vanilla doom" means the original game, no roe and no mods whatsoever, just "pure"doom3.exe, i may be wrong on how others perceieve that use of "vanilla doom" but for me, thats the intent of the term</div>
<br /><br />Thanks "Vin"... <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p179713" date="Posted: Sun Jun 03, 2007 9:43 pm "><author>vinnie_jones</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Youre welcome Mac53   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br />lets form a "anti-patch 1.31 club" lol   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20130319223029im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
