<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="2981"><title>Ladders</title><posts><post id="p29041" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:25 pm "><author>Krygor</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok, i know something material.... yah thats about it. How do i make ladders again? And where is the ladder material under in the materials folder?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29045" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 6:31 pm "><author>bullet</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">make a small thin brush over the thing you want to climb, and then texture it with   textures -&gt; common -&gt; ladder</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29056" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:03 pm "><author>Krygor</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">no func or special material 0_o</div>]]></body></post><post id="p29058" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:05 pm "><author>St4rdog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Krygor wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">no func or special material 0_o</div>
<br /><br />The "ladder" in "common" IS sort of like the special material. Just simply texture a brush with "ladder" and you can walk into it to climb it, nifty  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522163302im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p29061" date="Posted: Thu Aug 05, 2004 7:09 pm "><author>bullet</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">the common -&gt; ladder texture is the special material. You make your ladder or climbable surface (like if you want to be able to up a mossy wall). Then you make a brush with common -&gt; ladder on it, that is the size of your ladder. Line the two up, and voila, whatever surface has that ladder material on it will be climbable.
<br /><br />You might get stuck at the top of the ladder, though. If you do and just sort of bounce up and down, then take the clipper tool and cut the corner off at the top so it's an easier slope for the player to get up.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30915" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 12:03 am "><author>Zanuff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I created an under-the-floor thing, that you can get down, but not back up.  Would you use ladder so the player can get back up?  When I do there is a climbing-ladder sound that doesn't quite fit with what I'm trying to accomplish.
<br /><br />It's either can't get down or can't get up without having a ladder.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p50005" date="Posted: Tue Sep 14, 2004 7:43 am "><author>-bluebox-</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i created a map with a ladder in it, but when loaded it up its was invisible, then i relised that the ladder only had a ladder texture on it but no other texture! therefore is there a way to put on the ladder texture and another texture so it can be seen?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p50010" date="Posted: Tue Sep 14, 2004 8:42 am "><author>b0ksah</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You create your ladder ... with normal textures ..then you make a brush the size of your ladder and then cover your ladder with it ..this brush you give the ladder texture. The ladder texture is invisble in-game, it just controls the ladder "ability" ... you can basically place ladder textured brushes on a wall to make it climbalbe if you want. again ...the ladder texture control a game function ... it's not a visble or "solid" texture.
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522163302im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522163302im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_twisted.gif" alt=":twisted:" title="Twisted Evil" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p50323" date="Posted: Wed Sep 15, 2004 5:54 am "><author>-bluebox-</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">doesn't matter i got it working! i just created a ladder-like model then put the ladder texture over the top!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p65182" date="Posted: Mon Nov 29, 2004 10:55 am "><author>Domarius</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Is their any info on making it possible for Monsters to climb ladders as well, and not just the player?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p65185" date="Posted: Mon Nov 29, 2004 11:04 am "><author>Duff</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Domarius wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Is their any info on making it possible for Monsters to climb ladders as well, and not just the player?</div>
<br /><br />in mars city underground a zombie climbs up a ladder doesn't he? have a look at him, its most likely a script though</div>]]></body></post><post id="p65202" date="Posted: Mon Nov 29, 2004 2:08 pm "><author>Domarius</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks.  I will, but I'm almost certain it's another one of the many scripts that take them across glass windows, bending through stairs, etc.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p196495" date="Posted: Sat Mar 15, 2008 5:00 pm "><author>PeppeJ</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It is no Script it is a animation in the Zombie entity List</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
