<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="3119"><title>How to add the recepionist fro Mars City?</title><posts><post id="p30036" date="Posted: Sat Aug 07, 2004 12:56 pm "><author>Dingo_aus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I a newbie at Doom3 (didn't see alpha or anything like that)
<br /><br />So my question is How do I add the Mars City Recepionist Model. I can place the entity but it shows in the editor without a  head and I can't seem to place one on it. And in game not even the body shows up.
<br /><br />Any idea on how to add this model with animations just like in the game?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30197" date="Posted: Sat Aug 07, 2004 5:38 pm "><author>Vash</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Basically, almost all models show up-editor without a head. You'll need to compile and playtest to see it with a head. You can use whatever animation you want be going to the entities properties and scrolling through the animations list at the bottom.
<br /><br />I got this working. Basically, I put in a func_static with a chair model, then put in marscity_recetionist2. I aligned it a bit to look like he was on the chair.
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162542im_/http://www.kemall.net/doom3/receptionist.JPG" alt="Image" /><br /><br />It isnt complete, he is typing on a keyboard that isnt there - and he collides a bit with the chair - but you can fix it up.
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162542/http://www.kemall.net/doom3/receptionist.map" class="postlink">Download Map</a> [<span style="font-weight: bold">Right click + Save as...</span>](ignore the zombie and stuff - that was for another test =P).</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30606" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 12:24 pm "><author>Dingo_aus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">dude - you ROCK!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p44516" date="Posted: Tue Aug 31, 2004 1:08 am "><author>SonicClang</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Actually the chair is part of the model. But for some reason it disappears once you kill the guy. No fun <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162542im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> I like killing the receptionist.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p44595" date="Posted: Tue Aug 31, 2004 3:31 am "><author>mittens</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Any idea how to rotate the entity? I tried doing so in the editor, and failed. I looked through the DEF files and saw nothing. Is it something associated with the animation (also, each marscity_receptionist has a different rotation value, from the looks of it).
<br /><br />Any ideas?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p44648" date="Posted: Tue Aug 31, 2004 6:50 am "><author>amusedtoe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">SonicClang wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Actually the chair is part of the model. But for some reason it disappears once you kill the guy. No fun <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162542im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> I like killing the receptionist.</div>
<br /><br />In my map the chair stays when I kill em, it's a moveable too.
<br /><br />To rotate them use the degree buttons in the bottom left corner of the entity window.  If those angles don't suit you just change the number to one of your own.  You may also have to delete any rotation key that ended up on it when you were trying to rotate it, still don't know if that's universal or not but it doesn't work for me otherwise.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p44752" date="Posted: Tue Aug 31, 2004 12:59 pm "><author>SonicClang</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I wonder why the chair disappears for me when I kill him. 
<br /><br />To rotate him press R and drag your mouse. He doesn't rotate to every single possible degree, only a few pre-set ones.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p45606" date="Posted: Thu Sep 02, 2004 3:45 am "><author>kator</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">SonicClang wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I wonder why the chair disappears for me when I kill him...</div>
<br /><br />I have the same problem.. the funny thing is I put a "outdoors box" around my map to support some windows and guess what.. I found a pile of chairs under my level resting on the bottom of the "outside" bounding box.. I can't figure out why they will rest there but not on the floor in the map..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p63537" date="Posted: Wed Nov 17, 2004 1:28 pm "><author>critanime</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">this is something to do with how the model was built i am guessing. when you kill the guy and open the terminal you get a error message saying that a item has gone past the phisical boundries of the map, into the void, and that it will replace it. 
<br /><br />it's a funny thing is the build engine in doom 3. Sort of rminds me of the Half life 1 engine in some respects. i had similar problems with it. 
<br /><br />but on  more related note i wanted to know about the keyboard they use. is that a model or is it built using brushes??</div>]]></body></post><post id="p65214" date="Posted: Mon Nov 29, 2004 4:36 pm "><author>Wykyd_1</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I think i know why this happens, I discovered that if you place a movable on the "floor" of your map with the point of the model touching the brush then when moved it will dissapear into it. I place moveables 1 or even .5 grid units away from the brush and they work fine.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p65245" date="Posted: Mon Nov 29, 2004 8:20 pm "><author>critanime</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I did some expeimentation on this matter and found that at times it also can have someting to do with the caulk texture. The caulk texture as far as i understand it tell the engine not to do anything with it. So you are basically left with a patch. I found that if something is thrown into a patch hard enough it will actually go through the patch in a sort of a bug state.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206096" date="Posted: Wed Oct 15, 2008 1:55 am "><author>bobvorn</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how can you make people be able to talk to you? I really need to know because I am like a noob at editing.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206156" date="Posted: Thu Oct 16, 2008 4:44 pm "><author>Alternate</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's one big-time necro there.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p206243" date="Posted: Sat Oct 18, 2008 8:27 pm "><author>bobvorn</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Alternate wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">That's one big-time necro there.</div><br /><br />were you talking about my question on how to make you be able to talk to people?</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
