<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="3185"><title>Projected lights</title><posts><post id="p30412" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 2:04 am "><author>kherman</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Can someone do a quick explanation on these?  I am having a hard time understanding how to aim the lights properly.  I can aim in a direction, I just  have a hard time making the light "perfect".</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30444" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 3:51 am "><author>Njal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What exactly do you want to know?
<br />You aim it by rotating and moving it and you control the spread of the light with the 3 size values in the light entity options (J) or whatever you want to call it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30500" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 7:30 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How to position projected lights:
<br /><br />- make a light
<br />- hit "j" to open the light inspector
<br />- make it a projected light 
<br />- close the light inspector
<br />- select the light (if deselcted) and use alt + lmb to drag the pink control points around
<br />- change the viewports to move the different control points around
<br />- if you can't then deselct and reselect the light, usually works</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30661" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 2:45 pm "><author>kherman</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for the responses.  I gues the control points are getting to me.  It's hard to make them aim "evenly" at a surface if you start toying with them.  And the 2D area doesn't make it easy to remedy the problem.
<br /><br />Also, when you press J and hte window pops up, the projected lights have 12 values you can set.  I am assuming those are never touched and the control points are the only real way to set up projected lights.  Is this true?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30662" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 2:52 pm "><author>Coolbreeze78</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thats not entirely true... my friend and I started playing with these controls ... they are pretty simple ... cant see them atm cause Im in hell but ill try and remember...
<br /><br />I know there were 3 different options ... one controls the aim of the light..with XYZ or left/right, forward/backward, up/down.  Another controls the cone of the light I beilive and the last one controls the depth or how far the light shines ... these may not be exactly right cause I cant see it right now but play with them in the editor and then push F7 to update what it looks like in the 3d render view...
<br /><br />Hope that helps...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30728" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 5:26 pm "><author>DaZ</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">the onlyt other useful values there are the explicict start/end points.
<br /><br />these allow you to control where the light starts and stops lighting the level along its trajectory. have a play and u will see what i mean</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30788" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 7:50 pm "><author>Unoid</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I feelt he pain of getitng projected lights to shine like we logicly think they should.
<br /><br />Quake2 mapping was so much easier, making a light ent and a info_target and linking the light to the target, then you give the radius and other Light properties.
<br /><br />The d3 way is a ton harder to get the same easy results. I've been playing around and projected lights simply suck. I'll make a good description with pics soon as to show how hard it is.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30792" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 8:01 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Unoid wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">The d3 way is a ton harder to get the same easy results. I've been playing around and projected lights simply suck. I'll make a good description with pics soon as to show how hard it is.</div>
<br /><br />They don't suck - they're plain awsome.
<br /><br />Only a poor craftsman blames his tools.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30825" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 9:04 pm "><author>kherman</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">BNA! wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle">Unoid wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">The d3 way is a ton harder to get the same easy results. I've been playing around and projected lights simply suck. I'll make a good description with pics soon as to show how hard it is.</div><br /><br />They don't suck - they're plain awsome.<br /><br />Only a poor craftsman blames his tools.</div>
<br /><br />But a craftsman still gets mad at a stripped screw once in a while.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30832" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 9:15 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">kherman wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">But a craftsman still gets mad at a tripped screw once in a while.</div>
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175602im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p30848" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 9:44 pm "><author>weedje</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ahhh, thats so cool, thanks for the info BNA! !   <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175602im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
