<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="3231"><title>Finding Leaks?</title><posts><post id="p30725" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 5:20 pm "><author>helix</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I keep on getting a leak and I have 0 clue where it's at. I've even taken a huge box and stuck it around my entire map so far and still have it.... any ideas?
<br />-Helix</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30729" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 5:27 pm "><author>DaZ</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">load up your map in the editor, then click the file menu and sselect pointfile.
<br /><br />this will show a line going through your level, follow it and see where it exits the map, theres your leak <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p30754" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 6:21 pm "><author>m4rine</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">also theres a menu that has find next leak location that will take you right to it, i cant remember what menu it is in but its there. this only works once you have loaded your point file (file - pointfile)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30755" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 6:23 pm "><author>Njal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The console also prints what entity that has leaked</div>]]></body></post><post id="p30840" date="Posted: Sun Aug 08, 2004 9:36 pm "><author>kat</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Njal wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">The console also prints what entity that has leaked</div>That's slightly misleading as it suggests the selected entity is at error when it's usually a gap in the brushwork. BSP basically uses the 1st entity it comes across, when it 'floods' that map to work out where they are in the map, as a point of reference to trace a route to the hole in the brushwork, just follow the route and you'll usually find it pass though a gap somewhere or other.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31094" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 5:13 am "><author>JustinBailey</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">
<!-- m -->
  <a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175607/http://blaze.spicelab.net/doom3/?tutorial=ge02">http://blaze.spicelab.net/doom3/?tutorial=ge02</a>
<!-- m -->
</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31129" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 6:11 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">JustinBailey wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">http://blaze.spicelab.net/doom3/?tutorial=ge02</div>
<br /><br />Finally added you to the tutorial listing <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p35175" date="Posted: Sat Aug 14, 2004 4:02 am "><author>JustinBailey</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hehe thanks <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p50775" date="Posted: Thu Sep 16, 2004 4:19 pm "><author>Vehementi Dominus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That helped a lot.
<br /><br />one thing though, what happens if the red line points to a brush tht's not a hole?
<br /><br />even when i put a box around the whole thing it still points to the same thing.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p50783" date="Posted: Thu Sep 16, 2004 5:06 pm "><author>Docgalaad</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Is this brush textured properly ?
<br />Some textures are forbidden if you intend to make this wall a hull for the map. 
<br /><br />Advice: each time you make a new wall in contact with the void, select the brush and apply a caulk texture. Once you placed the wall, travel inside the building and apply your custom textures, face by face (SHIFT-CTRL-ALT-MIDDLE-CLICK). 
<br /><br />In my opinion, a map should be entirely pink if seen from the void.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p50817" date="Posted: Thu Sep 16, 2004 6:34 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Don't waste your time appliyng caulk to every faces in the void.. just don't use materials that don't stop visibility, and be sure that on your brushes there aren't face with the  "_emptyname " material.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p50843" date="Posted: Thu Sep 16, 2004 7:33 pm "><author>KrisTof</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The best way I found to find the leaks following Pointfile is to use the arrow to move my camera on the outside of the map. (following it through the inside of the map is often useless)
<br /><br />There should be a red line sticking out of your map. Navigate your camera to the exiting point of the red line. 
<br /><br />Remember that some texture are not solid or have transparent parts, this would cause leakage. 
<br /><br />Only apply caulk when you really need it, like when you have curved patches.
<br /><br />My 2 cents.
<br /><br />Good luck !</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53634" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2004 2:39 am "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm still not getting the idea. The red line ended at a point, and left a gap to a second point. What's that supposed to mean? What do I do? It seems to be on or around my giant terrain model (the one that's a huge landscape with a power plant out in the distance. A little help, please?  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175607im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_mad.gif" alt=":x" title="Mad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p53636" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2004 2:57 am "><author>ecurB</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi evilartist,
<br /><br />I've noticed that sometimes the origin point of models can get set to somewhere outside the physical boundaries of the model itself... so you might have the origin point somewhere out in space even though the visible model is inside the map, and I believe that can cause a leak.
<br /><br />For simple models, there's a key combination to centre to origin point in the middle of the model geometry - I think it's <span style="font-style: italic">shift + o</span> (sorry, at work and without the editor in front of me at present). I don't know if this works on complex or imported models though.
<br /><br />You say the pointfile line ends at one spot then continues - what's sitting in between where it stops and where it starts again?
<br /><br />Cheers</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53779" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2004 7:08 pm "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I move the huge landscape model out of the way and see if there's anything that causes a leak there, but the leak seems to be out in the middle of nothing where the model used to be. I see the line end at a dot, then there's a second dot a small distance away from the first. What's going on and how do I fix this problem? Also, I already have a huge box of caulk-textured brushes bordering the entire level, so what can I do?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53788" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2004 7:19 pm "><author>goliathvt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Post the map.  I'll be happy to check it out for ya.
<br /><br />G</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53794" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2004 7:42 pm "><author>elroacho</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">make sure that line is completely surouned with a solid brush, i had that happen to me, there where no leaks but a red  line would appear under my map not "going into" it but by itself underneath all the brushes.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53828" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2004 9:28 pm "><author>headshotfairy</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">KrisTof wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Only apply caulk when you really need it, like when you have curved patches.</div>
<br /><br />Pray tell, what is "Caulk"? or Auto-Caulk? All I can tell is that it seems to be a special texture applied to exterior surfaces, and that some of the built in DOOM3 Single player levels use it in vast quantities.
<br /><br />noticed also that auto-caulk applies caulk textures to surfaces which are touching together. You have to select multiple brushes and run Auto-Caulk (There's a hotkey that runs it)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53843" date="Posted: Tue Sep 28, 2004 10:20 pm "><author>elroacho</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">caulk was implimented in q3 as a "sealer" and it also helps by applying it to surfaces which you can't see to help prevent them from being drawn. i use it religiously, some people dont use it at all. it's not really necessary unless your messigng around with meshs, but it doesn't hurt to use it elsewhere.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53912" date="Posted: Wed Sep 29, 2004 2:43 am "><author>evilartist</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks for the advice, elroache. I tried that, and the leak finder stopped bugging me about that spot, but then bugged me about another spot. I put brushes around it, and then another, and another...it was finding leaks in all my lights, and guis, etc. So I put another caulk box around the whole freakin' map (it's only an experimental map with three rooms and a hall, no biggie). It worked! Can lights shining outside of map brushes cause leakage? If so, then that might have been the case.
<br /><br />Thanks again, all you guys.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
