<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="3308"><title>When 4 mosters are killed -&gt; Open Door</title><posts><post id="p31250" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 9:58 am "><author>Boz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hi!&#13;<br /><br />Does anyone know how to open a door when 4 specific monsters are killed?&#13;<br /><br />Thanks for any replies!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31252" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 10:07 am "><author>obihb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well, haven't done it but I would guess you tag them with a <span style="font-weight: bold">trigger_count</span> and let it count to 4.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31254" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 10:10 am "><author>eskimo roll</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">That's going to require some scripting, check out the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewforum.php?f=4" class="postlink">quake3world.org scripting forum</a> for more information, it may even be worth posting this question there.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31260" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 10:22 am "><author>obihb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Just did a quick test. Create a <span style="font-weight: bold">trigger_count</span> and tag your 4 monsters with it. Then tag the trigger with what you want to trigger, like the door you want to open. Add 4 to the trigger <span style="font-weight: bold">count</span> and that's it. Also remember to use the <span style="font-weight: bold">no_touch</span> or <span style="font-weight: bold">locked</span> keys on the door entity or it'll open anyway if you get close to it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31345" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 2:25 pm "><author>Boz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Cool thanks! And this worked ok? Will this be easy for me to set up as I've never attempted this before..&#13;<br /><br />BTW, I'm remaking 'Dead Simple' from Doom II so I'll post it up when it's all finished, it's gonna contain some new twists <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /> Hopefully I'll be able to find some good sites to host the file as well..&#13;<br /><br />Thanks</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31554" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 8:20 pm "><author>obihb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It works but if you've never edited with Radiant before I suggest going through some quick tutorials for the basics otherwise you might not know how to access or apply what I posted previously. It's a very simple setup for someone who knows Radiant or Quake3/Doom3 editing.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31670" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 11:45 pm "><author>Boz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmm, I managed to kind of get it working, I linked everything up, and this is apparent from the lines that indicate this in the editor but when the mosters are killed the door is still shut but I can walk right through it... any pointers?&#13;<br /><br />Thanks for the help so far <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":-)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p31673" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 11:48 pm "><author>Boz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Actually it seems to do this even before th monster is killed, now I'm confused <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":-(" title="Sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p32096" date="Posted: Tue Aug 10, 2004 3:50 pm "><author>Boz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'd really appreciate some further help with this if possible as it's really got me stumped. I've tried a few different things and nothing seems to work, could you possibly just do a step by step with just two monsters?&#13;<br /><br />Thanks</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
