<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="3310"><title>Video Tutorial - Turkey Game *UPDATED*</title><posts><post id="p31255" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 10:10 am "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Here's another quickie, it shows how to implement the turkey game into a 'computer' screen inside of the game. This can be used to insert any kind of prebuilt GUI or custom.
<br /><br />Thanx to Vash for teaching us this in his great 2-line tutorial <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />j/k, great job Vash! Coulnd't have done it without ya!
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622/http://www.mnemic.tk/education/videotutorials/movies/d3ed_turkey_game_audio_tscc.rar">http://www.mnemic.tk/education/videotut ... o_tscc.rar</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic">Size:</span></span>1.68 Mb
<br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic">Length:</span></span>1:02 Minutes
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622/http://img23.exs.cx/my.php?loc=img23&amp;image=d3ed_turkey_game.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://img23.exs.cx/img23/9086/d3ed_turkey_game.th.jpg" alt="Image" /></a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p31271" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 10:48 am "><author>inPherno</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The link seems to be broken.... and the link to your website seems to be broken too.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31279" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 11:22 am "><author>Burrito</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yep, broken.
<br /><br />Edit: Working again.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p31317" date="Posted: Mon Aug 09, 2004 1:12 pm "><author>Soapurb</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Doesn't show where to get that "Dialog" window, where is it?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p32231" date="Posted: Tue Aug 10, 2004 6:42 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hmm, I'm not sure which dialogue u mean, but it's probably like the GUI window, which is accessed from the ENTITIES panel, press {N} I think the key is to get it, and down at the bottom right corner.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p32233" date="Posted: Tue Aug 10, 2004 6:47 pm "><author>Vash</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hehe, leet <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p41817" date="Posted: Wed Aug 25, 2004 8:47 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">*UPDATED WITH AUDIO!!*
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622/http://www.mnemic.tk/education/videotutorials/movies/d3ed_turkey_game_audio_tscc.rar">http://www.mnemic.tk/education/videotut ... o_tscc.rar</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p76301" date="Posted: Mon Feb 07, 2005 12:17 am "><author>cusTom3</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /> "Smash those turkeys hard, baby"  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><br /><br />OMG, i can't stop laughing at that last line  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /><br /><br />Thanks for all the great tutorials MNeMiC</div>]]></body></post><post id="p76325" date="Posted: Mon Feb 07, 2005 2:16 am "><author>KoRnScythe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Whenever I click your link, or links, or anything from you, it doesn't find it  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p76367" date="Posted: Mon Feb 07, 2005 3:26 pm "><author>pbmax</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">KoRnScythe wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Whenever I click your link, or links, or anything from you, it doesn't find it  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div>
<br /><br />don't give up so easily. when this happens, its likely because the author redesigned his/her site.
<br /><br />so go to the main page instead ( <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522175622/http://www.mnemic.tk/">http://www.mnemic.tk/</a><!-- m --> ) and look around. its still there, just in a different spot.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p179977" date="Posted: Wed Jun 06, 2007 1:36 pm "><author>heagar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">im sure no one ever reads this topic anymore inless there new and wanna know how to make a sttp arcade game in there map. but i have a question. 
<br />in the game it self if you get 30k or so points it sends you a pda message.
<br /><br />iam guessing that activated a trigger. so should it be posable to set a score to open a door. 
<br /><br />in my mp map im tryin to make a good secret room. with the turkey punchers score as a trigger. if anyone can help me plz let me know. on xfire or here in this topic or message me though the forms thanks
<br /><br />Heagar</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180356" date="Posted: Sat Jun 09, 2007 6:22 pm "><author>DoV_Tomas</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">For a challenge I looked into this issue and I didn't have much luck cracking it. 
<br /><br />It's been a long time since I've played the game but I assumed the sequence takes place in the cafeteria in the very first map of the game. I opened the Marscity map and examined the Turkey Puncher entity (model and gui) and there was nothing connected to the model - ie no triggers, relay, sendemail entity, etc. 
<br /><br />I next looked into the gui coding and again nothing indicating a trigger. I even went as far as looking into def files, the map script, and other possible places the code may reside. I did find the actual email that is sent but nothing  that sends it. I also did a forum search and again I found no information on how the message is sent. 
<br /><br />Of course I'm no expert but thus far I've usually been able track things down using the methods I described above. I really wonder since it's an easter egg whether it's hard coded somewhere. In time I'll likely find it but for now it's got me stumped. Sorry couldn't help dude.
<br /><br />The only fast solution I would suggest is to add some code to the TP gui to make it send a trigger at say an arbitrary score (for example something less than 30k). Actually that would probably be easier than finding how id did it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180443" date="Posted: Sun Jun 10, 2007 7:09 pm "><author>heagar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yeah i looked at the gui too i was thinking about looking in the pda 
<br /><br />how do you think i should go about makeing it trigger at such and such score i am no good at scripting i did only the first tutoial on gui scripting</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180688" date="Posted: Tue Jun 12, 2007 4:20 am "><author>DoV_Tomas</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well first off IMO a puzzle that's sure to take a player a few minutes to solve may not be a good idea in a MP map, given the pace and frenetic nature of arena style MP maps. 
<br /><br />My memory of the editor is a bit faded, but I don't recall any ready-made entity that can sense the score of the TP game. I can't really even think of a way to do it with triggers if in fact the game's score is what you want to activate an action. 
<br /><br />Honestly re-working the script is really the only right way to do it. If you're not a coder well it's about time you learn a little since coding really does unlock a lot of powerful options. You don't even really have to write the code, just cut and paste. Maybe for now leave it and work on other stuff in your map and play a bit with scripting. Likely you'll find the solution in time. That's how I learned and that's how a lot of people learned also. If I had the time I would look into it for you, put working two jobs really doesn't leave a whole lot at the end of the day. 
<br /><br />GL</div>]]></body></post><post id="p180871" date="Posted: Wed Jun 13, 2007 8:05 pm "><author>pickleok777</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">pls update link or add a mirror</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
