<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="3588"><title>tutorial on Creating Glass and breakable glass in doom3</title><posts><post id="p33250" date="Posted: Wed Aug 11, 2004 9:16 pm "><author>RedWolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok, here is a Tutorial to create glass in doom 3. 
<br /><br />Click on the thumbnail images to see Full sized "huge" images (My desktop rez of 1280 x 1024) you may need to full screen the pop up window and click the expand to full-size image in the bottom right corner of the image sometimes it takes a sec to appear.... 
<br /><br />There are two ways to create glass. One way is simply create a brush that covers your window opening, and select a glass texture. However, if you do this, and then do the way I’ll show you in this tutorial, you’ll notice a difference in the see through ability of the glass…  In other words, if you make a normal brush, the window is actually drawn twice.
<br /><br />Ok, start off by making a large room, actual size matters not. For this tutorial, it will be 256x512x256. Add your player start point. Put one light on each side of the map. 
<br /><br />First we need to create an opening for the window: 
<br />Add a Wall about 16 units thick splitting the 512 into to halves. Make the wall approximately 156 units long and 64 units high. With it still selected, hit the spacebar, to duplicate it. Align the two brushes, and then move it up 64 units. 
<br /><br />Your map should look thusly, 
<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen04.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen04a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a>
<br /><br />Now, with the brush still selected duplicate it again, re align it with the first and resize it to only 32 units long, then in the “Z” window drag it down so it splits the other two. Then duplicate it again, re align it, and move it to the other side of the opening. 
<br /><br />If you’re following along you map now looks something like this, 
<br /><br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen05.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen05a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a>
<br /><br />Ok, now we have our opening.
<br /><br /><br />Now create the window with a patch! Ok, create a simple brush out of the glass texture texture/glass/gass2_nvp make it so the brush is say 16 units thick and make it the length of our opening the height doesn’t matter. 
<br /><br />SEE:
<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen01.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen01a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a>
<br /><br />Now with the brush selected go up to the patch menu from the menu bar, and go down click on “simple patch mesh…” For now we aren’t even going to worry about the setting just click ok when the “simple patch mesh…” box pops up. 
<br /><br />Ok if you followed along, you map now looks like this. 
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen11.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen11a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a> 
<br /><br />Notice that the brush now has no Height to it. The patch is horizontal and we want it vertical so with the patch selected click the Y-Axis Rotate button on the menu bar located @here follow the mouse pointer in this image
<br /><br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen12.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen12a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a>
<br />Unfortunately, the mouse didn't show up, the button you want is located directly above the left most side of, the box that says y-axis rotate. It looks like a Y right side up with a curved arrow pointing to a y lying on its side.
<br /><br />The patch then turns vertical, simply resize it vertically to cover the opening, like this, 
<br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen13.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen13a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a> 
<br /><br />This was in rendered mode. It must be in render mode to see the glass as it will be in game. Now you may play the map and check out the window  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />You'll notice, that when you fire at it with your pistil, it creates a tiny cracked “whole” (though the bullet does not go through the glass). This is a good effect for single player, but this effect, when shot with a rocket launcher, blackens the glass. So for multiplayer, you may wish to stop this effect. 
<br /><br />Here is how you do that,
<br />Start by going to textures/common/full_clip  select this texture. Then create a brush that fully encases the glass and covers the entire opening it should look something like this,
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen02.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen02a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a>
<br /><br />I don't think clip brushes are show by default so you may not see the clip brush: If this happens you’ll need to go to the view menu run your mouse over show then make sure or check next to the “show clip brush” or hit ctrl+L
<br /><br />Now you may play the map, and you'll notice that bullets will not affect the window.
<br /><br /><br /><br />Ok, for breakable glass make sure you delete the clip brush, and select the glass patch. With the patch selected right click on the editor window to bring up the menu, choose func, then func_fracture. Shown here
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen03.JPG" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://members.cox.net/redwolf1/Screen03a.JPG" alt="Image" /></a>
<br /><br />The glass patch is now a func_fracture entity!  Recompile, and play the game after 2 or 3 shots with the pistil it will now break!
<br /><br />Gee so many people wanted to know it it’s that easy! To make a glass breakable. 
<br /><br /><br />I hope this tutorial was helpful, Please post comments or problems or errors ect. As always if someone knows a better way of doing this or knows how to create breakable glass it would be a great tutorial thanks.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p33252" date="Posted: Wed Aug 11, 2004 9:18 pm "><author>bljohnson</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Holy schnikeys those screenshots are huge.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p33256" date="Posted: Wed Aug 11, 2004 9:21 pm "><author>lophyte</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I just glanced over the tutorial, its a great place for beginners to start with glass. My only problem is the size of your screenshots - BNA suggests a limit of 640 pixels wide so you might want to either resize them or link to them.
<br /><br />Also, for breakable glass, I touch on how to create breakable glass in my <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=3529" class="postlink">ragdoll through glass</a> tutorial.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p33262" date="Posted: Wed Aug 11, 2004 9:29 pm "><author>RedWolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">roflmao, sorry, I didn't take the time to resize, atleast you can see everything  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif" alt=":o" title="Surprised" /><br /><br />I've created linked thumbnails so you don't loose quality.  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p33278" date="Posted: Wed Aug 11, 2004 9:45 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice additon - please resize the images to a width of 640 pixels <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p33313" date="Posted: Wed Aug 11, 2004 10:20 pm "><author>RedWolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-weight: bold">lophyte wrote:</span>
<br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">I just glanced over the tutorial, its a great place for beginners to start with glass. My only problem is the size of your screenshots - BNA suggests a limit of 640 pixels wide so you might want to either resize them or link to them. <br /><br />Also, for breakable glass, I touch on how to create breakable glass in my ragdoll through glass tutorial.I just glanced over the tutorial, its a great place for beginners to start with glass. My only problem is the size of your screenshots - BNA suggests a limit of 640 pixels wide so you might want to either resize them or link to them. <br /><br />Also, for breakable glass, I touch on how to create breakable glass in my ragdoll through glass tutorial.</div>
<br /><br />Thanks! Its really easy to make breakable glass, I'm going to add it to my Tut above thanks again!....</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39732" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 10:08 pm "><author>c0bra</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I get "maps/me/glass.proc not found" when I try to run it <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p39902" date="Posted: Sun Aug 22, 2004 4:21 am "><author>RedWolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm assuming your map is called glass.map ? If so then you need to compile the map for it to create the glass.proc . Open your map in ratiant, and go to the bsp menu and hit bsp, or at the console you can type testmap me/glass and see if that works</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99073" date="Posted: Sun Jun 12, 2005 12:44 pm "><author>sabotath</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hello all out there,
<br /><br />Since I'm new to levelediting and read a lot of tutorials, I thought *lets make a simpel map with one glass window*
<br />In the editor everything went well, but when I wanted to check the result in game I experienced an incredible lag, the screen almost froze on me...
<br /><br />So.....what is causing this lag and is there a way to solve it?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99089" date="Posted: Sun Jun 12, 2005 3:04 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmmm. You just posted a similar question in relation to adding monsters to your map.
<br /><br />You said there that it's a problem that you don't have when playing the SP game.
<br /><br />One thing to note is that when you're playing the SP game, you don't have the editor running in the background. Have you tried playing your custom maps without the editor running?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99102" date="Posted: Sun Jun 12, 2005 4:12 pm "><author>sabotath</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">tnx rich, not running the editor in the background solved this problem  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_redface.gif" alt=":oops:" title="Embarassed" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p114765" date="Posted: Mon Oct 03, 2005 3:38 am "><author>RedWolf</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Also, if you don't use the glass texture with _nvp at the end of it, it will lag when the editor is running (which is why I used it in the tutorial) <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p151886" date="Posted: Tue Aug 01, 2006 9:53 am "><author>skyfox7</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i followed your tutorial but i cant see the glass, when i shoot it it makes the glass bullet holes but the texture looks like the previous wall texture that used to be there
<br /><br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://i65.photobucket.com/albums/h240/ChrisTheRipper_2006/Glasswall.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p214966" date="Posted: Mon Jun 01, 2009 4:03 pm "><author>ShaZe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Does it change anything to do it wiht a patch or use a normal brush caulked on the others side? Like better shatter way or reducing the lag?<br /><br />Because I don't know why but for some reason, when I destroy the glass, I get some huge lag (1 fps during a while) in fullscreen, and my specs are far from being bad (just got a new HD 4890). And if I remember correctly, it was working perfectly fine with a brush before....<br /><br />It might only be the drivers or something.... Or maybe we have to specify certain setting otherwise it cause major lag? I will probably need to experiment a lil bit more on this after work.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p217015" date="Posted: Mon Aug 10, 2009 2:20 am "><author>dutchlady123</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">wonderful! thanks for the info.. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif" alt=":P" title="Razz" /><br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://simulationpretpersonnel.com/" class="postlink"><span style="color: #ECECEC"><span style="text-decoration: underline">demande simulation pret personnel en ligne</span></span></a><span style="color: #ECECEC"> - Pret personnel en ligne et de comparer les meilleurs taux afin de... La demande de prêt personnelen ligne</span><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522170157/http://simulationpretpersonnel.com/" class="postlink"><span style="color: #ECECEC"><span style="text-decoration: underline">demande simulation pret personnel en ligne</span></span></a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p217072" date="Posted: Tue Aug 11, 2009 7:45 am "><author>Theftbot</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how do you get your panels (camera, inspectors, (xy,yz,xz)) to line up.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
