<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="3627"><title>Tutorials: Vacuum Zones (3 tutorials)</title><posts><post id="p33529" date="Posted: Thu Aug 12, 2004 5:36 am "><author>TheCray_nz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">My first tutorial (yeah, I know, it took too long)... the one you've all been waiting for... Vacuum (or no oxygen) zones =D
<br /><br />This one is really really simple, so we'll just get straight into it.
<br /><br />First, create an empty room as usual, put a couple of lights in it as well as an info_player_start.
<br /><br />To create the vacuum effect, you want to add an <span style="color: red">info_vacuum</span> entity into the space where you want the vacuum to take effect.
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://homepages.paradise.net.nz/~ajlc/d3_tuts/img_001.gif" alt="Image" /><br />What your map should look like.
<br /><br /><br />Once you start the map, any parts of the map which are able to reach the info_vacuum entity (even through doors and windows, we'll fix that in the next tutorial) will be in a vacuum.
<br /><br />so, run it, play around, die eventually. Then come right back because it's time for...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p33530" date="Posted: Thu Aug 12, 2004 5:37 am "><author>TheCray_nz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Vacuum Zones Tutorial #2: Creating vacuum barriers
<br /><br />In the last tutorial we created a basic room with a vacuum entity, which sucked the air out of the room. The problem with that layout is that if you were to add more rooms they would also be in a vacuum, even if seperated by a door or window. In this tutorial I will show you how to create areas which the vacuum cannot penetrate.
<br /><br />Start off with the map you created in the previous tutorial. Add a wall with a hole in it to the center of the room, and add a window into that gap.
<br />It should look something like this:
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://homepages.paradise.net.nz/~ajlc/d3_tuts/img_003.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />If you test this map, you'll see that the vacuum still takes effect. This is undesireable.
<br /><br />To fix that, create a brush which fills the gap which the window takes up (it can be thinner or thicker, just as long as it is the same width and height), and apply the editor/visportal texture to this brush. Remember where it is, because it may dissapear (depending on your Show settings), but this doesn't matter. Next, create a <span style="color: red">info_vacuumseperator</span> entity, and place it so that it is touching your visportal brush.
<br />Your map should look something like this now (ignore the visportal for now, it's for the next tutorial):
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://homepages.paradise.net.nz/~ajlc/d3_tuts/img_002.gif" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Run the map, and you are now in a safe area, while the area outside the window is still in a vacuum.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p33532" date="Posted: Thu Aug 12, 2004 5:38 am "><author>TheCray_nz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Vacuum Zones Tutorial #3: Creates dynamic vacuum zones
<br /><br />Alright, now we have a zone where there is a vacuum, and one where there is no vacuum. This isn't really useful in any real-world application however, so it's time to learn how to turn the barriers on and off so we can create zones which can be either in or out of the vacuum.
<br /><br />We'll start where the last tutorial left off, so load up that map.
<br /><br />Select the window brush, and bring up the entity manager (press 'n'). Find <span style="color: red">func_fracture</span> in the list, and click create. This will turn our window into a breakable one. We want this to trigger the <span style="color: red">info_vacuumseperator</span> entity when it is shattered. We do this by adding a <span style="color: blue">target</span> key into the entity manager and giving it a value of "vacuum_seperator_1".
<br /><br />Select the <span style="color: red">info_vacuumseperator</span> entity, and give it a <span style="color: blue">targetname</span> of "vacuum_seperator_1".
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://homepages.paradise.net.nz/~ajlc/d3_tuts/img_002.gif" alt="Image" /><br /><br />What happens here, is when the window is broken, it looks for the entity named vacuum_seperator_1, and triggers it. If you look in the vacuum_seperator description it says that if you trigger it, it will allow the vacuum to flood through. On top of that, if you trigger it again it will close the vacuum barrier, and the vacuum will dissapear.
<br /><br />The vacuumseperator entity can be triggered by whatever you want, monsters dying, a button or gui being pressed, doors opening, lots of different things. The low pressure world of mars is your oyster <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p33553" date="Posted: Thu Aug 12, 2004 6:21 am "><author>kabe69</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">GG, but wheres the vid lol</div>]]></body></post><post id="p33559" date="Posted: Thu Aug 12, 2004 6:32 am "><author>TheCray_nz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hehe, I'm too lazy  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p33562" date="Posted: Thu Aug 12, 2004 6:36 am "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice one, very hand, and - thank god - brief <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p35691" date="Posted: Sun Aug 15, 2004 4:55 am "><author>madmanmick</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hey i did this the same way, but when i break the glass, it triggers the vacuum, but only in the room the vacuum is placed! it still wont flood through the visportal! so i break the glass and can stand in a room that has a broken window onto the mars surface, but i only start losing oxygen if i jump out onto the outside area! how do i fix this?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p36651" date="Posted: Mon Aug 16, 2004 9:21 pm "><author>Scribblehead</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Is there anyway to trigger a speaker with fracture?
<br /><br />I.e when i shoot the glass out, and vacuum sets in - can i make it so that the fracture triggers a sound?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p36747" date="Posted: Mon Aug 16, 2004 11:17 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">there should be a property for some entities called something like:
<br /><br />target_brake:
<br /><br />and just put the sound to that one would work fine, I triggered a door to open when a barrel blew up - worked just fine.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p40433" date="Posted: Mon Aug 23, 2004 10:22 am "><author>Bismarc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">hey i did this the same way, but when i break the glass, it triggers the vacuum, but only in the room the vacuum is placed! it still wont flood through the visportal! so i break the glass and can stand in a room that has a broken window onto the mars surface, but i only start losing oxygen if i jump out onto the outside area! how do i fix this?</div>
<br /><br />I broke my head on this and find the cure. After you do all that is said in tutorial, select both vacuum_separator and braekable glass and click select/Connnect Entities. Now when you drag vacuum_separatov from glass you should see an arror pointing from glass to vacuum_separatov.
<br /><br />It's interesting that without setting glass's health it stands 3 punches but vacuum creates after the 2-nd. So, wit the 3-d punch we just push already broken material(i mean glass) and see visual effect of braking. Is that how it works?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p40451" date="Posted: Mon Aug 23, 2004 11:55 am "><author>rujoking</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">MNeMiC wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">there should be a property for some entities called something like:<br /><br />target_brake:<br /><br />and just put the sound to that one would work fine, I triggered a door to open when a barrel blew up - worked just fine.</div>
<br /><br />I'd like to see a Rube Goldberg-style level; you punch the glass, which causes a vacuum.  This kills a Zombie, whose ragdoll falls on a metal plate, causing a barrel to fall from the ceiling.  The barrel explodes, causing a wall to break open, from which a large spike flies out.  The spike hits a swinging light, and the light's movement triggers another zombie to walk over to a hole in the floor.  He falls in, and as he splats against the ground he hits a button that causes blast doors to close over the broken window.
<br /><br />Mousetrap!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p51240" date="Posted: Fri Sep 17, 2004 9:35 pm "><author>cas111</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">pk i have no idea wat i did wrong but i did every thing in the tutorial for the first two but it is still a vacume in the rest of my map so if any one could help me with this it would be much apreciated</div>]]></body></post><post id="p54867" date="Posted: Sun Oct 03, 2004 4:37 pm "><author>evirus</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Bismarc wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">hey i did this the same way, but when i break the glass, it triggers the vacuum, but only in the room the vacuum is placed! it still wont flood through the visportal! so i break the glass and can stand in a room that has a broken window onto the mars surface, but i only start losing oxygen if i jump out onto the outside area! how do i fix this?</div><br /><br />I broke my head on this and find the cure. After you do all that is said in tutorial, select both vacuum_separator and braekable glass and click select/Connnect Entities. Now when you drag vacuum_separatov from glass you should see an arror pointing from glass to vacuum_separatov.<br /><br />It's interesting that without setting glass's health it stands 3 punches but vacuum creates after the 2-nd. So, wit the 3-d punch we just push already broken material(i mean glass) and see visual effect of braking. Is that how it works?</div>
<br /><br />the 2nd punch breaks the glass enough to cause air to leak out... the 3rd punch causes the glass to break apart compleatly</div>]]></body></post><post id="p65928" date="Posted: Fri Dec 03, 2004 12:50 pm "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Bismarc wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">hey i did this the same way, but when i break the glass, it triggers the vacuum, but only in the room the vacuum is placed! it still wont flood through the visportal! so i break the glass and can stand in a room that has a broken window onto the mars surface, but i only start losing oxygen if i jump out onto the outside area! how do i fix this?</div><br /><br />I broke my head on this and find the cure. After you do all that is said in tutorial, select both vacuum_separator and braekable glass and click select/Connnect Entities. Now when you drag vacuum_separatov from glass you should see an arror pointing from glass to vacuum_separatov.<br /><br />It's interesting that without setting glass's health it stands 3 punches but vacuum creates after the 2-nd. So, wit the 3-d punch we just push already broken material(i mean glass) and see visual effect of braking. Is that how it works?</div>When I click Connect Entities I hear a windows sound. By the way, doom says that the separator didn`t contact a portal
<br /><br />EDIT: I have now make a new map, and it doesn`t work at all.
<br />Only if I use the noclip code and I come very close to the floor and visportal and wall then my oxygen refills, else I have vacuum.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p73183" date="Posted: Fri Jan 21, 2005 2:57 am "><author>TheFallenOne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I have done the tutorial to a "T" and I still get the vacuum. I hit escape so that it would pause and I brought up the consol to see if there were errors loading my map and i found that it said error Vacuum_seperater 1 does not touch visual portal and Vacuum_seperater 2 does not touch a visual portal when in the editor they are definetly touching since they are sitting inside of the visual portal. Can someone help me?
<br /><br />I noticed someone else say this and no one answered............. PLEASE ANSWER ME!!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p73188" date="Posted: Fri Jan 21, 2005 4:12 am "><author>elroacho</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">make sure your visportal is going inside the structural walls a little bit.
<br /><br />makes sure all sides are nodraw except for 1 which is visportal.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p73196" date="Posted: Fri Jan 21, 2005 7:01 am "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it`s only works on mine if you don`t have a patch mesh for a windows. So just a glasstextured brush.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p103275" date="Posted: Sun Jul 10, 2005 12:45 am "><author>ajm113</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Tanks this will be very useful to me <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161822im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p103331" date="Posted: Sun Jul 10, 2005 1:37 pm "><author>Bauul</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">now someone needs to combine this with the directional gravity mod for some really spectactular sequences</div>]]></body></post><post id="p103338" date="Posted: Sun Jul 10, 2005 3:14 pm "><author>r1pp3r</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how do i make it so monsters/ other marines run out of exygen and die?</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
