<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="4475"><title>Video Tutorial - Terrain *UPDATED*</title><posts><post id="p39466" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 1:43 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Make hills and other terrain easy as pie, the terrain I make in this tutorial looks like shit though, but just keep on tweaking it and it should hopefully look really good. 
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828/http://www.mnemic.tk/education/videotutorials/movies/d3ed_terrain_audio_tscc.rar">http://www.mnemic.tk/education/videotut ... o_tscc.rar</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic">Size:</span></span>6.84 Mb
<br /><span style="font-weight: bold"><span style="font-style: italic">Length:</span></span>1.15 Minutes
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828/http://img68.exs.cx/my.php?loc=img68&amp;image=d3ed_terrain.jpg" class="postlink"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://img68.exs.cx/img68/1201/d3ed_terrain.th.jpg" alt="Image" /></a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p39572" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 5:49 pm "><author>VizoR</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">what codec do i need to view this?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39575" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 5:55 pm "><author>BeHe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I cant view any of them either, WMP wont auto download the needed codec either.. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p39580" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 5:59 pm "><author>Immortal</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">same for me :p cannot view that kind of vids</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39591" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 6:24 pm "><author>MachAzereel</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">check out hes website, it has a link to the codec <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p39592" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 6:25 pm "><author>heidinabucket</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Tried 4 players,no joy.
<br /><br />What do we need to run the vid tuts?
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p39594" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 6:28 pm "><author>heidinabucket</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br />Got the codecs!
<br />Cheers!  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p39612" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 6:50 pm "><author>dehzooka</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">he has a link to the codecs in another thread of his,
<br /><br />a good suggestion is to try and split the mesh in grid units..ex:
<br /><br />split a 512x512 patch into 8x8 for 64x64 unit shaped squares or 4x8, etc.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39625" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:10 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I'm re-uploading ALL! the tutorials right now, I updated the readme file so now you should have ALL the instructions you will need, if you can't follow the instructions (I don't post direct link to the page), then I don't think that you are fit to watch the tutorials.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39637" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:18 pm "><author>BeHe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Frankly Id rather not see the damn tutorials than download 42 (!!!!) Mbs of codecs and god knows what other backround running shite.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39640" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:21 pm "><author>BeHe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Oh yeah Id just like to add that the bullshit codec package has screwed over my PC and I cant run any video files at all now.
<br /><br />Cheers for that..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39642" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:22 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Then just uninstall, your the second person who have had this problem, don't know why but it happened to my friend aswell, but he had viruses in the background, you should check for that, anyways, I'm using em, and probably im not the only one, this is all that I need.
<br /><br />And also, be my guest and save my bandwidth by not downloading the tutorials ^_^</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39653" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:36 pm "><author>BeHe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I did uninstall, now a large number of files that used to play just fine and are also I might add distributed by large and reputable software companies no longer work.
<br /><br />Why on earth do you have to use some god damn obscure codec anyway?
<br />every other damn video ive watched for months has been just dandy until MNeMiC comes along with his travelling '42MBs of Codec+other assorted rubbish you really dont want on your PC' roadshow....
<br /><br />Download that crappy codec bundle at your own risk.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39658" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:43 pm "><author>BeHe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Maybe you can write a tutorial on how to un-screw-over my pc, make it HTML though eh?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39662" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:54 pm "><author>|KRiTiKaL|</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">no doubt MNeMiC,  what a great attitude Behe has.  Works fine for me.  
<br /><br />When should your upload be done?  I am looking forward to a new vid.  
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_exclaim.gif" alt=":!:" title="Exclamation" /> Big thanks and appreciation to anyone who will actually take time out to help strangers!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39664" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:57 pm "><author>BeHe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">|KRiTiKaL| wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">no doubt MNeMiC,  what a great attitude Behe has.  Works fine for me.  </div>
<br /><br />Thats great kritikal, im sure youd be all happy and smiles if you downloaded something that screwed your pc.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39665" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 7:59 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">BeHe, sorry about that, just uninstall the program, and no, I won't write a tutorial on it, if you don't know how to uninstall a program, then you are surely not fit to develolp maps, no offence but thats the way it is.
<br /><br />My friend who had the same problem just uninstalled the application and then everything was fine.
<br /><br />Could you tell me what exactly gets 'screwed' up and I will try my best to help you.
<br /><br />KRiTiKaL - It's really fun to help out when you can.
<br /><br />Uplaod finished in 12 minutes it says, but all the ones for Doom 3 is finished now.
<br /><br />And thanx again, to help out, when you figure something out, tell it here in the forums to let all others know about it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39668" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 8:02 pm "><author>BeHe</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I did uninstall the ace codec pack, and half my vids stopped working. I downloaded all the codecs from MS, even reinstalled WMP9 - still not working. So in the end I reinstalled the ace pack, now everthing is working again except YOUR BLOODY TUTORIALS ARRRFGHGHH!
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522161828im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cry.gif" alt=":cry:" title="Crying or Very sad" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p39674" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 8:13 pm "><author>|KRiTiKaL|</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Sorry to flame here but behe you should change your name to Baby.  You know they do make a tutorial, its called PC's for Dummys.  You have not been very nice.  It obviously did not mess up your Internet or PC enough to inhibit your posting.  Try being a little less pissy and act like you have some common sense.  Nobody here owes you a damn thing, were not your mom or your dad or anything inbetween.  So give respect and get respect.  Cheers!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p39675" date="Posted: Sat Aug 21, 2004 8:13 pm "><author>MNeMiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Do you mean the Doom 3 tutorials? for them you don't need ACE MEGA CODEC PACK, for them all you need is the 200kb TSCC ^_^, lol
<br /><br />For some of the older tutorials, you will need DivX only, and thats why I linked to the codec pack =P</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
