<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="6043"><title>WARNING: backwards triangle in input!</title><posts><post id="p51080" date="Posted: Fri Sep 17, 2004 1:43 pm "><author>logoliv</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hi all  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />I've read all the posts in the forums concerning this warning, but nothing applies to my case, so i think the overlapping brushes explanation or brushes not snapping to grid are not valid ones...
<br /><br />I've made a simple test : I've created a simple cubic brush in a simple room and compiled =&gt; no backwards triangle (normal lol), then I've cloned the brush and moved it positively along the x axis =&gt; still OK. But when I clone it and move it positively along y axis I obtain the backwards triangle warning  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_eek.gif" alt=":shock:" title="Shocked" /><br /><br />It's a very common warning because every mapper seems to have plenty of these in their maps, and I would like to get rid of it to have a "clean" compile  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /> Anyway, it's very annoying that it happens everytime I make a clone or copy/paste command and move the brush in the wrong direction !
<br /><br />Any post about a possible explanation will be welcome  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p51092" date="Posted: Fri Sep 17, 2004 2:39 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Warning it's not an "error". Dmap tells to you that "maybe could be something that it's not perfect"..  So, you can't avoid that, and don't worry. there is no reason to think that this message is achieved with "dirty" mapping. Create your map as clean as you can, and don't pay attention to this error.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p51098" date="Posted: Fri Sep 17, 2004 2:58 pm "><author>logoliv</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">thanks for your post Rayne  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> OK... I will do with this warning flooding my console  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" title="Sad" /> Anyway I've spent the afternoon trying to resolve it, made a lot of tests, and it seems that it occurs without obvious logical reason  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_confused.gif" alt=":?" title="Confused" /><br />It's really annoying when you want to optimize your map and to have all perfect...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p51100" date="Posted: Fri Sep 17, 2004 2:59 pm "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">It's not an imperfection. It's a WARNING. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p51106" date="Posted: Fri Sep 17, 2004 3:16 pm "><author>rgun</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah, my map has so many stupid warning messages come up! Most of them being the backwards triangle, or the null entity crap!</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
