<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="6306"><title>Tutorial: Projected Lights (With screenshots!)</title><posts><post id="p53434" date="Posted: Sun Sep 26, 2004 10:27 pm "><author>KolosoK</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">First of all, I did a search on this tutorial on d3w. I found some, but they did not include screenshots of the creation process. This is my first tutorial that I am posting here.
<br /><br /><br />-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<br /><br />Do you want your lighting to look like this:
<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://img84.exs.cx/img84/955/grate.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />If so, follow the easy steps! It will take about 5 minutes to achieve such an effect.
<br /><br />Step 1: Make a light model/texture from which you want the light to be emitted from. I selected a_trimlight_08_fin from the textures\base_lights directory.
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://img89.exs.cx/img89/8779/grate2.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Step 2: Add a light. Place it so the origin (the red dot) of the light overlaps the center of the face of the light texture or model.
<br /><br />Step 3: With the light selected, press J on your keyboard. Now check the "Projected Light" radio button.
<br /><br />Step 4: Now it's time to move the pink dots around to where you want your light projected. Make sure to move them in all the windows: XY, XZ, and YZ. Just click and drag! Make sure the light overlaps the surface. If it does not overlap the surface, it will not light it up!
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://img9.exs.cx/img9/5357/grate3.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Step 5: With the light selected, press N to bring up the properties manager. Here you can disable shadows if you want by typing in the key "noshadows" and the value of "1". You might also mess around with the color by hitting "k" to change the color of your light (give it a darker color to reduce its intensity). 
<br /><br />Step 6: It is now time to copy the light and rotate it so it will project from your other light sources.
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://img40.exs.cx/img40/9762/grate4.jpg" alt="Image" /><br /><br />Step 7: Compile your map, and test it! Check out the first screenshot and see how it should look like.
<br /><br /><br />I hope this helps some of you! Have a kick-ass day!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53493" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2004 11:19 am "><author>Dogstar</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well I found that useful - dare I say 'illuminating'? Thanks for posting this. Every little tut helps! I'm going to try it out later tonight. I just need the cheap thrill of getting something - anything- to work properly. Maybe this will be it! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p53501" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2004 1:06 pm "><author>bb_matt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice work Kolosk !
<br /><br />I've done a follow up tutorial to briefly explain how to create custom projected lights.
<br /><br /><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/viewtopic.php?t=6314" class="postlink">Projected Lights, Part II - Custom Lights</a></div>]]></body></post><post id="p53502" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2004 1:10 pm "><author>moziz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">another good small tutorial what explains only one THE thing and nothing useless. Good work Kolosok  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p53514" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2004 2:52 pm "><author>funcrusher</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Personally I wouldn't use a projected light for strip lighting like that, looks pretty fake, to me. 
<br /><br />Taking a cue from real world lighting, I found a point light with one of the "falloff_exp*" textures overlaid give you a much better approximation of how what appears to be a "light bar" (much like a flourescent bulb) would cast light. Projected lights seem better used sparingly for actual spotlight-type light textures or models.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p53551" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2004 7:13 pm "><author>Eutectic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Perhaps but as Matt demonstrated in in Part II tutorial on projected lights, making it look real might simply be a matter of finding or creating the right light texture for it. One big advantage of projected lights is that the "light volume vs. actual lighted area" equation is much easier to control than with point lights.
<br /><br />With point lights, you have to create a much bigger light volume than what will actually look lighted in the game. The consequence in such a small area is that you inevitably end up with overlapping light volumes. Projected lights with a fine-tuned light texture offers the possibility to produce the desired effect without overlapping light volumes.
<br /><br />Just my 2 cents.
<br /><br />Oh and good work Kosolok and Matt. Thanks to your efficient "to the point" tutorials, I understand how to use projected lights and light textures. A big Thank You to both of you  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p53554" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2004 7:30 pm "><author>bb_matt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Eutectic wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent"><br />With point lights, you have to create a much bigger light volume than what will actually look lighted in the game. The consequence in such a small area is that you inevitably end up with overlapping light volumes. Projected lights with a fine-tuned light texture offers the possibility to produce the desired effect without overlapping light volumes.<br /></div>
<br /><br />Yes - it's basically a bit of a trick really. Of course, you have to be a bit careful how you use them in terms of shadows and the brightness of the projection onto a surface - it could look a bit odd in some circumstances.
<br /><br />If you look at the "misconception" thread I started, it goes into projected lights when De makes that suggestion and indicates these kinds of tricks have been used in CG for years. It basically solved the final part of a lighting dillema I had.
<br /><br />I got a brightly lit largish area using 3 points, 1 ambient and a bunch of projected lights, which basically solved problems with FPS - projected lights are an excellent and very useful addition and can solve many lighting problems - specifically where FPS would otherwise suffer using conventional lighting.
<br /><br />I've been experimenting quite a bit with them today - just for the record, don't try to project a RoQ file  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_lol.gif" alt=":lol:" title="Laughing" /><br /><br />Well, I had to try ! <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p53586" date="Posted: Mon Sep 27, 2004 9:37 pm "><author>KolosoK</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I will add one thing:
<br /><br />To not make it look so fake, I moved the center back inside the brush a bit, so the width of the light is identical to the object from which it comes out of. You can see this in the screenshot.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59737" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 5:50 am "><author>W01f</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Sorry for bringing back an old topic, but I thought i'd mention that the way that scene is set up, that whole tiny floor area will register as having four light volumes touching it. You can bring that number down to one by simply clipping an X in the brush as seen in the pic below (and slightly nudging the texture alignment on any two brushes so the bsp doesn't weld them together)
<br /><br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20100522162610im_/http://www.infosprite.com/members/W01f/grate4.jpg" alt="Image" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p59835" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 3:03 pm "><author>S@TaNiC</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Seeing this topic has been bought back up and is most probably searched for quite a bit it may also be worth mentioning that you can also combine the light with the texture, so if the light flashes or is coloured so is  the light on the texture. This dosnt work with all textures but can easily be solved.
<br /><br />To combine the two first select the light and then the brush with the texture on it and press shift+k both objects should turn green within the editor.
<br /><br />As i said above this dosnt work with all textures and a_trimlight_08_fin happens to be one of these.
<br />The current mtr file for this texture looks like this
<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">textures/base_light/a_trimlight_08_fin<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage textures/base_light/a_trimlight_08_fin.tga<br /><br />   diffusemap   textures/base_light/a_trimlight_d08_fin.tga<br />   specularmap   textures/base_light/a_trimlight_s08_fin.tga<br />     bumpmap      addnormals( textures/base_light/a_trimlight_local.tga  , heightmap( textures/base_light/a_trimlight_b08_fin.tga, 3 ) )<br />   {<br />      blend    gl_one,gl_one<br />      map    textures/base_light/trimlight_fx.tga<br />      rgb   blamptable[ time * 5 ]<br />   }<br /><br />}<br /></div><br /><br />The line above "rgb	blamptable[ time * 5 ]" is what currently makes this texture flash.<br />So i make my own mtr for this .<br /><div class="codetitle"><b>Code:</b></div><div class="codecontent">textures/base_light/a_trimlight_08_test<br />{<br />   qer_editorimage textures/base_light/a_trimlight_08_fin.tga<br /><br />   diffusemap   textures/base_light/a_trimlight_d08_fin.tga<br />   specularmap   textures/base_light/a_trimlight_s08_fin.tga<br />     bumpmap      addnormals( textures/base_light/a_trimlight_local.tga  , heightmap( textures/base_light/a_trimlight_b08_fin.tga, 3 ) )<br />   {<br />      blend    gl_one,gl_one<br />      map    textures/base_light/trimlight_fx.tga<br />      colored<br />   }<br />}<br /></div>
<br /><br />As you can see all ive done is replaced the one line with "colored" now if you retexture the brush with this "a_trimlight_08_test" and combine it with the light, the texture will take on the properties of the light.
<br /><br />Well ive only quickly put this together and someone may point out that this is not the best way to do the mtr file but it works for now, hope this helps.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99727" date="Posted: Sat Jun 18, 2005 3:17 pm "><author>modern</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You cannot change the intensity of a projected light by adding a key "light".  Can this tutorial be edited please to correct this mistake please!</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99741" date="Posted: Sat Jun 18, 2005 5:26 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Sure.
<br /><br />Provide me with corrected text for this section...
<br /><br /><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Step 5: With the light selected, press N to bring up the properties manager. Here you can disable shadows if you want by typing in the key "noshadows" and the value of "1". You can also set the intensity of the light by typing in the key "light" and the value of "x", with x standing for how bright you want it. I used the value of 1 for noshadows and the value of 30 for light. You might also mess around with the "_color" key to change the color of your light. </div>
<br /><br />...and I'll edit it into the original post.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99803" date="Posted: Sun Jun 19, 2005 2:19 am "><author>voldemort</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">If you happen to have a colorable texture or model that you are using for the light select both and hit K instead of j  and this will allow you to assign the colro to both</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99827" date="Posted: Sun Jun 19, 2005 8:31 am "><author>modern</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How about this?
<br /><br />Step 5: With the light selected, press N to bring up the properties manager. Here you can disable shadows if you want by typing in the key "noshadows" and the value of "1". You might also mess around with the "_color" key to change the color of your light (give it a darker color to reduce its intensity).
<br /><br />You cannot change the intensity of the projected light by typing in the key "light" and the value of "x".</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99830" date="Posted: Sun Jun 19, 2005 9:05 am "><author>Rayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Why messin' around with _color  key  when you can hit "k"  and choose a color from a beautifull color picker?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99831" date="Posted: Sun Jun 19, 2005 9:22 am "><author>modern</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Good point, how about this? 
<br /><br />Step 5: With the light selected, press N to bring up the properties manager. Here you can disable shadows if you want by typing in the key "noshadows" and the value of "1". You might also mess around with the color by hitting "k" to change the color of your light (give it a darker color to reduce its intensity). 
<br /><br />You cannot change the intensity of the projected light by typing in the key "light" and the value of "x".</div>]]></body></post><post id="p99883" date="Posted: Sun Jun 19, 2005 4:14 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Done.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
