<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="6744"><title>Doom 3 Editor Launcher - Now with .PK4 Creator plugin!</title><posts><post id="p57040" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 1:38 pm "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-weight: bold">Doom 3 Editor Launcher</span>
<br />[Updated 29/10/2004]
<br /><br />Doom 3 Editor Launcher is a launcher to make running all the different Doom editors alot simpler by placing a menu in the system tray.
<br /><br />Latest Version: 0.31   <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip</a><!-- m --> (15kb)
<br />-All functionality works, but plugins are still in testing. 
<br />-Make sure to read the Readme.txt - it explains info about Plugins
<br /><br /><br />Plugins
<br />.PK4 Creator - <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/PK4Creator.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/PK4Creator.zip</a><!-- m --> (247kb)
<br />-Sampe plugin source avaliable at <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/sampleplugin.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/sampleplugin.zip</a><!-- m --> (13kb, VB6 source code)
<br /><br />If you find any issues with the launcher, either post them here or mail them to <!-- e --><a href="mailto:wraiyth@gmail.com">wraiyth@gmail.com</a><!-- e --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57041" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 2:04 pm "><author>Enforcer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very Kewl. Do you think you could release the source? And just for die hard doom fans fix the ico looks bad, But very kewl i like it its alot better than having 12 icos(not really 12) sitting around</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57110" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 7:10 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Looks nice, but:
<br /><br />1. I have 2 different doom installs on my computer, an option to set which one to open would be useful.
<br /><br />2. An option dialog where we feed in our own command line parameters to the program would help for all people who use custom command lines (which are pretty much everyone).
<br /><br />3. You shouldn't link to "Edit Scripts", it doesn't work and crashes the game. Use "Edit Decls" instead.
<br /><br />4. You missed an "i" in "Edit GUIs" <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57181" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 10:28 pm "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">-Added a crude configuration that allows you to set the current installation path and installation drive. Right click on the icon, and select configuration. I'll improve how it looks in the next release probably
<br />-Removed Edit Scripts, and fixed the typo in Edit GUIs
<br /><br />I'll fix up the icon as soon as I can find a decent icon editor.
<br />As for source code, well I dunno. I might release it once I've got everything implemented and commented.
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823/http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com.au/matt/d3editorlauncher.exe">http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com ... uncher.exe</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />If anyone has any suggestions on how to set up custom parameters, I'd be happy to hear them. Wether you just enter them yourself each time, or select from a list, wether it applies to all shortcuts or just some etc, because I don't know how other people would want it.
<br /><br />EDIT: Forgot to mention that it doesn't need to be in the same directory as doom 3 now</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57188" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 11:26 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">r_brightness, r_gamma, r_fullscreen and com_allowConsole are the most common parameters people want to use I believe, and these would not change from time to time so an option to simply include these in the command line would be good. The option is to simply have a text field where people can enter whatever they want that will be in the command line.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57195" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 11:46 pm "><author>Docgalaad</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You can even ensure than +editor is always at the end of the parameter list. Cause if you have "+editor +r_fullscreen +vid_restart +blabla" the editor will be all messed up. +editor is better as the last command.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57202" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 12:22 am "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You should never need vid_restart in your shortcut as long as editor is the last one.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57254" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 5:01 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok I'm trying to work on being able to apply custom parameters to each shortcut individually, and I figured the besy way was a simple options dialog for each one when the menu was right clicked.
<br />However I have absolutely no idea how to subclass right clicking for menus, as VB doesn't natively support it.
<br />If there are any VB gurus here, then help <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57277" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 7:43 am "><author>SyPHer_</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Awesome program! This owns hard. I think all that it can do now is ok, I think it just needs command lines and it will own hard. Keep up the good work.
<br /><br />Oh and sorry, dont know anything about vb  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57281" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 9:03 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">My code is really messy at the moment so I'm going to spend the next few days making it relatively readable, commenting and stuff.
<br />Yet another release, you can now set parameters for all Editor shortcuts, and the Doom 3 shortcut itself. Tested &amp; working here.
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823/http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com.au/matt/d3editorlauncher.exe">http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com ... uncher.exe</a><!-- m --> (40k)
<br /><br />Unless anyone replies in the next few days with a way to subclass right clicking on menus, then I'll probably do one of three things:
<br />1 - For each menu item, have a sub-menu to allow custom parameters to be set for ONLY that item
<br />2 - Have tabs on the options to allow for each shortcut
<br />3 - Have two entirely different menus
<br /><br />Option 2 is most likely.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57438" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 3:59 am "><author>Eutectic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">iceheart wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">You should never need vid_restart in your shortcut as long as editor is the last one.</div>
<br /><br />Not necessarily. For example, I have 2 shortcuts on my desktop: one to play the game and one to edit maps. I like to play the game at one resolution and edit maps at a different resolution. I have the vid_restart switch on both my shortcuts so that way, I can alternate between playing and editing and the game view will always be at the proper resolution.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57445" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 5:10 am "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I meditated on this for a moment and tried making two shortcuts with these command lines:
<br /><br />C:\D3EDITING\Doom3.exe +set r_mode 5 +set com_allowConsole 1 +set r_fullscreen 0 +set r_brightness 1 +set r_gamma 1 +editor
<br /><br />and
<br /><br />C:\D3EDITING\Doom3.exe +set r_mode 3 +set com_allowConsole 1 +set r_fullscreen 1 +set r_brightness 1.2 +set r_gamma 1.3
<br /><br />These work exactly as you would expect (640x480 in game, 1024x768 in editor, game in fullscreen and with different gamma/brightness). 
<br /><br />I can't see any need for vid_restart in the shortcut since the shortcut is read before the video system is started, but if you have some situation where this is necessary could you please describe it closer?
<br /><br />After some further meditation (and use of the search feature <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />) I have determined that the likely cause of abberant behavior is the use of "seta" in the command line, "seta" tags the cvar as "archive" and saves it into the doomconfig.cfg file so that it will be used every time, it seems that cfg files override the command line and this leads to conflict. This behavior is not required when dealing with command lines (since it is read every execution anyway). It seems that variables stored using "seta" override values in the command line, causing the old resolution to be used until you vid_restart.
<br /><br />Basically, use "seta" to put in a default value, and use "set" whenever you want to use some other value.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57447" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 5:31 am "><author>Eutectic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ahhhh... that's why: seta  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_idea.gif" alt=":idea:" title="Idea" /> Of course. Very sharp observation on your part iceheart. I set those shortcuts and used "seta" the very day I bought the game and the thought never occured to me since.  Me goes off to adjust my shortcuts. The game and editor will load faster thanks to this  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />Thanks for the clarification mate <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57458" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 6:59 am "><author>bb_matt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What I'd like to know is if there is any way to close the editor but keep the game open - toggling between game/editor with F2/TAB is a good feature, but if you want to check your FPS, you have to close everything down and restart doom3.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p58714" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2004 2:12 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">bb_matt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">What I'd like to know is if there is any way to close the editor but keep the game open - toggling between game/editor with F2/TAB is a good feature, but if you want to check your FPS, you have to close everything down and restart doom3.</div>
<br /><br />Not that I know of
<br /><br />I'm working on making the configuration look a bit better, and I'm also implementing plugin architecture, mainly coz its easier for me to customize for myself without modifying the original source.
<br />If other people want to be able to do plugins for it, then I'll release a few samples people can work off.
<br />At the very least I can add new features by it. I'm thinking of writing a .PK4 creator (which would automatically create a .pk4 files from a given directory, excluding DoomConfig.cfg and doomkey), and distributing it as a plugin.
<br />Comments on the plugin idea would be appreciated...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p58737" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2004 6:02 am "><author>demonspawn</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very nice work Wraiyth.
<br />I think having a pk4 packer that is built into your prog would also help in detering mappers from tampering with stock files as well making sure all released pk4's would be clean releases as well.
<br />Nice addition buddy...good tool  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p58741" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2004 6:18 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">demonspawn wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Very nice work Wraiyth.<br />I think having a pk4 packer that is built into your prog would also help in detering mappers from tampering with stock files as well making sure all released pk4's would be clean releases as well.<br />Nice addition buddy...good tool  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>
<br /><br />Thanks man <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225004823im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />I'm working out a few bugs I've got, and I'm also working on a .PK4 creator right now.
<br />Plugin creators will probably have to distribute a batch file with their plugins that automatically register them - I can't think of a better way to do it, and without the DLLs being registered then the plugins don't work full stop. Trying to write a dll register into the program just causes too many problems, especially when the program is run by someone who hasn't run it yet.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59163" date="Posted: Tue Oct 26, 2004 11:39 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">PK4 Creator plugin is still in testing, but a stable working release is avaliable. Check top post for information.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59166" date="Posted: Tue Oct 26, 2004 12:03 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The link to the launcher in the top posting seems to be wrong, at least i get a 404..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59180" date="Posted: Tue Oct 26, 2004 2:33 pm "><author>themadtux</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yup.. seems the file is not there...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59283" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 2:55 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmm I'll take a look at it when I get home, sorry about that... It SHOULD work, unless the server screwed up.
<br /><br />EDIT: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225001527/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p59338" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 11:16 am "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ah, now the links works, thanks.
<br /><br />The launcher wont work until the plugin is installed, it says something about an error 429, can't create object.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59462" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 10:15 pm "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">neumayr wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Ah, now the links works, thanks.<br /><br />The launcher wont work until the plugin is installed, it says something about an error 429, can't create object.</div>
<br /><br />Do you mean that if theres a plugin in the directory, and you run the launcher WITHOUT registering the plugin, you get that error?
<br />If thats what you mean, I'm already aware of it <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225001527im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> The plugin architecture just needs the plugin to be registered before it works.
<br />I'll add better error checking to my to do list for the next version.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59466" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 10:37 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nope, that's not what I meant.
<br />It gave the error without anything else in the directory.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59499" date="Posted: Thu Oct 28, 2004 1:45 am "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Uh, another thing I noticed is that +set fs_game doesn't seem to work.
<br />I put it in both params fields, but when I try test my map it loads the one from base/maps, instead of the one from &lt;mod&gt;/maps...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59532" date="Posted: Thu Oct 28, 2004 7:29 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Nope, that's not what I meant. <br />It gave the error without anything else in the directory.</div>
<br /><br />Thats... really weird, because the thing I concentrated most on was was making sure it worked without any plugins in the same directory - if theres nothing IN the directory it never tries to load anything except for itself.
<br />Does the launcher actually keep running the error? You've said +set fs_game doesn't work, which means you must have gotten it working eventually...
<br />On that note, I'll take a look at that parameter as soon as I get home tonight.
<br /><br />EDIT: How are you actually using the +set fs_game command? Are you using any other params with it?
<br />EDIT 2: It seems the launcher isn't actually saving launch parameters properly. I'll fix ASAP and let you know when its fixed.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59579" date="Posted: Thu Oct 28, 2004 3:55 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I got it to work by installing the plugin ;)
<br />I'll experiment some more when I get home..
<br /><br />The command I use as "+set fs_game testmod", and it's the only command I use.
<br />Nice to know you're trying to fix it, I really appreciate your work.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59688" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 12:13 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Updated to Version 0.31, see main post for link. neumayr you've been credited in the readme.txt file <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225001527im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />I've actually got a sample plugin which launches a custom game by default, so if you want I can whack one up for you neumayr, in case you want to keep your Doom 3 shortcut in the program proper <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225001527im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p59700" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 1:53 am "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice to hear, but the link in the main post still gives me version 0.3..
<br />That plugin would be awesome :)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59717" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 4:01 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The link in the main post is definitely 0.31, its the only file on the server and I tested it before I put it up</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59864" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 6:01 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah, now the link works. Probably some weird proxy error...
<br /><br />Anyway, +set fs_game works now, thanks.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p90896" date="Posted: Tue Apr 26, 2005 2:38 am "><author>romperstomper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">odd, someone i know have the exact same prob, he used a dl version of doom and that command worked fine, then he bought the game, updated it and now he cant mod anymore cuss that parameter dont work.
<br />Fun innit....?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p126813" date="Posted: Sat Dec 24, 2005 4:05 pm "><author>Gmz1013</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how come this doesnt work for ROE?
<br /><br />it leaves the ROE textures black...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p126883" date="Posted: Sun Dec 25, 2005 3:20 am "><author>Luigi</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Probably because it was made before RoE was released.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p126931" date="Posted: Sun Dec 25, 2005 6:20 pm "><author>Gmz1013</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it was?... duh... ok, i'll make my own then</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227874" date="Posted: Sun Oct 10, 2010 7:41 pm "><author>ashkan</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Can you please reupload?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57040" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 1:38 pm "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><span style="font-weight: bold">Doom 3 Editor Launcher</span>
<br />[Updated 29/10/2004]
<br /><br />Doom 3 Editor Launcher is a launcher to make running all the different Doom editors alot simpler by placing a menu in the system tray.
<br /><br />Latest Version: 0.31   <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip</a><!-- m --> (15kb)
<br />-All functionality works, but plugins are still in testing. 
<br />-Make sure to read the Readme.txt - it explains info about Plugins
<br /><br /><br />Plugins
<br />.PK4 Creator - <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/PK4Creator.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/PK4Creator.zip</a><!-- m --> (247kb)
<br />-Sampe plugin source avaliable at <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/sampleplugin.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/sampleplugin.zip</a><!-- m --> (13kb, VB6 source code)
<br /><br />If you find any issues with the launcher, either post them here or mail them to <!-- e --><a href="mailto:wraiyth@gmail.com">wraiyth@gmail.com</a><!-- e --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57041" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 2:04 pm "><author>Enforcer</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very Kewl. Do you think you could release the source? And just for die hard doom fans fix the ico looks bad, But very kewl i like it its alot better than having 12 icos(not really 12) sitting around</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57110" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 7:10 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Looks nice, but:
<br /><br />1. I have 2 different doom installs on my computer, an option to set which one to open would be useful.
<br /><br />2. An option dialog where we feed in our own command line parameters to the program would help for all people who use custom command lines (which are pretty much everyone).
<br /><br />3. You shouldn't link to "Edit Scripts", it doesn't work and crashes the game. Use "Edit Decls" instead.
<br /><br />4. You missed an "i" in "Edit GUIs" <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57181" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 10:28 pm "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">-Added a crude configuration that allows you to set the current installation path and installation drive. Right click on the icon, and select configuration. I'll improve how it looks in the next release probably
<br />-Removed Edit Scripts, and fixed the typo in Edit GUIs
<br /><br />I'll fix up the icon as soon as I can find a decent icon editor.
<br />As for source code, well I dunno. I might release it once I've got everything implemented and commented.
<br /><br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350/http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com.au/matt/d3editorlauncher.exe">http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com ... uncher.exe</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />If anyone has any suggestions on how to set up custom parameters, I'd be happy to hear them. Wether you just enter them yourself each time, or select from a list, wether it applies to all shortcuts or just some etc, because I don't know how other people would want it.
<br /><br />EDIT: Forgot to mention that it doesn't need to be in the same directory as doom 3 now</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57188" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 11:26 pm "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">r_brightness, r_gamma, r_fullscreen and com_allowConsole are the most common parameters people want to use I believe, and these would not change from time to time so an option to simply include these in the command line would be good. The option is to simply have a text field where people can enter whatever they want that will be in the command line.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57195" date="Posted: Sat Oct 16, 2004 11:46 pm "><author>Docgalaad</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You can even ensure than +editor is always at the end of the parameter list. Cause if you have "+editor +r_fullscreen +vid_restart +blabla" the editor will be all messed up. +editor is better as the last command.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57202" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 12:22 am "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">You should never need vid_restart in your shortcut as long as editor is the last one.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57254" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 5:01 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ok I'm trying to work on being able to apply custom parameters to each shortcut individually, and I figured the besy way was a simple options dialog for each one when the menu was right clicked.
<br />However I have absolutely no idea how to subclass right clicking for menus, as VB doesn't natively support it.
<br />If there are any VB gurus here, then help <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57277" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 7:43 am "><author>SyPHer_</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Awesome program! This owns hard. I think all that it can do now is ok, I think it just needs command lines and it will own hard. Keep up the good work.
<br /><br />Oh and sorry, dont know anything about vb  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=":wink:" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57281" date="Posted: Sun Oct 17, 2004 9:03 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">My code is really messy at the moment so I'm going to spend the next few days making it relatively readable, commenting and stuff.
<br />Yet another release, you can now set parameters for all Editor shortcuts, and the Doom 3 shortcut itself. Tested &amp; working here.
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350/http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com.au/matt/d3editorlauncher.exe">http://drunkenness.creates.disorder.com ... uncher.exe</a><!-- m --> (40k)
<br /><br />Unless anyone replies in the next few days with a way to subclass right clicking on menus, then I'll probably do one of three things:
<br />1 - For each menu item, have a sub-menu to allow custom parameters to be set for ONLY that item
<br />2 - Have tabs on the options to allow for each shortcut
<br />3 - Have two entirely different menus
<br /><br />Option 2 is most likely.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57438" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 3:59 am "><author>Eutectic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">iceheart wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">You should never need vid_restart in your shortcut as long as editor is the last one.</div>
<br /><br />Not necessarily. For example, I have 2 shortcuts on my desktop: one to play the game and one to edit maps. I like to play the game at one resolution and edit maps at a different resolution. I have the vid_restart switch on both my shortcuts so that way, I can alternate between playing and editing and the game view will always be at the proper resolution.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57445" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 5:10 am "><author>iceheart</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I meditated on this for a moment and tried making two shortcuts with these command lines:
<br /><br />C:\D3EDITING\Doom3.exe +set r_mode 5 +set com_allowConsole 1 +set r_fullscreen 0 +set r_brightness 1 +set r_gamma 1 +editor
<br /><br />and
<br /><br />C:\D3EDITING\Doom3.exe +set r_mode 3 +set com_allowConsole 1 +set r_fullscreen 1 +set r_brightness 1.2 +set r_gamma 1.3
<br /><br />These work exactly as you would expect (640x480 in game, 1024x768 in editor, game in fullscreen and with different gamma/brightness). 
<br /><br />I can't see any need for vid_restart in the shortcut since the shortcut is read before the video system is started, but if you have some situation where this is necessary could you please describe it closer?
<br /><br />After some further meditation (and use of the search feature <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" />) I have determined that the likely cause of abberant behavior is the use of "seta" in the command line, "seta" tags the cvar as "archive" and saves it into the doomconfig.cfg file so that it will be used every time, it seems that cfg files override the command line and this leads to conflict. This behavior is not required when dealing with command lines (since it is read every execution anyway). It seems that variables stored using "seta" override values in the command line, causing the old resolution to be used until you vid_restart.
<br /><br />Basically, use "seta" to put in a default value, and use "set" whenever you want to use some other value.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p57447" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 5:31 am "><author>Eutectic</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ahhhh... that's why: seta  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_idea.gif" alt=":idea:" title="Idea" /> Of course. Very sharp observation on your part iceheart. I set those shortcuts and used "seta" the very day I bought the game and the thought never occured to me since.  Me goes off to adjust my shortcuts. The game and editor will load faster thanks to this  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /><br /><br />Thanks for the clarification mate <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p57458" date="Posted: Mon Oct 18, 2004 6:59 am "><author>bb_matt</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">What I'd like to know is if there is any way to close the editor but keep the game open - toggling between game/editor with F2/TAB is a good feature, but if you want to check your FPS, you have to close everything down and restart doom3.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p58714" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2004 2:12 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">bb_matt wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">What I'd like to know is if there is any way to close the editor but keep the game open - toggling between game/editor with F2/TAB is a good feature, but if you want to check your FPS, you have to close everything down and restart doom3.</div>
<br /><br />Not that I know of
<br /><br />I'm working on making the configuration look a bit better, and I'm also implementing plugin architecture, mainly coz its easier for me to customize for myself without modifying the original source.
<br />If other people want to be able to do plugins for it, then I'll release a few samples people can work off.
<br />At the very least I can add new features by it. I'm thinking of writing a .PK4 creator (which would automatically create a .pk4 files from a given directory, excluding DoomConfig.cfg and doomkey), and distributing it as a plugin.
<br />Comments on the plugin idea would be appreciated...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p58737" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2004 6:02 am "><author>demonspawn</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Very nice work Wraiyth.
<br />I think having a pk4 packer that is built into your prog would also help in detering mappers from tampering with stock files as well making sure all released pk4's would be clean releases as well.
<br />Nice addition buddy...good tool  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p58741" date="Posted: Sun Oct 24, 2004 6:18 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">demonspawn wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Very nice work Wraiyth.<br />I think having a pk4 packer that is built into your prog would also help in detering mappers from tampering with stock files as well making sure all released pk4's would be clean releases as well.<br />Nice addition buddy...good tool  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>
<br /><br />Thanks man <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101225002350im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br /><br />I'm working out a few bugs I've got, and I'm also working on a .PK4 creator right now.
<br />Plugin creators will probably have to distribute a batch file with their plugins that automatically register them - I can't think of a better way to do it, and without the DLLs being registered then the plugins don't work full stop. Trying to write a dll register into the program just causes too many problems, especially when the program is run by someone who hasn't run it yet.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59163" date="Posted: Tue Oct 26, 2004 11:39 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">PK4 Creator plugin is still in testing, but a stable working release is avaliable. Check top post for information.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59166" date="Posted: Tue Oct 26, 2004 12:03 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The link to the launcher in the top posting seems to be wrong, at least i get a 404..</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59180" date="Posted: Tue Oct 26, 2004 2:33 pm "><author>themadtux</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yup.. seems the file is not there...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59283" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 2:55 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hmm I'll take a look at it when I get home, sorry about that... It SHOULD work, unless the server screwed up.
<br /><br />EDIT: <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224231534/http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip">http://wraiyth.cjb.net/d3el/d3editorlauncher.zip</a><!-- m --></div>]]></body></post><post id="p59338" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 11:16 am "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Ah, now the links works, thanks.
<br /><br />The launcher wont work until the plugin is installed, it says something about an error 429, can't create object.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59462" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 10:15 pm "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">neumayr wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Ah, now the links works, thanks.<br /><br />The launcher wont work until the plugin is installed, it says something about an error 429, can't create object.</div>
<br /><br />Do you mean that if theres a plugin in the directory, and you run the launcher WITHOUT registering the plugin, you get that error?
<br />If thats what you mean, I'm already aware of it <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224231534im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /> The plugin architecture just needs the plugin to be registered before it works.
<br />I'll add better error checking to my to do list for the next version.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59466" date="Posted: Wed Oct 27, 2004 10:37 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nope, that's not what I meant.
<br />It gave the error without anything else in the directory.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59499" date="Posted: Thu Oct 28, 2004 1:45 am "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Uh, another thing I noticed is that +set fs_game doesn't seem to work.
<br />I put it in both params fields, but when I try test my map it loads the one from base/maps, instead of the one from &lt;mod&gt;/maps...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59532" date="Posted: Thu Oct 28, 2004 7:29 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Nope, that's not what I meant. <br />It gave the error without anything else in the directory.</div>
<br /><br />Thats... really weird, because the thing I concentrated most on was was making sure it worked without any plugins in the same directory - if theres nothing IN the directory it never tries to load anything except for itself.
<br />Does the launcher actually keep running the error? You've said +set fs_game doesn't work, which means you must have gotten it working eventually...
<br />On that note, I'll take a look at that parameter as soon as I get home tonight.
<br /><br />EDIT: How are you actually using the +set fs_game command? Are you using any other params with it?
<br />EDIT 2: It seems the launcher isn't actually saving launch parameters properly. I'll fix ASAP and let you know when its fixed.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59579" date="Posted: Thu Oct 28, 2004 3:55 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I got it to work by installing the plugin ;)
<br />I'll experiment some more when I get home..
<br /><br />The command I use as "+set fs_game testmod", and it's the only command I use.
<br />Nice to know you're trying to fix it, I really appreciate your work.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59688" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 12:13 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Updated to Version 0.31, see main post for link. neumayr you've been credited in the readme.txt file <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224231534im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /><br />I've actually got a sample plugin which launches a custom game by default, so if you want I can whack one up for you neumayr, in case you want to keep your Doom 3 shortcut in the program proper <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20101224231534im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p59700" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 1:53 am "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Nice to hear, but the link in the main post still gives me version 0.3..
<br />That plugin would be awesome :)</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59717" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 4:01 am "><author>Wraiyth</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">The link in the main post is definitely 0.31, its the only file on the server and I tested it before I put it up</div>]]></body></post><post id="p59864" date="Posted: Fri Oct 29, 2004 6:01 pm "><author>neumayr</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Yeah, now the link works. Probably some weird proxy error...
<br /><br />Anyway, +set fs_game works now, thanks.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p90896" date="Posted: Tue Apr 26, 2005 2:38 am "><author>romperstomper</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">odd, someone i know have the exact same prob, he used a dl version of doom and that command worked fine, then he bought the game, updated it and now he cant mod anymore cuss that parameter dont work.
<br />Fun innit....?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p126813" date="Posted: Sat Dec 24, 2005 4:05 pm "><author>Gmz1013</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how come this doesnt work for ROE?
<br /><br />it leaves the ROE textures black...</div>]]></body></post><post id="p126883" date="Posted: Sun Dec 25, 2005 3:20 am "><author>Luigi</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Probably because it was made before RoE was released.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p126931" date="Posted: Sun Dec 25, 2005 6:20 pm "><author>Gmz1013</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">it was?... duh... ok, i'll make my own then</div>]]></body></post><post id="p227874" date="Posted: Sun Oct 10, 2010 7:41 pm "><author>ashkan</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Can you please reupload?</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
