<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="7764"><title>Doom map errors!</title><posts><post id="p66803" date="Posted: Wed Dec 08, 2004 6:00 pm "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I`ve got an error:
<br />.........Map game shutdown.........
<br />...............................................
<br />...............................................
<br /><br />***************************
<br />ERROR: No free entities
<br />***************************
<br /><br />Does anybody know what it`s means, and how do you fix that?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p66804" date="Posted: Wed Dec 08, 2004 6:02 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How many entites do you have in your map? You wouldn't by chance have 4060 would you?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p66805" date="Posted: Wed Dec 08, 2004 6:04 pm "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Is there a limit of 4060?
<br />Now, I`ve maked a Cargo Storage room, and I can`t say there are a little bit of entities.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p66809" date="Posted: Wed Dec 08, 2004 6:25 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I wrote a script awhile back to fill a room with instances of a grass model I made and I found that as soon as the count went over 4057 the game would exit to the console with an error message.
<br /><br />But the map had 3 additional entities from the start, an info_player_start, a light, and a worldspawn.
<br /><br />I'm pretty sure that means there is a limit of 4060 entities.
<br /><br />I can't believe you have that many in your map though. I mean, you hand placed 4000+ entities?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p66810" date="Posted: Wed Dec 08, 2004 6:29 pm "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">yes. hand-placed
<br /><br />Is there a fast way to remove entities(of the same sort)?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p66837" date="Posted: Wed Dec 08, 2004 7:58 pm "><author>Lunaran</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Select one and hit shift-A.
<br /><br />Rich: the limit might actually be 4096, since id always uses powers of 2 for that kind of thing.  Doom3 might have a lot of things that count as entities that don't actually show up, bookkeeping ents and so forth.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p67074" date="Posted: Thu Dec 09, 2004 8:00 pm "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Does anybody know what this means?:
<br />ERROR: i &gt;= MAX_REACH_PER_AREA</div>]]></body></post><post id="p67118" date="Posted: Fri Dec 10, 2004 4:40 pm "><author>=NoMercy=</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hey I get the same gay ass error, hmm dunno whats the problem it was working fine before.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p67122" date="Posted: Fri Dec 10, 2004 5:07 pm "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">=NoMercy= wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Hey I get the same gay ass error, hmm dunno whats the problem it was working fine before.</div>
<br /><br />I think, from a other topic placed by me(cranegame) I Copied the map from alpha labs sector 3, and I seperate the part with crane from the rest of the level. Then, I`ve created new object witch I can pickup with the crane. While running dmap I saw that The Doom 3 offical game levels are created with areas, and if you did the same what I did, that 1 area a maximum of entities have. There`s then not a real solution.
<br /><br />By the way. It`s possible that you can`t understand me, because I`m from Holland, and I can understand almost everything, but not write everything I want to write. <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" title="Smile" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p67136" date="Posted: Fri Dec 10, 2004 7:06 pm "><author>=NoMercy=</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">so your saying I should add more visportals?
<br /><br />Edit oh and i dont have muc entities, mostly brushes but my map isnt big anyways.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p68349" date="Posted: Sat Dec 18, 2004 5:50 pm "><author>Sebazzz</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Sorry to buck this back, but now I`m not happy anymore,
<br />now I get the Max reach error, what the hell it means, too,
<br />in my own made map!!!????
<br /><br />EDIT: This is probaly the solution: after you get the error, retry to load your map. Then I`ve got a error, I had no worldspawn anymore,but that`s now fixed.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p68385" date="Posted: Sat Dec 18, 2004 9:18 pm "><author>BNA!</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">=NoMercy= wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Hey I get the same gay ass error, hmm dunno whats the problem it was working fine before.</div>
<br /><br />Express yourself differently than "gay ass" please - thanks in advance.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p126325" date="Posted: Tue Dec 20, 2005 3:58 pm "><author>DarkMatterGR</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I am not quite sure but this happens usually when one or more of your monsters have too many 'options' of movement, hidding etc. During the compilation of your map -the aas proccess- the game is trying to create the AI for your monsters. If there are no monster clip areas then the whole map is considered to be one single area for your monsters so every single one can move and 'think' how to react in the environment all the time. This can cause garbage performance and if the game cant handle this it gives you the error i &gt; MAX_REACH_PER_AREA.
<br /><br />To solve this simply seperate your map into areas wich will work as a guide to your monsters. Simply decide where each of your monsters will be able to move and create a room (a brush and then curve it) arround them, giving it the common/monster_clip texture. This will work as a restriction for the monster(s) inside this area limiting their choises. Be carefull not to make too small rooms cause your monsters will be 'stupid', neither too big cause u'll only cause more performance problems.
<br /><br />I hope this helped. It worked for me at least...</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
