<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="8166"><title>Hope this is the right forum to ask about it.</title><posts><post id="p70716" date="Posted: Thu Jan 06, 2005 2:27 pm "><author>scorpion122</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Well I have a problem while making a tutorial with cut boolean compground objects.&#13;<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://psychokillax.tripod.com/html/weaponmodeling.html">http://psychokillax.tripod.com/html/weaponmodeling.html</a><!-- m -->&#13;<br />Go here for more information about the tutorial.&#13;<br />I'm at the part with the grip and making detail but there is a small problem with cutting the cylinders you will see more at the screenshots i'm posting.&#13;<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.infosprite.com/members/reptile/cutting.gif" alt="Image" /><ul><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.infosprite.com/members/reptile/before.gif" alt="Image" /><ul>Hope that might be helpfull to see what is wrong and my problem.<br />Thanks a million.</ul></ul><br />Edit: sorry 56 k users.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p70846" date="Posted: Fri Jan 07, 2005 2:27 am "><author>SyPHer_</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Hhhmmm. Well boolean's are always messing things and I see them as the equivelent of CSG Subtract in mapping, works sometimes but theres always bugs in the system.&#13;<br /><br />Jus try completely restarting the clip, I'm sure that if you follow the tutorial completely you shoudnt have any problems.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p70859" date="Posted: Fri Jan 07, 2005 3:42 am "><author>contraband</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I agree with SyPHer, booleans is sometimes like digging a square hole with hand grenades. In the tutorial the cylinders are longer then the square ammo case. In your pics they are shorter. Did I pass the eye test?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p70915" date="Posted: Fri Jan 07, 2005 2:18 pm "><author>scorpion122</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Lol normally i'm not the big fan of csg substract with mapping because the thing you substract is getting too ugly the way.&#13;<br />For example cutting a room with make of made it hollow , isnt good.&#13;<br />So I prefer to make the floor then copy the floor for the ceilling and put walls together.&#13;<br />But I cannot understand why the hell I'm loosing parts of the grip.&#13;<br />I think i will try this turorial again until I have no error about this.&#13;<br />Mapping is much more easier to understand guys.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p70928" date="Posted: Fri Jan 07, 2005 3:25 pm "><author>Slogbog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">i had this problem once, i cant remember eactly what fixed it, but just keep tooling with it and itll work. Just do like sypher said, and completely reattempt the clip, i think i did something similar - just recreated the object for subtraction. You can see what happens when you try and add it and intersect it as well, it goes weird then too i think, i dont remember if i ever actually figured out what caused it.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p70937" date="Posted: Fri Jan 07, 2005 3:49 pm "><author>rich_is_bored</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I dunno who's tutorial that is but IMHO, it's bad practice to use boolean operations regardless what modeling package you're using.&#13;<br /><br />There are plenty of other methods to create that clip. It's a shame I'm not familiar enough with MAX to explain them to you.&#13;<br /><br />Oh BTW, could you resize that image so it's no wider than 640px please?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p71044" date="Posted: Sat Jan 08, 2005 12:38 am "><author>Slogbog</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I think booleans have a time and place, but i agree that they should not be used on that clip. Some simple edge cutting and extruding would be a far better way IMO - and would leave a much cleaner result.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p71191" date="Posted: Sat Jan 08, 2005 7:39 pm "><author>scorpion122</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Thanks guys I already figured it out and got it working ..dont know how I did this but...Oh and in D3 the weapon looks a bit big.&#13;<br />Is there anything I can do for scaling it a bit smaller?&#13;<br />Like the normal maschinegun's size.&#13;<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.infosprite.com/members/reptile/gun.gif" alt="Image" /><br />Hope ya like it so far. &#13;<br /><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_cool.gif" alt="8)" title="Cool" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p71293" date="Posted: Sun Jan 09, 2005 9:48 am "><author>SyPHer_</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">Select all of the objects (Ctrl + A) and then use the scale tool (R) and scale it down! If it scales the objects seperatly then select all objects and goto Group -&gt; Group, call it what you want and then scale it down. Post a screenshot of it ingame  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p71508" date="Posted: Mon Jan 10, 2005 5:27 pm "><author>scorpion122</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">SyPHer_ wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">Select all of the objects (Ctrl + A) and then use the scale tool (R) and scale it down! If it scales the objects seperatly then select all objects and goto Group -&gt; Group, call it what you want and then scale it down. Post a screenshot of it ingame  <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>&#13;<br />K thanks , just lemme finish the md5 meshes then I give ya the link to download my sniper mod or whatever you want to call the weapon.&#13;<br />In my list I called it recon for ghost recon.-]</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
