<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><thread id="9581"><title>Maya 6.5 importer</title><posts><post id="p84617" date="Posted: Sat Mar 26, 2005 11:29 pm "><author>_placid_</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I started animating a character with Maya 6.5 and found out recently that it's completely incompatible with Maya 6. When attempting to import into Doom3 with the Maya 6 impoter it just crashed with a fatal error, hence not leaving a way with which to get Maya 6.5 animations into Doom3.
<br /><br />I e-mailed Brian Harris, the guy from id who runs <!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.iddevnet.com/">http://www.iddevnet.com/</a><!-- m --> and this is what he said:
<br /><br />"We don't actually have Maya 6.5 yet, but the source code for the 
<br />exporter has been released, so if you know a programmer that has 6.5 
<br />you can get him to compile it with the new libraries.  Sucks that 6.5 
<br />isn't compatible with 6.0 <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":-(" title="Sad" />  They should really call it 7.0 if it's 
<br />incompatible. "
<br /><br /><br />So... is there anyone around who has enough knowledge to be able to compile that dll for everyone who's using the newer Maya? I'm willing to provide any needed files for the sake of making this dll publically available. I'll also be sure to forward it to Brian also so he can make a post about it on iddevnet.com.
<br /><br />This is the note it says about the Maya importer source on iddevnet:
<br />"To compile the Maya Import dll, you will need to get the Maya 4.5 or the Maya 6.0 SDK from Alias. There is a note in the directory explaining where the files need to go. The project comes set up to compile a dll for Maya 4.5. If you want to compile a dll for Maya 6.0, instructions are in maya_main.cpp. For Maya 6.0, you will need Visual Studio 2003 or higher. The Maya 6.0 SDK does not work with Visual Studio 2002."</div>]]></body></post><post id="p84619" date="Posted: Sat Mar 26, 2005 11:36 pm "><author>BloodRayne</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">How about Dominion? <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" title="Wink" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p84755" date="Posted: Sun Mar 27, 2005 10:38 pm "><author>_placid_</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">well, let him know what's up and maybe he might do it, i've never seen him on irc and rarely see him on the forum.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p86702" date="Posted: Wed Apr 06, 2005 3:06 pm "><author>Anodoin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I've got Maya 6.5 and Visual Studio .Net 2003, but I can't find the source for the exporter.  If anybody can help me out with that I'll bounce back the dll.
<br /><br />EDIT:  Ooooh man, am I a dummy.  I was looking for the exporter code in the Maya SDK, not Doom 3's.  I compiled it, it seems to work (i.e., it doesn't crash) but my models don't export properly (perhaps because I'm new at this).  I'm working on that bit, though.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p86948" date="Posted: Thu Apr 07, 2005 11:21 pm "><author>binaryc</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">I uploaded the exporter Anodoin compiled here:
<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/downloads/MayaImportx86_Maya65.zip">http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/downloads ... Maya65.zip</a><!-- m -->
<br /><br />If it doesn't work, blame him <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>]]></body></post><post id="p86959" date="Posted: Fri Apr 08, 2005 2:07 am "><author>Anodoin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">binaryc wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">I uploaded the exporter Anodoin compiled here:<br /><!-- m --><a class="postlink" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516/http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/downloads/MayaImportx86_Maya65.zip">http://www.iddevnet.com/doom3/downloads ... Maya65.zip</a><!-- m --><br /><br />If it doesn't work, blame him <img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20070509181516im_/http://www.doom3world.org/phpbb2/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" title="Very Happy" /></div>
<br /><br /><br />LOL
<br /><br />Yeah, let me know if it doesn't work, I'm new to modeling so I can't really test it on an advanced model.  But if it doesn't I'll see what I can do to get it to work for you.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p87999" date="Posted: Wed Apr 13, 2005 9:23 am "><author>matt50683</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">how do you use this dll in maya 6.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p88044" date="Posted: Wed Apr 13, 2005 2:35 pm "><author>matt50683</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody">hi, i still cant figure this out.. i need a maya 6.5 file to be converted so that i can use it in 6.0.. would someone help? or download the file off me and convert for me?</div>]]></body></post><post id="p88196" date="Posted: Thu Apr 14, 2005 3:14 am "><author>Anodoin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">matt50683 wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">hi, i still cant figure this out.. i need a maya 6.5 file to be converted so that i can use it in 6.0.. would someone help? or download the file off me and convert for me?</div>
<br /><br />Well, what we're speaking of in here is getting a model from Maya 6.5 into Doom 3.  Id had released exporters for Maya v 4.5, 5 and 6.0, but 6.5 was different enough that it wouldn't work, so I compiled the export dll files for 6.5.  
<br /><br />That being said...  maybe what you can do, is get someone to compile the 6.5 file into Doom's md5 format, and then use Seith's utility to convert the md5 file back into a Maya file that you can use.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p96066" date="Posted: Wed May 25, 2005 2:27 am "><author>Mordekai</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle"><b>Quote:</b></div><div class="quotecontent">Well, what we're speaking of in here is getting a model from Maya 6.5 into Doom 3.  Id had released exporters for Maya v 4.5, 5 and 6.0, but 6.5 was different enough that it wouldn't work, so I compiled the export dll files for 6.5.</div>
<br /><br />So where would this exporter for Maya 6 be?  Maybe I've misread the information but I thought that there was only a importer available, not an exporter.</div>]]></body></post><post id="p96068" date="Posted: Wed May 25, 2005 2:35 am "><author>Anodoin</author><body><![CDATA[<div class="postbody"><div class="quotetitle">Mordekai wrote:</div><div class="quotecontent">So where would this exporter for Maya 6 be?  Maybe I've misread the information but I thought that there was only a importer available, not an exporter.</div>
<br /><br />Look on iddevnet.com in the downloads section, or search the message boards here.  Officially, there is only Id's Maya v4.5, 5 and 6 importer.  Unofficially (i.e., don't ask Id for help with it) is the Maya 6.5 importer I compiled, and Seith's program which converts Id's .md5 format into Maya's native format.</div>]]></body></post></posts></thread></xml>
